Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON Clinton/PERSON Drew/PERSON ``/O Clint/O ''/O Dempsey/PERSON -LRB-/O born/O March/O 9/O ,/O 1983/O -RRB-/O is/O an/O American/O soccer/O player/O who/O plays/O for/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION national/O team/O ./O 
Growing/O up/O in/O Nacogdoches/LOCATION ,/O Texas/LOCATION ,/O Dempsey/PERSON played/O for/O one/O of/O the/O top/O youth/O soccer/O clubs/O in/O the/O state/O ,/O the/O Dallas/LOCATION Texans/O ,/O before/O playing/O for/O Furman/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION 's/O men/O 's/O soccer/O team/O ./O 
In/O 2004/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON was/O drafted/O by/O Major/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION Soccer/ORGANIZATION club/O New/LOCATION England/LOCATION Revolution/O ,/O where/O he/O quickly/O integrated/O himself/O into/O the/O starting/O lineup/O ./O 
Hindered/O initially/O by/O a/O jaw/O injury/O ,/O he/O would/O eventually/O score/O 25/O goals/O in/O 71/O appearances/O with/O the/O Revolution/O ./O 
Between/O 2007/O and/O 2012/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON played/O for/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION team/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION and/O is/O the/O club/O 's/O highest/O Premier/O League/O goalscorer/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON first/O represented/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION at/O the/O 2003/O FIFA/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION Championship/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O United/LOCATION Arab/LOCATION Emirates/LOCATION ./O 
He/O made/O his/O first/O appearance/O with/O the/O senior/O team/O on/O November/O 17/O ,/O 2004/O ,/O against/O Jamaica/LOCATION ;/O he/O was/O then/O named/O to/O the/O squad/O for/O the/O 2006/O World/O Cup/O and/O scored/O the/O team/O 's/O only/O goal/O of/O the/O tournament/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON recorded/O the/O fastest/O goal/O in/O U.S./LOCATION World/O Cup/O qualifying/O history/O by/O scoring/O after/O 53/O seconds/O of/O an/O eventual/O 8/O --/O 0/O defeat/O of/O Barbados/LOCATION ./O 
He/O later/O bested/O that/O feat/O in/O 2012/O scoring/O just/O 36/O seconds/O into/O a/O 1/O --/O 2/O qualifying/O loss/O at/O Jamaica/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O 2010/O FIFA/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Cup/ORGANIZATION ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O against/O England/LOCATION ,/O becoming/O the/O second/O American/O ,/O after/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON ,/O to/O score/O goals/O in/O multiple/O World/O Cup/O tournaments/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON became/O the/O first/O American/O player/O to/O score/O a/O hat-trick/O in/O the/O English/O Premier/O League/O ,/O in/O the/O 5/O --/O 2/O win/O over/O Newcastle/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION in/O January/O 2012/O ./O 
Youth/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON was/O born/O in/O Nacogdoches/LOCATION ,/O Texas/LOCATION and/O ,/O for/O much/O of/O his/O childhood/O ,/O his/O family/O lived/O in/O a/O trailer/O park/O ,/O where/O he/O and/O his/O siblings/O grew/O up/O playing/O soccer/O with/O the/O local/O children/O or/O anyone/O they/O could/O find/O ./O 
His/O older/O brother/O Ryan/PERSON was/O offered/O a/O tryout/O for/O the/O Dallas/LOCATION Texans/O ,/O an/O elite/O youth/O soccer/O club/O ,/O and/O brought/O Clint/PERSON ,/O who/O was/O noticed/O and/O recruited/O while/O passing/O time/O juggling/O a/O ball/O on/O the/O sidelines/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON became/O a/O standout/O on/O the/O team/O at/O an/O early/O age/O ,/O but/O had/O to/O quit/O due/O to/O his/O family/O 's/O time/O and/O money/O constraints/O as/O his/O eldest/O sister/O Jennifer/PERSON was/O becoming/O a/O ranked/O youth/O tennis/O player/O ./O 
Several/O parents/O of/O his/O teammates/O with/O the/O Texans/O offered/O to/O assist/O the/O Dempseys/ORGANIZATION with/O expenses/O and/O travel/O ,/O allowing/O him/O to/O rejoin/O the/O club/O ./O 
On/O November/O 27/O ,/O 1995/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON lost/O his/O then/O 16-year-old/O sister/O Jennifer/PERSON to/O a/O brain/O aneurysm/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON was/O devastated/O with/O the/O family/O 's/O loss/O and/O later/O explained/O that/O this/O event/O helped/O him/O developed/O a/O deeper/O motivation/O to/O pursue/O soccer/O ;/O in/O honor/O of/O his/O sister/O ./O 
He/O went/O on/O to/O be/O the/O captain/O and/O high/O scorer/O of/O the/O Texans/O and/O was/O honored/O with/O the/O MVP/O of/O the/O Tampa/LOCATION Bay/LOCATION Sun/LOCATION Bowl/LOCATION tournament/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON studied/O the/O play/O of/O Argentina/LOCATION 's/O national/O team/O ,/O especially/O Diego/PERSON Maradona/PERSON ./O 
Clint/PERSON was/O heartbroken/O when/O the/O news/O came/O to/O Nacogdoches/LOCATION that/O Maradona/PERSON would/O not/O be/O playing/O in/O the/O 1994/O World/O Cup/O game/O played/O in/O the/O Cotton/O Bowl/O ./O 
He/O attended/O Furman/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION as/O a/O health/O and/O exercise/O major/O and/O a/O key/O player/O for/O Paladins/O football/O ./O 
Club/O career/O New/ORGANIZATION England/ORGANIZATION Revolution/ORGANIZATION New/ORGANIZATION England/ORGANIZATION Revolution/ORGANIZATION selected/O Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON eighth/O overall/O in/O the/O 2004/O MLS/O SuperDraft/O ./O 
In/O his/O rookie/O season/O ,/O he/O started/O 23/O of/O 24/O matches/O scoring/O seven/O goals/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON helped/O the/O Revolution/O to/O the/O Eastern/O Conference/O Finals/O and/O earned/O 2004/O MLS/O Rookie/O of/O the/O Year/O Honors/O ./O 
In/O 2005/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON contributed/O ten/O goals/O and/O nine/O assists/O in/O 26/O games/O ./O 
He/O scored/O the/O game-winning/O goal/O in/O the/O Eastern/ORGANIZATION Conference/ORGANIZATION Final/ORGANIZATION on/O his/O way/O to/O an/O appearance/O in/O the/O MLS/O Cup/O Final/O ./O 
In/O 2006/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON added/O 8/O more/O goals/O ,/O but/O missed/O significant/O time/O in/O the/O playoffs/O due/O to/O injury/O ./O 
He/O came/O on/O as/O a/O substitute/O in/O the/O MLS/O Cup/O Final/O ,/O but/O the/O Revolution/O lost/O their/O second/O straight/O final/O ,/O this/O time/O in/O a/O penalty/O shoot-out/O ./O 
Fulham/ORGANIZATION 2006/O --/O 07/O season/O In/O December/O 2006/O ,/O English/O club/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION offered/O MLS/O $/O 4/O million/O for/O the/O transfer/O of/O Dempsey/LOCATION ,/O then/O the/O largest/O amount/O ever/O offered/O for/O an/O MLS/ORGANIZATION player/O and/O became/O another/O American/O addition/O to/O the/O Cottagers/O roster/O ./O 
On/O January/O 11/O ,/O 2007/O ,/O he/O was/O granted/O a/O work/O permit/O from/O the/O Home/O Office/O as/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION announced/O his/O signing/O on/O a/O long-term/O deal/O ./O 
This/O made/O Dempsey/PERSON the/O most/O expensive/O US/LOCATION export/O to/O the/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION in/O a/O deal/O worth/O a/O reported/O #/O 2/O million/O ./O 
He/O made/O his/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION debut/O in/O a/O 1/O --/O 1/O home/O draw/O against/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/ORGANIZATION on/O January/O 20/O ,/O 2007/O ./O 
His/O FA/O Cup/O debut/O followed/O seven/O days/O later/O in/O a/O 3/O --/O 0/O home/O win/O over/O Stoke/ORGANIZATION City/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O first/O goal/O for/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION on/O 5/O May/O when/O he/O struck/O the/O only/O goal/O of/O a/O 1/O --/O 0/O home/O win/O over/O Liverpool/ORGANIZATION ./O 
This/O goal/O saved/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION from/O relegation/O and/O effectively/O guaranteed/O their/O place/O in/O the/O top-flight/O for/O the/O following/O season/O ./O 
2007/O --/O 08/O season/O On/O August/O 25/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O first/O goal/O of/O the/O 2007/O --/O 08/O season/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 1/O away/O loss/O to/O Aston/ORGANIZATION Villa/ORGANIZATION ./O 
He/O followed/O this/O up/O by/O scoring/O in/O Fulham/LOCATION 's/O next/O fixture/O in/O a/O 3/O --/O 3/O home/O draw/O against/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION on/O 1/O September/O ./O 
Two/O weeks/O later/O ,/O he/O opened/O the/O scoring/O in/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O 1/O --/O 1/O away/O draw/O against/O Wigan/ORGANIZATION Athletic/ORGANIZATION ./O 
These/O goals/O gave/O Dempsey/PERSON three/O in/O as/O many/O games/O after/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION manager/O Lawrie/PERSON Sanchez/PERSON 's/O decision/O to/O convert/O Dempsey/PERSON into/O a/O striker/O following/O an/O injury/O to/O compatriot/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON ./O 
On/O September/O 29/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON was/O involved/O in/O an/O aerial/O collision/O with/O John/PERSON Terry/PERSON during/O a/O 0/O --/O 0/O draw/O at/O Stamford/LOCATION Bridge/LOCATION which/O resulted/O in/O Terry/PERSON being/O substituted/O ./O 
There/O was/O some/O suggestion/O that/O Dempsey/PERSON used/O a/O deliberate/O elbow/O on/O Terry/PERSON ;/O however/O ,/O he/O was/O n't/O punished/O for/O the/O incident/O as/O referee/O Martin/PERSON Atkinson/PERSON did/O n't/O report/O it/O to/O the/O Football/ORGANIZATION Association/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O November/O 3/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O during/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O 3/O --/O 1/O home/O win/O over/O Reading/O to/O secure/O just/O a/O second/O league/O win/O of/O the/O season/O ./O 
He/O scored/O his/O last/O goals/O of/O the/O season/O in/O a/O 1/O --/O 1/O home/O draw/O with/O Wigan/ORGANIZATION Athletic/ORGANIZATION and/O 5/O --/O 1/O away/O loss/O to/O Tottenham/LOCATION in/O December/O ./O 
In/O May/O 2008/O ,/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION announced/O Dempsey/PERSON had/O signed/O a/O contract/O extension/O which/O would/O keep/O him/O at/O the/O club/O until/O the/O summer/O of/O 2010/O ./O 
Fulham/ORGANIZATION beat/O Portsmouth/ORGANIZATION 1/O --/O 0/O on/O the/O final/O day/O of/O the/O season/O to/O secure/O Premier/O League/O status/O for/O another/O year/O ./O 
He/O ended/O the/O season/O as/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O top/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION goalscorer/O with/O six/O goals/O ./O 
2008/O --/O 09/O season/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O first/O goal/O of/O the/O 2008/O --/O 09/O season/O in/O a/O 1/O --/O 1/O away/O draw/O at/O Portsmouth/LOCATION on/O October/O 26/O ./O 
His/O first/O home/O goal/O of/O the/O season/O came/O in/O a/O 3/O --/O 0/O win/O over/O Middlesbrough/ORGANIZATION on/O December/O 20/O ./O 
Eight/O days/O later/O he/O scored/O twice/O in/O the/O West/LOCATION London/LOCATION derby/O against/O Chelsea/ORGANIZATION which/O included/O a/O last-minute/O equaliser/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 2/O home/O draw/O ./O 
On/O February/O 24/O ,/O 2009/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O the/O first/O FA/O Cup/O goal/O of/O his/O career/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 1/O home/O win/O over/O Swansea/LOCATION City/LOCATION in/O the/O fifth-round/O ./O 
His/O final/O home/O goal/O of/O the/O season/O came/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 1/O defeat/O to/O Blackburn/ORGANIZATION Rovers/ORGANIZATION on/O March/O 11/O ./O 
Fulham/ORGANIZATION came/O from/O a/O goal/O down/O to/O beat/O Manchester/ORGANIZATION City/ORGANIZATION 3/O --/O 1/O away/O from/O home/O as/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O two/O goals/O on/O April/O 12/O ./O 
For/O the/O second/O successive/O season/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON ended/O as/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O top/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION goalscorer/O joint/O with/O Andrew/PERSON Johnson/PERSON with/O seven/O goals/O ./O 
These/O goals/O helped/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION secure/O a/O seventh-place/O finish/O in/O the/O Premier/O League/O ,/O the/O highest/O in/O the/O club/O 's/O history/O ,/O and/O confirmed/O their/O qualification/O for/O the/O newly/O formed/O UEFA/ORGANIZATION Europa/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION for/O the/O following/O season/O ./O 
2009/O --/O 10/O season/O On/O 13/O August/O 2009/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON signed/O a/O contract/O extension/O to/O remain/O with/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION through/O 2013/O ./O 
On/O August/O 20/O ,/O he/O scored/O his/O first/O goal/O in/O European/O competition/O ,/O in/O the/O newly/O formed/O Europa/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ,/O netting/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O second/O goal/O in/O a/O 3/O --/O 1/O win/O against/O Amkar/ORGANIZATION Perm/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O play-off/O round/O ./O 
On/O December/O 30/O ,/O La/LOCATION Gazzetta/LOCATION dello/O Sport/O named/O Dempsey/PERSON as/O one/O of/O the/O top/O eleven/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION players/O of/O the/O season/O ./O 
On/O January/O 17/O ,/O 2010/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON suffered/O a/O suspected/O cruciate/O knee/O ligament/O injury/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 0/O away/O defeat/O to/O Blackburn/ORGANIZATION Rovers/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O March/O 11/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON returned/O ,/O coming/O on/O in/O the/O last/O minute/O of/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O loss/O away/O to/O Juventus/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O then/O completed/O 72/O minutes/O of/O their/O away/O loss/O to/O Manchester/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O league/O ./O 
On/O March/O 18/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON came/O off/O the/O bench/O against/O Juventus/ORGANIZATION in/O their/O second-leg/O ,/O last-16/O tie/O in/O the/O Europa/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION and/O scored/O the/O winner/O on/O a/O long/O chip/O shot/O ./O 
Fulham/ORGANIZATION won/O the/O game/O 4/O --/O 1/O and/O this/O game/O resulted/O in/O Fulham/LOCATION winning/O an/O award/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O Dempsey/PERSON receiving/O an/O award/O for/O his/O `/O Wonderful/O '/O -LRB-/O Quote/O from/O the/O commentator/O on/O ESPN/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/O goal/O ./O 
The/O Guardian/O suggested/O that/O the/O goal/O ``/O might/O become/O the/O most/O famous/O goal/O in/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O history/O ''/O ./O 
On/O May/O 12/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON replaced/O Bobby/PERSON Zamora/PERSON in/O the/O 55th/O minute/O of/O the/O 2010/O UEFA/ORGANIZATION Europa/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION Final/O ,/O thus/O making/O history/O in/O becoming/O the/O first/O ever/O American/O to/O appear/O in/O a/O major/O European/LOCATION final/O ./O 
In/O the/O end/O ,/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION lost/O the/O match/O ,/O as/O Atlético/ORGANIZATION Madrid/ORGANIZATION 's/O Diego/PERSON Forlán/PERSON scored/O in/O the/O 116th/O minute/O of/O extra/O time/O ,/O giving/O Atlético/ORGANIZATION a/O 2/O --/O 1/O win/O ./O 
His/O performances/O throughout/O 2009/O --/O 10/O earned/O him/O the/O designation/O of/O Most/O Valuable/O Player/O among/O Americans/O in/O Europe/LOCATION by/O SoccerOverThere.com/O ,/O among/O other/O sources/O ./O 
2010/O --/O 11/O season/O Dempsey/PERSON remained/O a/O regular/O starter/O ,/O one/O of/O only/O five/O Americans/O in/O the/O Premier/O League/O to/O do/O so/O currently/O ./O 
On/O September/O 18/O ,/O 2010/O ,/O he/O scored/O an/O equalising/O goal/O on/O 56/O minutes/O with/O a/O header/O against/O Blackburn/ORGANIZATION Rovers/ORGANIZATION at/O Ewood/LOCATION Park/LOCATION in/O the/O 1/O --/O 1/O draw/O and/O continue/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O undefeated/O streak/O in/O the/O Barclays/ORGANIZATION Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O October/O 2/O ,/O he/O scored/O against/O West/ORGANIZATION Ham/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION past/O Robert/PERSON Green/PERSON ,/O the/O same/O keeper/O that/O he/O had/O scored/O against/O in/O the/O World/O Cup/O ./O 
He/O then/O continued/O his/O form/O by/O scoring/O two/O goals/O against/O Wigan/ORGANIZATION Athletic/ORGANIZATION on/O October/O 30/O as/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION ran/O out/O 2/O --/O 0/O winners/O ./O 
On/O January/O 22/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O another/O double/O versus/O Stoke/O ,/O putting/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION temporarily/O out/O of/O relegation/O contention/O ./O 
On/O March/O 19/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON became/O the/O first/O American/O to/O score/O 10/O goals/O in/O a/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION season/O ,/O beating/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON 's/O previous/O record/O of/O nine/O ,/O also/O set/O while/O at/O Fulham/LOCATION in/O the/O 2005/O --/O 06/O season/O and/O 2006/O --/O 07/O season/O ./O 
Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON broke/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION 's/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION goalscoring/O record/O by/O netting/O twice/O in/O a/O 3/O --/O 0/O victory/O over/O Bolton/PERSON on/O April/O 27/O ,/O 2011/O ./O 
He/O has/O scored/O a/O total/O of/O 33/O goals/O for/O the/O team/O in/O the/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ,/O topping/O both/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON and/O Steed/PERSON Malbranque/PERSON ,/O each/O with/O 32/O ./O 
With/O these/O goals/O ,/O he/O scored/O 12/O goals/O for/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O 2010/O --/O 11/O season/O ./O 
At/O the/O end/O of/O the/O season/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON was/O voted/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION player/O of/O the/O season/O by/O the/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION fans/O and/O his/O 12/O Premier/O League/O strikes/O meant/O he/O was/O the/O club/O 's/O leading/O goalscorer/O for/O the/O campaign/O ./O 
2011/O --/O 12/O season/O Dempsey/PERSON marked/O his/O return/O to/O the/O first/O team/O by/O scoring/O a/O brace/O in/O the/O first/O leg/O of/O their/O Europa/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION play-off/O clash/O against/O Dnipro/ORGANIZATION Dnipropetrovsk/ORGANIZATION at/O Craven/ORGANIZATION Cottage/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON ended/O with/O two/O goals/O as/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION ran/O out/O 3/O --/O 0/O winners/O ,/O setting/O up/O a/O comfortable/O second/O leg/O in/O Ukraine/LOCATION ./O 
On/O December/O 5/O ,/O 2011/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O in/O the/O 85th/O minute/O to/O secure/O a/O 1/O --/O 0/O win/O against/O Liverpool/ORGANIZATION at/O Craven/ORGANIZATION Cottage/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O goal/O propelled/O Dempsey/PERSON to/O become/O the/O most/O prolific/O American/O goalscorer/O in/O the/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION ,/O passing/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION legend/O and/O fellow/O American/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O fifth/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION goal/O of/O the/O campaign/O with/O a/O header/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 0/O home/O win/O against/O Bolton/PERSON on/O December/O 17/O ,/O lifting/O his/O side/O six/O points/O clear/O of/O the/O drop/O zone/O ./O 
In/O the/O club/O 's/O West/LOCATION London/LOCATION derby/O against/O rivals/O Chelsea/ORGANIZATION on/O Boxing/O Day/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O the/O equalizing/O goal/O as/O the/O game/O ended/O in/O a/O 1/O --/O 1/O draw/O ./O 
He/O then/O scored/O the/O first/O hat-trick/O of/O his/O career/O on/O January/O 7/O against/O Charlton/PERSON in/O their/O FA/O Cup/O Third/O Round/O game/O which/O ended/O in/O a/O 4/O --/O 0/O victory/O ./O 
On/O 21/O January/O 2012/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O another/O hat-trick/O against/O Newcastle/ORGANIZATION while/O the/O game/O ended/O in/O a/O 5/O --/O 2/O win/O for/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION and/O sent/O his/O goal/O tally/O in/O the/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION to/O nine/O for/O the/O season/O ./O 
With/O his/O hat-trick/O against/O Newcastle/ORGANIZATION ,/O he/O became/O the/O first/O ever/O American/O player/O to/O score/O a/O hat-trick/O in/O the/O Premier/O League/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O 10th/O Premier/O League/O goal/O of/O the/O season/O ,/O sixteenth/O in/O all/O competitions/O ,/O in/O a/O 1/O --/O 1/O draw/O against/O former/O manager/O Roy/PERSON Hodgson/PERSON 's/O West/LOCATION Brom/LOCATION on/O February/O 1/O ,/O 2011/O ./O 
This/O recent/O run/O of/O good/O form/O has/O seen/O Dempsey/PERSON play/O higher-up/O the/O field/O into/O an/O orthodox/O striker/O position/O ./O 
He/O ``/O assisted/O ''/O another/O goal/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 1/O win/O against/O Stoke/ORGANIZATION City/ORGANIZATION on/O February/O 11/O ,/O 2012/O ./O 
His/O 28th-minute/O shot/O hit/O the/O crossbar/O and/O was/O deflected/O by/O Stoke/O goalkeeper/O Thomas/PERSON Sørensen/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O therefore/O awarded/O as/O an/O own/O goal/O off/O the/O goalie/O ./O 
His/O form/O this/O season/O continued/O against/O Wolverhampton/ORGANIZATION Wanderers/ORGANIZATION where/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O twice/O in/O a/O 5/O --/O 0/O victory/O for/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION ./O 
On/O 8/O March/O 2012/O ,/O the/O day/O before/O Dempsey/PERSON 's/O 29th/O birthday/O ,/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION manager/O Martin/PERSON Jol/PERSON revealed/O that/O the/O club/O have/O opened/O talks/O with/O the/O American/O over/O a/O new/O three-year/O contract/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O fourteenth/O and/O fifteenth/O Premier/O League/O goals/O of/O the/O campaign/O ,/O bringing/O his/O tally/O to/O twenty-one/O in/O all/O competitions/O ,/O in/O a/O 3/O --/O 0/O away/O win/O over/O Bolton/ORGANIZATION Wanderers/ORGANIZATION on/O April/O 7/O ,/O the/O first/O a/O free/O kick/O and/O the/O second/O a/O header/O ./O 
The/O strikes/O moved/O Dempsey/PERSON past/O Louis/PERSON Saha/PERSON 's/O record/O of/O thirteen/O Premier/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION goals/O for/O the/O club/O in/O a/O single/O season/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON finished/O fourth/O on/O the/O FWA/O Footballer/O of/O the/O Year/O list/O behind/O winner/O Robin/PERSON van/PERSON Persie/PERSON and/O Manchester/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION pair/O Wayne/PERSON Rooney/PERSON and/O Paul/PERSON Scholes/PERSON ,/O who/O came/O in/O second/O and/O third/O ,/O respectively/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON became/O the/O first/O American/O to/O reach/O the/O milestone/O of/O fifty/O goals/O in/O the/O Premier/O League/O ,/O with/O a/O free-kick/O against/O Sunderland/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O last/O home/O game/O of/O the/O season/O ./O 
On/O 7/O June/O 2012/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON was/O voted/O the/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION `/O Player/O of/O the/O Season/O '/O by/O fans/O for/O the/O second/O straight/O season/O ./O 
On/O 31/O August/O 2012/O ,/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION confirmed/O Dempsey/PERSON 's/O transfer/O to/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Tottenham/O Hotspur/O On/O 31/O August/O 2012/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON joined/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/ORGANIZATION on/O a/O three-year/O contract/O for/O a/O fee/O believed/O to/O be/O in/O the/O region/O of/O #/O 6/O million/O -LRB-/O $/O 9.5/O million/O -RRB-/O ./O 
The/O deal/O made/O Dempsey/PERSON the/O highest/O salaried/O US/LOCATION football/O player/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
With/O the/O 23/O shirt/O that/O he/O wore/O at/O Fulham/LOCATION and/O the/O number/O 8/O that/O he/O usually/O wears/O on/O international/O duty/O unavailable/O ,/O he/O opted/O for/O the/O number/O 2/O jersey/O which/O he/O wore/O at/O Furman/ORGANIZATION University/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O first/O and/O the/O game-winning/O goal/O for/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION in/O a/O 3/O --/O 2/O win/O over/O Manchester/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION ./O 
It/O was/O the/O first/O time/O in/O 23/O years/O that/O Tottenham/ORGANIZATION had/O won/O at/O Old/LOCATION Trafford/LOCATION ./O 
He/O scored/O his/O second/O goal/O for/O Spurs/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O 39th/O minute/O in/O an/O away/O game/O at/O Southampton/LOCATION in/O October/O ./O 
Dempsay/PERSON 3rd/O goal/O was/O scored/O against/O Reading/O on/O New/O Year/O 's/O day/O 2013/O to/O help/O his/O Spurs/ORGANIZATION side/O win/O 3/O --/O 1/O ./O 
In/O the/O FA/O Cup/O 3rd/O round/O ,/O he/O scored/O a/O double/O against/O Coventry/O ./O 
International/O career/O Dempsey/PERSON first/O played/O for/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION national/O team/O at/O the/O 2003/O FIFA/ORGANIZATION World/ORGANIZATION Youth/ORGANIZATION Championship/ORGANIZATION in/O the/O United/LOCATION Arab/LOCATION Emirates/LOCATION ./O 
He/O made/O his/O first/O appearance/O with/O the/O senior/O team/O on/O November/O 17/O ,/O 2004/O ,/O against/O Jamaica/LOCATION ./O 
He/O has/O frequently/O lined/O up/O as/O a/O striker/O due/O to/O his/O scoring/O threat/O and/O aerial/O ability/O ,/O but/O his/O preferred/O and/O more/O normal/O role/O is/O off/O the/O striker/O ./O 
He/O won/O the/O highest/O individual/O honor/O in/O football/O in/O America/LOCATION when/O he/O was/O named/O Honda/ORGANIZATION Player/O of/O the/O Year/O for/O 2006/O ,/O beating/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION teammates/O Kasey/PERSON Keller/PERSON and/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON in/O a/O poll/O of/O sportswriters/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON received/O 237/O points/O in/O voting/O by/O 207/O sports/O journalists/O to/O claim/O the/O award/O ./O 
On/O May/O 2/O ,/O 2006/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON was/O named/O to/O the/O U.S./LOCATION roster/O for/O the/O 2006/O World/O Cup/O in/O Germany/LOCATION ./O 
He/O was/O the/O only/O American/O player/O to/O score/O a/O goal/O in/O the/O tournament/O with/O his/O equalizing/O goal/O in/O the/O Americans/O '/O eventual/O 2/O --/O 1/O loss/O to/O Ghana/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION '/O opening/O 2010/O World/O Cup/O qualifier/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON recorded/O the/O then/O fastest/O goal/O in/O U.S./LOCATION qualifying/O history/O with/O a/O chest/O trap/O and/O sliding/O shot/O 53/O seconds/O into/O a/O 8/O --/O 0/O defeat/O of/O Barbados/LOCATION ./O 
But/O thereafter/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON experienced/O a/O dip/O in/O form/O leading/O some/O to/O doubt/O his/O first-choice/O status/O with/O the/O national/O team/O ./O 
However/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON turned/O his/O fortunes/O around/O in/O the/O 2009/O FIFA/ORGANIZATION Confederations/O Cup/O ./O 
In/O the/O final/O group/O stage/O match/O against/O Egypt/LOCATION ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O a/O trademark/O diving/O header/O off/O a/O Jonathan/PERSON Spector/PERSON cross/O ,/O making/O the/O final/O result/O 3/O --/O 0/O ./O 
This/O ,/O combined/O with/O Brazil/LOCATION 's/O 3/O --/O 0/O victory/O against/O Italy/LOCATION in/O the/O other/O group/O match/O that/O was/O being/O played/O simultaneously/O ,/O put/O the/O U.S./LOCATION through/O to/O the/O semifinals/O ./O 
In/O the/O semi-final/O match/O against/O Spain/LOCATION ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O to/O put/O the/O USA/LOCATION up/O 2/O --/O 0/O to/O send/O them/O to/O the/O finals/O ./O 
He/O was/O named/O the/O Man/O of/O the/O Match/O for/O his/O performance/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON scored/O in/O his/O third/O straight/O game/O in/O the/O Confederations/O Cup/O Final/O against/O Brazil/LOCATION ,/O redirecting/O a/O similar/O cross/O from/O Spector/PERSON in/O the/O 10th/O minute/O to/O open/O the/O scoring/O ./O 
Following/O the/O loss/O ,/O he/O was/O awarded/O the/O Bronze/O Ball/O as/O the/O tournament/O 's/O 3rd/O best/O performer/O ./O 
He/O ended/O the/O World/O Cup/O qualifying/O campaign/O tied/O with/O Landon/PERSON Donovan/PERSON as/O the/O team/O 's/O second/O top/O scorer/O ,/O behind/O Jozy/PERSON Altidore/PERSON ,/O with/O five/O goals/O in/O thirteen/O matches/O ./O 
On/O June/O 12/O ,/O 2010/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON became/O the/O second/O American/O -LRB-/O after/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON -RRB-/O to/O score/O in/O more/O than/O one/O World/O Cup/O when/O he/O scored/O the/O equalizer/O goal/O against/O England/LOCATION in/O the/O Americans/O '/O first/O game/O of/O the/O 2010/O World/O Cup/O after/O the/O West/LOCATION Ham/LOCATION and/O England/LOCATION goalkeeper/O Robert/PERSON Green/PERSON made/O a/O major/O error/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON 's/O disallowed/O goal/O later/O in/O the/O tournament/O vs./O Algeria/LOCATION in/O the/O group/O stage/O was/O very/O controversial/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON was/O called/O offside/O ,/O but/O the/O replay/O showed/O that/O he/O was/O most/O likely/O not/O offside/O ./O 
Despite/O this/O call/O ,/O his/O teammate/O Landon/PERSON Donovan/PERSON scored/O a/O late/O stoppage/O time/O goal/O to/O win/O the/O game/O 1/O --/O 0/O ./O 
During/O the/O 2011/O Gold/O Cup/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON played/O a/O key/O role/O in/O helping/O the/O U.S./LOCATION advance/O to/O the/O finals/O ./O 
In/O the/O group/O stages/O he/O recorded/O a/O goal/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 0/O win/O over/O Canada/LOCATION ,/O and/O in/O the/O quarterfinals/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON also/O scored/O a/O goal/O in/O a/O 2/O --/O 0/O win/O over/O Jamaica/LOCATION ./O 
In/O the/O semi-finals/O against/O Panama/LOCATION ,/O who/O had/O shockingly/O defeated/O the/O U.S./LOCATION 1/O --/O 2/O in/O the/O group/O stage/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O the/O only/O goal/O to/O advance/O the/O Americans/O to/O the/O final/O ./O 
With/O a/O sliding/O touch/O Dempsey/PERSON redirected/O U.S./LOCATION Midfielder/O Landon/PERSON Donovan/PERSON 's/O pass/O into/O the/O net/O ./O 
On/O February/O 29/O ,/O 2012/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O the/O lone/O goal/O in/O an/O international/O friendly/O against/O four/O time/O World/O Cup/O Champion/O Italy/LOCATION ./O 
Jozy/PERSON Altidore/PERSON assisted/O on/O the/O goal/O ,/O allowing/O the/O U.S./LOCATION to/O win/O for/O the/O first/O time/O against/O Italy/LOCATION in/O eleven/O games/O played/O since/O 1934/O ./O 
Dempsey/PERSON broke/O his/O own/O fastest-goal/O record/O in/O World/O Cup/O Qualifying/O on/O September/O 7/O ,/O scoring/O just/O 39/O seconds/O into/O a/O 2/O --/O 1/O defeat/O against/O Jamaica/LOCATION in/O Kingston/LOCATION ./O 
During/O a/O qualifying/O match/O against/O Guatemala/LOCATION on/O October/O 16/O ,/O 2012/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON scored/O his/O 29th/O and/O 30th/O international/O goal/O ,/O tying/O him/O with/O Brian/PERSON McBride/PERSON for/O third/O most/O goals/O scored/O for/O the/O U.S./ORGANIZATION National/ORGANIZATION Team/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O goals/O helped/O the/O U.S./LOCATION advance/O into/O the/O final/O qualifying/O stage/O for/O World/O Cup/O 2014/O ./O 
International/O goals/O Playing/O style/O Dempsey/PERSON is/O a/O versatile/O right/O footed/O withdrawn/O forward/O ,/O normally/O playing/O on/O the/O left/O or/O right/O for/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ,/O at/O times/O shooting/O from/O long/O distances/O and/O even/O scoring/O at/O club/O level/O from/O said/O long/O range/O shots/O ./O 
However/O ,/O he/O has/O also/O proven/O to/O be/O more/O of/O a/O threat/O the/O closer/O to/O goal/O he/O gets/O ./O 
His/O goals/O against/O Egypt/LOCATION and/O Spain/LOCATION in/O the/O Confederations/O Cup/O came/O almost/O immediately/O after/O being/O moved/O to/O forward/O by/O a/O substitution/O from/O Bob/PERSON Bradley/PERSON ./O 
Known/O for/O his/O toughness/O and/O resilience/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON played/O two/O games/O for/O New/LOCATION England/LOCATION Revolution/O with/O a/O broken/O jaw/O in/O 2004/O before/O the/O team/O trainer/O diagnosed/O it/O ,/O and/O upon/O his/O return/O ,/O he/O played/O through/O the/O pain/O of/O a/O sprained/O ankle/O ./O 
Despite/O usually/O playing/O in/O wide/O positions/O ,/O he/O frequently/O scores/O close-range/O goals/O and/O has/O scored/O repeatedly/O with/O diving/O headers/O in/O crowded/O situations/O ./O 
His/O tenacity/O in/O midfield/LOCATION combined/O with/O his/O audacious/O close/O control/O dribbling/O skills/O frequently/O results/O in/O opponents/O fouling/O him/O ,/O and/O Dempsey/PERSON has/O gained/O a/O reputation/O for/O fierce/O play/O ./O 
This/O has/O on/O several/O occasions/O lapsed/O into/O violent/O conduct/O ./O 
He/O was/O suspended/O by/O the/O New/O England/O Revolution/O for/O two/O weeks/O in/O March/O 2006/O for/O a/O fist/O fight/O with/O teammate/O Joe/PERSON Franchino/PERSON during/O a/O practice/O game/O and/O was/O twice/O suspended/O by/O MLS/ORGANIZATION during/O the/O 2006/O season/O for/O violent/O conduct/O against/O opponents/O ,/O including/O an/O elbow/O that/O broke/O the/O jaw/O of/O national/O teammate/O Jimmy/PERSON Conrad/PERSON ./O 
In/O a/O similar/O incident/O with/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION in/O 2007/O ,/O Dempsey/PERSON accidentally/O broke/O the/O cheekbone/O of/O Chelsea/ORGANIZATION defender/O John/PERSON Terry/PERSON in/O an/O aerial/O challenge/O but/O was/O not/O penalized/O ./O 
A/O further/O similar/O incident/O ,/O in/O December/O 2011/O ,/O took/O place/O in/O a/O match/O against/O Manchester/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION ,/O with/O Dempsey/PERSON accidentally/O elbowing/O opponent/O Phil/PERSON Jones/PERSON in/O the/O side/O of/O the/O head/O and/O causing/O a/O suspected/O broken/O cheekbone/O ./O 
Again/O no/O action/O was/O taken/O by/O the/O referee/O ./O 
Career/O statistics/O Club/O As/O of/O 23:00/O ,/O 24/O December/O 2012/O -LRB-/O UTC/O -RRB-/O International/O As/O of/O 17/O October/O 2012/O Honors/O Club/O New/O England/O Revolution/O Runner-up/O MLS/O Cup/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O :/O 2005/O ,/O 2006/O MLS/O Supporters/O '/O Shield/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O :/O 2005/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION Runner-up/O UEFA/ORGANIZATION Europa/ORGANIZATION League/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O :/O 2009/O --/O 10/O International/ORGANIZATION United/ORGANIZATION States/ORGANIZATION Winner/ORGANIZATION CONCACAF/ORGANIZATION Gold/O Cup/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O :/O 2005/O ,/O 2007/O Runner-up/O FIFA/ORGANIZATION Confederations/O Cup/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O :/O 2009/O Individual/O MLS/O Rookie/O of/O the/O Year/O Award/O -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O :/O 2004/O Honda/O Player/O of/O the/O Year/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O :/O 2006/O ,/O 2011/O MLS/O Best/O XI/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O :/O 2005/O ,/O 2006/O U.S./LOCATION Soccer/O Athlete/O of/O the/O Year/O -LRB-/O 3/O -RRB-/O :/O 2007/O ,/O 2011/O ,/O 2012/O FIFA/ORGANIZATION Confederations/ORGANIZATION Cup/ORGANIZATION Bronze/ORGANIZATION Ball/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/O 1/O -RRB-/O :/O 2009/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION Player/O of/O the/O Season/O -LRB-/O 2/O -RRB-/O :/O 2010/O --/O 11/O ,/O 2011/O --/O 12/O Premiership/O Player/O of/O the/O Season/O :/O 4th/O place/O in/O 2011/O --/O 12/O Personal/O life/O Dempsey/PERSON is/O married/O to/O Bethany/PERSON Keegan/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON ./O 
They/O have/O a/O daughter/O named/O Elyse/PERSON and/O a/O son/O named/O Jackson/PERSON ./O 
-LRB-/O citation/O needed/O -RRB-/O In/O his/O spare/O time/O he/O is/O a/O fisherman/O ./O 
Music/O One/O of/O Dempsey/PERSON 's/O passions/O outside/O of/O soccer/O is/O hip/O hop/O music/O ./O 
Using/O the/O alias/O ``/O Deuce/O ,/O ''/O he/O ,/O along/O with/O fellow/O Texas/LOCATION rappers/O XO/ORGANIZATION and/O the/O late/O Houston/LOCATION rapper/O Big/O Hawk/O from/O the/O Screwed/O Up/O Click/O ,/O are/O featured/O rapping/O the/O song/O ``/O Do/O n't/O Tread/O ''/O in/O a/O Nike/ORGANIZATION football/O advertising/O campaign/O for/O the/O 2006/O World/O Cup/O with/O the/O intention/O to/O showcase/O both/O the/O sport/O 's/O working-class/O roots/O and/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION team/O ahead/O of/O the/O World/O Cup/O ./O 
The/O song/O 's/O video/O is/O dedicated/O to/O his/O sister/O Jennifer/PERSON ,/O who/O ,/O at/O age/O sixteen/O ,/O was/O suddenly/O struck/O with/O a/O fatal/O brain/O aneurysm/O ./O 
At/O Dempsey/PERSON 's/O request/O ,/O the/O video/O ends/O with/O a/O shot/O of/O him/O placing/O a/O flower/O at/O her/O grave/O ./O 
Notes/O References/O External/O links/O Profile/O at/O Yanks/ORGANIZATION Abroad/O Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON career/O stats/O at/O Soccerbase/O Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON profile/O Fulham/ORGANIZATION FC/O Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON profile/O Transfermarkt/O Andrea/PERSON Scanzi/PERSON La/O palombella/O rossa/O di/O Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON La/PERSON Stampa/PERSON ,/O 19/O March/O 2010/O Premier/O League/O profile/O Profile/O at/O SoccerSurfer.com/O Clint/PERSON Dempsey/PERSON --/O UEFA/ORGANIZATION competition/O record/O 
