English/english/JJ/MISC language/language/NN/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O article/article/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O about/about/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O other/other/JJ/O uses/use/NNS/O ,/,/,/O see/see/VB/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O disambiguation/disambiguation/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O West/West/NNP/MISC Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC language/language/NN/O that/that/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL spoken/speak/VBN/O in/in/IN/O early/early/JJ/O medieval/medieval/JJ/DATE England/England/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O is/be/VBZ/O now/now/RB/DATE the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O widely/widely/RB/O used/use/VBN/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O spoken/speak/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL language/language/NN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O majority/majority/NN/O populations/population/NNS/O of/of/IN/O several/several/JJ/O sovereign/sovereign/JJ/O states/state/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Canada/Canada/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Australia/Australia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Ireland/Ireland/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION Zealand/Zealand/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O a/a/DT/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O Caribbean/Caribbean/NNP/LOCATION nations/nation/NNS/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O third-most-common/third-most-common/JJ/O native/native/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O Mandarin/Mandarin/NNP/O Chinese/Chinese/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O Spanish/Spanish/NNP/MISC ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O widely/widely/RB/O learned/learn/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/DURATION second/second/JJ/DURATION language/language/NN/O and/and/CC/O is/be/VBZ/O an/a/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O European/European/NNP/ORGANIZATION Union/Union/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O many/many/JJ/O Commonwealth/Commonwealth/NNP/ORGANIZATION countries/country/NNS/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION Nations/Nations/NNPS/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O in/in/IN/O many/many/JJ/O world/world/NN/O organizations/organization/NNS/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC arose/arise/VBD/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Anglo-Saxon/anglo-saxon/JJ/MISC kingdoms/kingdom/NNS/O of/of/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O what/what/WP/O is/be/VBZ/O now/now/RB/DATE southeast/southeast/JJ/O Scotland/Scotland/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Following/follow/VBG/O the/the/DT/O extensive/extensive/JJ/O influence/influence/NN/O of/of/IN/O Great/great/JJ/LOCATION Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 17th/17th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE to/to/TO/DATE the/the/DT/DATE mid-20th/mid-20th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O through/through/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/O Empire/empire/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O also/also/RB/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION since/since/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE mid-20th/mid-20th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O it/it/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O been/be/VBN/O widely/widely/RB/O propagated/propagate/VBN/O around/around/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O leading/lead/VBG/O language/language/NN/O of/of/IN/O international/international/JJ/O discourse/discourse/NN/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O in/in/IN/O many/many/JJ/O regions/region/NNS/O ./././O
Historically/Historically/NNP/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC originated/originate/VBD/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O fusion/fusion/NN/O of/of/IN/O closely/closely/RB/O related/related/JJ/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ,/,/,/O now/now/RB/DATE collectively/collectively/RB/O termed/term/VBN/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O were/be/VBD/O brought/bring/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O eastern/eastern/JJ/O coast/coast/NN/O of/of/IN/O Great/great/JJ/LOCATION Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION by/by/IN/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC settlers/settler/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Anglo-Saxons/anglo-saxon/NNS/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 5th/5th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE --/--/:/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O word/word/NN/O English/English/NNP/MISC being/be/VBG/O derived/derive/VBN/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O name/name/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Angles/Angles/NNPS/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O ultimately/ultimately/RB/O from/from/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O ancestral/ancestral/JJ/O region/region/NN/O of/of/IN/O Angeln/Angeln/NNP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O in/in/IN/O what/what/WP/O is/be/VBZ/O now/now/RB/DATE Schleswig-Holstein/Schleswig-Holstein/NNP/LOCATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
A/a/DT/O significant/significant/JJ/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC words/word/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O constructed/construct/VBN/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O basis/basis/NN/O of/of/IN/O roots/root/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O ,/,/,/O because/because/IN/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O in/in/IN/O some/some/DT/O form/form/NN/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Christian/Christian/NNP/ORGANIZATION Church/Church/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O of/of/IN/O European/european/JJ/MISC intellectual/intellectual/JJ/O life/life/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O was/be/VBD/O further/further/JJ/O influenced/influence/VBN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O Old/Old/NNP/MISC Norse/Norse/NNP/MISC language/language/NN/O because/because/IN/O of/of/IN/O Viking/viking/JJ/O invasions/invasion/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 8th/8th/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/ORDINAL 9th/9th/JJ/ORDINAL centuries/century/NNS/DURATION ./././O
The/the/DT/O Norman/Norman/NNP/O conquest/conquest/NN/O of/of/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 11th/11th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE gave/give/VBD/O rise/rise/NN/O to/to/TO/O heavy/heavy/JJ/O borrowings/borrowing/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Norman-French/Norman-French/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O and/and/CC/O spelling/spelling/NN/O conventions/convention/NNS/O began/begin/VBD/O to/to/TO/O give/give/VB/O the/the/DT/O appearance/appearance/NN/O of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O close/close/JJ/O relationship/relationship/NN/O with/with/IN/O Romance/romance/NN/O languages/language/NNS/O to/to/TO/O what/what/WP/O had/have/VBD/O then/then/RB/O become/become/VBN/O Middle/Middle/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
The/the/DT/O Great/Great/NNP/O Vowel/Vowel/NNP/O Shift/shift/NN/O that/that/WDT/O began/begin/VBD/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O south/south/NN/O of/of/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 15th/15th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE is/be/VBZ/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O historical/historical/JJ/O events/event/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O mark/mark/VBP/O the/the/DT/O emergence/emergence/NN/O of/of/IN/O Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC from/from/IN/O Middle/Middle/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
Owing/owe/VBG/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O assimilation/assimilation/NN/O of/of/IN/O words/word/NNS/O from/from/IN/O many/many/JJ/O other/other/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O throughout/throughout/IN/O history/history/NN/O ,/,/,/O modern/modern/JJ/O English/English/NNP/MISC contains/contain/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O very/very/RB/O large/large/JJ/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O complex/complex/NN/O and/and/CC/O irregular/irregular/JJ/O spelling/spelling/NN/O ,/,/,/O particularly/particularly/RB/O of/of/IN/O vowels/vowel/NNS/O ./././O
Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC has/have/VBZ/O not/not/RB/O only/only/RB/O assimilated/assimilated/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O from/from/IN/O other/other/JJ/O European/european/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O from/from/IN/O all/all/DT/O over/over/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O Oxford/Oxford/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC Dictionary/Dictionary/NNP/MISC lists/list/VBZ/O over/over/IN/O 250,000/250,000/CD/NUMBER distinct/distinct/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O ,/,/,/O not/not/RB/O including/include/VBG/O many/many/JJ/O technical/technical/JJ/O ,/,/,/O scientific/scientific/JJ/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O slang/slang/NN/O terms/term/NNS/O ./././O
Significance/significance/NN/O ./././O
Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O sometimes/sometimes/RB/O described/describe/VBN/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL global/global/JJ/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O ,/,/,/O is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O dominant/dominant/JJ/O language/language/NN/O or/or/CC/O in/in/IN/O some/some/DT/O instances/instance/NNS/O even/even/RB/O the/the/DT/O required/required/JJ/O international/international/JJ/O language/language/NN/O of/of/IN/O communications/communication/NNS/O ,/,/,/O science/science/NN/O ,/,/,/O information/information/NN/O technology/technology/NN/O ,/,/,/O business/business/NN/O ,/,/,/O seafaring/seafaring/NN/O ,/,/,/O aviation/aviation/NN/O ,/,/,/O entertainment/entertainment/NN/O ,/,/,/O radio/radio/NN/O and/and/CC/O diplomacy/diplomacy/NN/O ./././O
Its/its/PRP$/O spread/spread/NN/O beyond/beyond/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/O Isles/Isles/NNP/LOCATION began/begin/VBD/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O growth/growth/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/O Empire/empire/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE late/late/JJ/DATE 19th/19th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE its/its/PRP$/O reach/reach/NN/O was/be/VBD/O truly/truly/RB/O global/global/JJ/O ./././O
Following/follow/VBG/O British/british/JJ/MISC colonisation/colonisation/NN/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O 16th/16th/JJ/ORDINAL to/to/TO/O 19th/19th/JJ/ORDINAL centuries/century/NNS/DURATION ,/,/,/O it/it/PRP/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O dominant/dominant/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Canada/Canada/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Australia/Australia/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION Zealand/Zealand/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
The/the/DT/O growing/grow/VBG/O economic/economic/JJ/O and/and/CC/O cultural/cultural/JJ/O influence/influence/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O US/US/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O its/its/PRP$/O status/status/NN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O global/global/JJ/O superpower/superpower/NN/O since/since/IN/O World/World/NNP/MISC War/War/NNP/MISC II/II/NNP/MISC have/have/VBP/O significantly/significantly/RB/O accelerated/accelerate/VBN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O spread/spread/NN/O across/across/IN/O the/the/DT/O planet/planet/NN/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC replaced/replace/VBD/O German/german/JJ/MISC as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O dominant/dominant/JJ/O language/language/NN/O of/of/IN/O science/science/NN/O Nobel/Nobel/NNP/MISC Prize/Prize/NNP/MISC laureates/laureate/VBZ/O during/during/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/DATE half/half/NN/DATE of/of/IN/DATE the/the/DT/DATE 20th/20th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC equalled/equal/VBD/O and/and/CC/O may/may/MD/O have/have/VB/O surpassed/surpass/VBN/O French/french/JJ/MISC as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O dominant/dominant/JJ/O language/language/NN/O of/of/IN/O diplomacy/diplomacy/NN/O during/during/IN/O the/the/DT/O last/last/JJ/DATE half/half/NN/DATE of/of/IN/DATE the/the/DT/DATE 19th/19th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE ./././O
A/a/DT/O working/work/VBG/O knowledge/knowledge/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC has/have/VBZ/O become/become/VBN/O a/a/DT/O requirement/requirement/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O fields/field/NNS/O ,/,/,/O occupations/occupation/NNS/O and/and/CC/O professions/profession/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O medicine/medicine/NN/O and/and/CC/O computing/computing/NN/O ;/;/:/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O consequence/consequence/NN/O over/over/IN/O a/a/DT/O billion/billion/CD/NUMBER people/people/NNS/O speak/speak/VBP/O English/English/NNP/MISC to/to/TO/O at/at/IN/O least/least/JJS/O a/a/DT/O basic/basic/JJ/O level/level/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O see/see/VB/O English/English/NNP/MISC as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O foreign/foreign/JJ/O or/or/CC/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL language/language/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O one/one/CD/TIME of/of/IN/TIME six/six/CD/TIME official/official/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION Nations/Nations/NNPS/ORGANIZATION ./././O
One/one/CD/NUMBER impact/impact/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O growth/growth/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O reduction/reduction/NN/O of/of/IN/O native/native/JJ/O linguistic/linguistic/JJ/O diversity/diversity/NN/O in/in/IN/O many/many/JJ/O parts/part/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ./././O
Its/its/PRP$/O influence/influence/NN/O continues/continue/VBZ/O to/to/TO/O play/play/VB/O an/a/DT/O important/important/JJ/O role/role/NN/O in/in/IN/O language/language/NN/O attrition/attrition/NN/O ./././O
Conversely/conversely/RB/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O natural/natural/JJ/O internal/internal/JJ/O variety/variety/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC along/along/IN/O with/with/IN/O creoles/creole/NNS/O and/and/CC/O pidgins/pidgin/NNS/O have/have/VBP/O the/the/DT/O potential/potential/JJ/O to/to/TO/O produce/produce/VB/O new/new/JJ/O distinct/distinct/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O from/from/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC over/over/IN/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
History/history/NN/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC originated/originate/VBD/O in/in/IN/O those/those/DT/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O of/of/IN/O North/North/NNP/LOCATION Sea/Sea/NNP/LOCATION Germanic/Germanic/NNP/LOCATION that/that/WDT/O were/be/VBD/O carried/carry/VBN/O to/to/TO/O Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION by/by/IN/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC settlers/settler/NNS/O from/from/IN/O various/various/JJ/O parts/part/NNS/O of/of/IN/O what/what/WP/O are/be/VBP/O now/now/RB/DATE the/the/DT/O Netherlands/Netherlands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O northwest/northwest/RB/LOCATION Germany/Germany/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Denmark/Denmark/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Up/up/IN/O to/to/TO/O that/that/DT/O point/point/NN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O Roman/Roman/NNP/LOCATION Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION the/the/DT/O native/native/JJ/O population/population/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O assumed/assume/VBN/O to/to/TO/O have/have/VB/O spoken/speak/VBN/O the/the/DT/O Celtic/celtic/JJ/O language/language/NN/O Brythonic/brythonic/JJ/MISC alongside/alongside/IN/O the/the/DT/O acrolectal/acrolectal/JJ/O influence/influence/NN/O of/of/IN/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O ,/,/,/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O 400-year/400-year/JJ/DURATION Roman/roman/JJ/MISC occupation/occupation/NN/O ./././O
One/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O these/these/DT/O incoming/incoming/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC tribes/tribe/NNS/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Angles/Angles/NNPS/MISC ,/,/,/O whom/whom/WP/O Bede/Bede/NNP/PERSON believed/believe/VBD/O to/to/TO/O have/have/VB/O relocated/relocate/VBN/O entirely/entirely/RB/O to/to/TO/O Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
The/the/DT/O names/name/NNS/O `/`/``/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION '/'/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O from/from/IN/O Engla/Engla/NNP/LOCATION land/land/NN/O ``/``/``/O Land/Land/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Angles/Angles/NNPS/MISC ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O English/English/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/MISC Old/Old/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC Englisc/Englisc/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O are/be/VBP/O derived/derive/VBN/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O name/name/NN/O of/of/IN/O this/this/DT/O tribe/tribe/NN/O --/--/:/O but/but/CC/O Saxons/Saxons/NNPS/MISC ,/,/,/O Jutes/Jutes/NNPS/PERSON and/and/CC/O a/a/DT/O range/range/NN/O of/of/IN/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC peoples/people/NNS/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O coasts/coast/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Frisia/Frisia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Lower/Lower/NNP/LOCATION Saxony/Saxony/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Jutland/Jutland/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Southern/Southern/NNP/LOCATION Sweden/Sweden/NNP/LOCATION also/also/RB/O moved/move/VBD/O to/to/TO/O Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O this/this/DT/O era/era/NN/O ./././O
Initially/initially/RB/O ,/,/,/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC was/be/VBD/O a/a/DT/O diverse/diverse/JJ/O group/group/NN/O of/of/IN/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ,/,/,/O reflecting/reflect/VBG/O the/the/DT/O varied/varied/JJ/O origins/origin/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Anglo-Saxon/anglo-saxon/JJ/MISC kingdoms/kingdom/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Great/great/JJ/LOCATION Britain/Britain/NNP/LOCATION but/but/CC/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O these/these/DT/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ,/,/,/O Late/late/JJ/LOCATION West/West/NNP/LOCATION Saxon/Saxon/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O eventually/eventually/RB/O came/come/VBD/O to/to/TO/O dominate/dominate/VB/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O it/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O this/this/DT/O that/that/IN/O the/the/DT/O poem/poem/NN/O Beowulf/Beowulf/NNP/PERSON is/be/VBZ/O written/write/VBN/O ./././O
Old/old/JJ/O English/English/NNP/MISC was/be/VBD/O later/later/RB/O transformed/transform/VBN/O by/by/IN/O two/two/CD/NUMBER waves/wave/NNS/O of/of/IN/O invasion/invasion/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL was/be/VBD/O by/by/IN/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O North/North/NNP/MISC Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC language/language/NN/O branch/branch/NN/O when/when/WRB/O Halfdan/Halfdan/NNP/PERSON Ragnarsson/Ragnarsson/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Ivar/Ivar/NNP/PERSON the/the/DT/O Boneless/Boneless/NNP/MISC started/start/VBD/O the/the/DT/O conquering/conquering/NN/O and/and/CC/O colonisation/colonisation/NN/O of/of/IN/O northern/northern/JJ/O parts/part/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/LOCATION Isles/Isles/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 8th/8th/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/ORDINAL 9th/9th/JJ/ORDINAL centuries/century/NNS/DURATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O see/see/VB/O Danelaw/Danelaw/NNP/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
The/the/DT/DATE second/second/NN/DATE was/be/VBD/O by/by/IN/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Romance/romance/NN/MISC language/language/NN/MISC Old/old/JJ/MISC Norman/Norman/NNP/MISC in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 11th/11th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O Norman/Norman/NNP/PERSON conquest/conquest/NN/O of/of/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Norman/Norman/NNP/PERSON developed/develop/VBD/O into/into/IN/O Anglo-Norman/Anglo-Norman/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O then/then/RB/O Anglo-French/anglo-french/JJ/MISC --/--/:/O and/and/CC/O introduced/introduce/VBD/O a/a/DT/O layer/layer/NN/O of/of/IN/O words/word/NNS/O especially/especially/RB/O via/via/IN/O the/the/DT/O courts/court/NNS/O and/and/CC/O government/government/NN/O ./././O
As/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O extending/extend/VBG/O the/the/DT/O lexicon/lexicon/NN/O with/with/IN/O Scandinavian/scandinavian/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O Norman/Norman/NNP/PERSON words/word/NNS/O these/these/DT/O two/two/CD/NUMBER events/event/NNS/O also/also/RB/O simplified/simplify/VBD/O the/the/DT/O grammar/grammar/NN/O and/and/CC/O transformed/transform/VBN/O English/English/NNP/MISC into/into/IN/O a/a/DT/O borrowing/borrowing/NN/O language/language/NN/O --/--/:/O more/more/JJR/O than/than/IN/O normally/normally/RB/O open/open/JJ/O to/to/TO/O accept/accept/VB/O new/new/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O from/from/IN/O other/other/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O linguistic/linguistic/JJ/O shifts/shift/NNS/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC following/follow/VBG/O the/the/DT/O Norman/Norman/NNP/MISC invasion/invasion/NN/O produced/produce/VBD/O what/what/WP/O is/be/VBZ/O now/now/RB/DATE referred/refer/VBN/O to/to/TO/O as/as/IN/O Middle/Middle/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ;/;/:/O Geoffrey/Geoffrey/NNP/PERSON Chaucer/Chaucer/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O The/the/DT/O Canterbury/Canterbury/NNP/O Tales/tale/NNS/O is/be/VBZ/O its/its/PRP$/O best-known/best-known/JJ/O work/work/NN/O ./././O
Throughout/throughout/IN/O all/all/PDT/O this/this/DT/O period/period/NN/O Latin/latin/NN/O in/in/IN/O some/some/DT/O form/form/NN/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O of/of/IN/O European/european/JJ/MISC intellectual/intellectual/JJ/O life/life/NN/O ,/,/,/O first/first/RB/ORDINAL the/the/DT/O Medieval/medieval/JJ/DATE Latin/latin/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Christian/Christian/NNP/ORGANIZATION Church/Church/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O later/later/RB/O the/the/DT/O humanist/humanist/JJ/O Renaissance/Renaissance/NNP/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O those/those/DT/O that/that/WDT/O wrote/write/VBD/O or/or/CC/O copied/copy/VBD/O texts/text/NNS/O in/in/IN/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O commonly/commonly/RB/O coined/coin/VBD/O new/new/JJ/O terms/term/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O to/to/TO/O refer/refer/VB/O to/to/TO/O things/thing/NNS/O or/or/CC/O concepts/concept/NNS/O for/for/IN/O which/which/WDT/O there/there/EX/O was/be/VBD/O no/no/DT/O existing/exist/VBG/O native/native/JJ/O English/english/JJ/MISC word/word/NN/O ./././O
Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O includes/include/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O works/work/NNS/O of/of/IN/O William/William/NNP/PERSON Shakespeare/Shakespeare/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O King/King/NNP/O James/James/NNP/PERSON Bible/Bible/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O is/be/VBZ/O generally/generally/RB/O dated/date/VBN/O from/from/IN/O about/about/IN/DATE 1550/1550/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O when/when/WRB/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION became/become/VBD/O a/a/DT/O colonial/colonial/JJ/O power/power/NN/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC served/serve/VBD/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O colonies/colony/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/O Empire/empire/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O post-colonial/post-colonial/JJ/O period/period/NN/O ,/,/,/O some/some/DT/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O newly/newly/RB/O created/create/VBN/O nations/nation/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O had/have/VBD/O multiple/multiple/JJ/O indigenous/indigenous/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O opted/opt/VBD/O to/to/TO/O continue/continue/VB/O using/use/VBG/O English/English/NNP/MISC as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O to/to/TO/O avoid/avoid/VB/O the/the/DT/O political/political/JJ/O difficulties/difficulty/NNS/O inherent/inherent/JJ/O in/in/IN/O promoting/promote/VBG/O any/any/DT/O one/one/CD/NUMBER indigenous/indigenous/JJ/O language/language/NN/O above/above/IN/O the/the/DT/O others/other/NNS/O ./././O
As/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O result/result/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O growth/growth/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/O Empire/empire/NN/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC was/be/VBD/O adopted/adopt/VBN/O in/in/IN/O North/North/NNP/LOCATION America/America/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O India/India/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Africa/Africa/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Australia/Australia/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O many/many/JJ/O other/other/JJ/O regions/region/NNS/O ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O trend/trend/NN/O extended/extend/VBN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O emergence/emergence/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O superpower/superpower/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE mid-20th/mid-20th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE ./././O
Classification/classification/NN/MISC and/and/CC/O related/related/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC language/language/NN/O belongs/belong/VBZ/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Anglo-Frisian/anglo-frisian/JJ/MISC sub-group/sub-group/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O West/West/NNP/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/O branch/branch/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC family/family/NN/O ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O member/member/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Indo-European/indo-european/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ./././O
Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O direct/direct/JJ/O descendant/descendant/NN/O of/of/IN/O Middle/Middle/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O itself/itself/PRP/O a/a/DT/O direct/direct/JJ/O descendant/descendant/NN/O of/of/IN/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O descendant/descendant/NN/O of/of/IN/O Proto-Germanic/Proto-Germanic/NNP/O ./././O
Typical/typical/JJ/O of/of/IN/O most/most/JJS/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O characterised/characterise/VBN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O use/use/NN/O of/of/IN/O modal/modal/JJ/O verbs/verb/NNS/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O division/division/NN/O of/of/IN/O verbs/verb/NNS/O into/into/IN/O strong/strong/JJ/O and/and/CC/O weak/weak/JJ/O classes/class/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O common/common/JJ/O sound/sound/JJ/O shifts/shift/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Proto-Indo-European/Proto-Indo-European/NNP/O known/know/VBN/O as/as/IN/O Grimm/Grimm/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O Law/law/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O closest/closest/JJS/O living/living/JJ/O relatives/relative/NNS/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC are/be/VBP/O Scots/scot/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O spoken/speak/VBN/O primarily/primarily/RB/O in/in/IN/O Scotland/Scotland/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O parts/part/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Northern/northern/JJ/LOCATION Ireland/Ireland/NNP/LOCATION where/where/WRB/O Ulster/Ulster/NNP/O Scots/Scots/NNP/O is/be/VBZ/O spoken/speak/VBN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O Frisian/frisian/JJ/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O spoken/speak/VBN/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O southern/southern/JJ/O fringes/fringe/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O North/North/NNP/LOCATION Sea/Sea/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O Denmark/Denmark/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Netherlands/Netherlands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Germany/Germany/NNP/LOCATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
After/after/IN/O Scots/scot/NNS/O and/and/CC/O Frisian/frisian/JJ/MISC come/come/VBN/O those/those/DT/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O are/be/VBP/O more/more/RBR/O distantly/distantly/RB/O related/related/JJ/O :/:/:/O the/the/DT/O non-Anglo-Frisian/non-anglo-frisian/JJ/MISC West/West/NNP/MISC Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Dutch/Dutch/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O Afrikaans/Afrikaans/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Low/low/JJ/O German/german/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O High/high/JJ/O German/german/JJ/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O North/North/NNP/LOCATION Germanic/germanic/JJ/LOCATION languages/language/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Swedish/Swedish/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O Danish/danish/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O Norwegian/norwegian/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Faroese/faroese/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
With/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O partial/partial/JJ/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O exception/exception/NN/O of/of/IN/O Scots/Scots/NNP/O ,/,/,/O none/none/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O other/other/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O is/be/VBZ/O mutually/mutually/RB/O intelligible/intelligible/JJ/O with/with/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O owing/owe/VBG/O in/in/IN/O part/part/NN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O divergences/divergence/NNS/O in/in/IN/O lexis/lexis/NN/O ,/,/,/O syntax/syntax/NN/O ,/,/,/O semantics/semantics/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O phonology/phonology/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O isolation/isolation/NN/O afforded/afford/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O English/english/JJ/MISC language/language/NN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/LOCATION Isles/Isles/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O although/although/IN/O some/some/DT/O ,/,/,/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O Dutch/Dutch/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O do/do/VBP/O show/show/VB/O strong/strong/JJ/O affinities/affinity/NNS/O with/with/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O especially/especially/RB/O to/to/TO/O earlier/earlier/JJR/O stages/stage/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
Isolation/isolation/NN/O has/have/VBZ/O allowed/allow/VBN/O English/English/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O Scots/Scots/NNP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O Faroese/faroese/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O to/to/TO/O develop/develop/VB/O independently/independently/RB/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Continental/Continental/NNP/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O and/and/CC/O their/they/PRP$/O influences/influence/NNS/O over/over/IN/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O addition/addition/NN/O to/to/TO/O isolation/isolation/NN/O ,/,/,/O lexical/lexical/JJ/O differences/difference/NNS/O between/between/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O other/other/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O exist/exist/VBP/O due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O diachronic/diachronic/JJ/O change/change/NN/O ,/,/,/O semantic/semantic/JJ/O drift/drift/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O to/to/TO/O substantial/substantial/JJ/O borrowing/borrowing/NN/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC of/of/IN/O words/word/NNS/O from/from/IN/O other/other/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O especially/especially/RB/O Latin/latin/JJ/O and/and/CC/O French/french/JJ/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O though/though/IN/O borrowing/borrowing/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O no/no/DT/O way/way/NN/O unique/unique/JJ/O to/to/TO/O English/English/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O example/example/NN/O ,/,/,/O compare/compare/VB/O ``/``/``/O exit/exit/NN/O ''/''/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Latin/Latin/NNP/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O vs./vs./FW/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC uitgang/uitgang/NN/O and/and/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC Ausgang/ausgang/NN/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O literally/literally/RB/O ``/``/``/O out-going/out-going/JJ/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O though/though/IN/O outgang/outgang/NN/O continues/continue/VBZ/O to/to/TO/O survive/survive/VB/O dialectally/dialectally/RB/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O ``/``/``/O change/change/NN/O ''/''/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O French/French/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O vs./vs./CC/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC andering/andering/NN/O and/and/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC Änderung/änderung/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O literally/literally/RB/O ``/``/``/O elsing/elsing/NN/O ,/,/,/O othering/other/VBG/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O i.e./i.e./FW/O ``/``/``/O alteration/alteration/NN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ;/;/:/O ``/``/``/O movement/movement/NN/O ''/''/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O French/French/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O vs./vs./CC/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC beweging/beweging/NN/O and/and/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC Bewegung/bewegung/NN/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O ``/``/``/O beway-ing/beway-ing/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O i.e./i.e./FW/O ``/``/``/O proceeding/proceed/VBG/O along/along/IN/O the/the/DT/O way/way/NN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ;/;/:/O etc./etc./FW/O ./././O
With/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O exception/exception/NN/O of/of/IN/O exit/exit/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O a/a/DT/O Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC borrowing/borrowing/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O Middle/Middle/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC had/have/VBD/O already/already/RB/O distanced/distance/VBN/O itself/itself/PRP/O from/from/IN/O other/other/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O having/have/VBG/O the/the/DT/O terms/term/NNS/O wharf/wharf/VBP/O ,/,/,/O schift/schift/VBP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O =/=/JJ/O ``/``/``/O shift/shift/NN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O wending/wend/VBG/O for/for/IN/O ``/``/``/O change/change/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O and/and/CC/O already/already/RB/O by/by/IN/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/english/JJ/MISC times/time/NNS/O the/the/DT/O word/word/NN/O bewegan/bewegan/NN/O meant/mean/VBD/O ``/``/``/O to/to/TO/O cover/cover/VB/O ,/,/,/O envelop/envelop/VB/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O rather/rather/RB/O than/than/IN/O ``/``/``/O to/to/TO/O move/move/VB/O ''/''/''/O ./././O
Preference/preference/NN/O of/of/IN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER synonym/synonym/NN/O over/over/IN/O another/another/DT/O also/also/RB/O causes/cause/VBZ/O differentiation/differentiation/NN/O in/in/IN/O lexis/lexis/NN/O ,/,/,/O even/even/RB/O where/where/WRB/O both/both/DT/O words/word/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC care/care/NN/O vs./vs./JJ/O German/german/JJ/MISC Sorge/sorge/NN/PERSON ./././O
Both/both/DT/O words/word/NNS/O descend/descend/VBP/O from/from/IN/O Proto-Germanic/proto-germanic/JJ/O \*/\*/SYM/O karō/karō/FW/O and/and/CC/O \*/\*/SYM/O surgō/surgō/NN/O respectively/respectively/RB/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O \*/\*/SYM/O karō/karō/FW/O has/have/VBZ/O become/become/VBN/O the/the/DT/O dominant/dominant/JJ/O word/word/NN/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC for/for/IN/O ``/``/``/O care/care/NN/O ''/''/''/O while/while/IN/O in/in/IN/O German/German/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O Dutch/Dutch/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Scandinavian/scandinavian/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O \*/\*/NN/O surgō/surgō/NN/O root/root/NN/O prevailed/prevail/VBD/O ./././O
\*/\*/SYM/O Surgō/surgō/NN/O still/still/RB/O survives/survive/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O however/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O sorrow/sorrow/NN/O ./././O
Despite/despite/IN/O extensive/extensive/JJ/O lexical/lexical/JJ/O borrowing/borrowing/NN/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O workings/workings/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC language/language/NN/O are/be/VBP/O resolutely/resolutely/RB/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O English/English/NNP/MISC remains/remain/VBZ/O classified/classify/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC language/language/NN/O due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O its/its/PRP$/O structure/structure/NN/O and/and/CC/O grammar/grammar/NN/O ./././O
Borrowed/borrow/VBN/O words/word/NNS/O get/get/VBP/O incorporated/incorporate/VBN/O into/into/IN/O a/a/DT/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC system/system/NN/O of/of/IN/O conjugation/conjugation/NN/O ,/,/,/O declension/declension/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O syntax/syntax/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O behave/behave/VB/O exactly/exactly/RB/O as/as/IN/O though/though/IN/O they/they/PRP/O were/be/VBD/O native/native/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC words/word/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
For/for/IN/O example/example/NN/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O word/word/NN/O reduce/reduce/VB/O is/be/VBZ/O borrowed/borrow/VBN/O from/from/IN/O Latin/latin/JJ/O redūcere/redūcere/NN/O ;/;/:/O however/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC one/one/CD/NUMBER says/say/VBZ/O ``/``/``/O I/I/PRP/O reduce/reduce/VBP/O -/-/:/O I/I/PRP/O reduced/reduce/VBD/O -/-/:/O I/I/PRP/O will/will/MD/O reduce/reduce/VB/O ''/''/''/O rather/rather/RB/O than/than/IN/O ``/``/``/O redūcō/redūcō/NN/O -/-/:/O redūxī/redūxī/NN/O -/-/:/O redūcam/redūcam/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O likewise/likewise/RB/O ,/,/,/O we/we/PRP/O say/say/VBP/O :/:/:/O ``/``/``/O John/John/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O life/life/NN/O insurance/insurance/NN/O company/company/NN/O ''/''/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O cf./cf./VBP/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Johns/Johns/NNP/O levensverzekeringsmaatschappij/levensverzekeringsmaatschappij/NN/O ''/''/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O =/=/JJ/O leven/leven/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O life/life/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O +/+/CC/O verzekering/verzekering/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O insurance/insurance/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O +/+/CC/O maatschappij/maatschappij/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O company/company/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O rather/rather/RB/O than/than/IN/O ``/``/``/O the/the/DT/O company/company/NN/O of/of/IN/O insurance/insurance/NN/O life/life/NN/O of/of/IN/O John/John/NNP/PERSON ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O cf./cf./VBP/O the/the/DT/O French/French/NNPS/MISC :/:/:/O la/la/DT/O compagnie/compagnie/FW/O d'assurance-vie/d'assurance-vie/FW/O de/de/FW/O John/John/NNP/PERSON -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Furthermore/furthermore/RB/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O all/all/DT/O basic/basic/JJ/O grammatical/grammatical/JJ/O particles/particle/NNS/O added/add/VBD/O to/to/TO/O nouns/noun/NNS/O ,/,/,/O verbs/verb/NNS/O ,/,/,/O adjectives/adjective/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O adverbs/adverb/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC ./././O
For/for/IN/O nouns/noun/NNS/O ,/,/,/O these/these/DT/O include/include/VBP/O the/the/DT/O normal/normal/JJ/O plural/plural/NN/O marker/marker/NN/O -/-/:/O s/s/NNS/O \//\//:/O -/-/:/O es/e/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O apple/apple/NN/O -/-/:/O apples/apple/NNS/O ;/;/:/O cf./cf./VB/O Frisian/frisian/JJ/MISC appel/appel/NN/O -/-/:/O appels/appel/NNS/O ;/;/:/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC appel/appel/NN/O -/-/:/O appels/appel/NNS/O ;/;/:/O Afrikaans/Afrikaans/NNP/O appel/appel/NN/O -/-/:/O appels/appel/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O possessive/possessive/JJ/O markers/marker/NNS/O -/-/:/O 's/'s/POS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Brad/Brad/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O hat/hat/NN/O ;/;/:/O German/german/JJ/MISC Brads/brad/NNS/MISC Hut/Hut/NNP/O ;/;/:/O Danish/danish/JJ/MISC Brads/brad/NNS/MISC hat/hat/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O -/-/:/O s/s/NNS/O '/'/POS/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O verbs/verb/NNS/O ,/,/,/O these/these/DT/O include/include/VBP/O the/the/DT/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL person/person/NN/O present/present/JJ/DATE ending/end/VBG/O -/-/:/O s/s/NNS/O \//\//:/O -/-/:/O es/e/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O he/he/PRP/O stands\/he/stands\/he/VBD/O reaches/reach/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O present/present/JJ/DATE participle/participle/NN/O ending/end/VBG/O -/-/:/O ing/ing/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O cf./cf./VBP/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/LOCATION -/-/:/O ende/ende/NN/O ;/;/:/O German/german/JJ/MISC -/-/:/O end/end/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e/e/LS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O simple/simple/JJ/O past/past/JJ/DATE tense/tense/JJ/O and/and/CC/O past/past/JJ/DATE participle/participle/NN/O ending/end/VBG/O -/-/:/O ed/ed/VBN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Swedish/swedish/JJ/LOCATION -/-/:/O ade/ade/NN/O \//\//:/O -/-/:/O ad/ad/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O formation/formation/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC infinitive/infinitive/JJ/O using/use/VBG/O to/to/TO/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O ``/``/``/O to/to/TO/O drive/drive/VB/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O cf./cf./VB/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/english/JJ/MISC tō/tō/NN/O drīfenne/drīfenne/NN/O ;/;/:/O Dutch/Dutch/NNP/MISC te/te/FW/O drijven/drijven/FW/O ;/;/:/O Low/low/JJ/O German/german/JJ/MISC to/to/TO/O drieven/drieven/VB/O ;/;/:/O German/german/JJ/MISC zu/zu/NN/O treiben/treiben/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Adverbs/adverb/NNS/O generally/generally/RB/O receive/receive/VBP/O an/a/DT/O -/-/:/O ly/ly/RB/O ending/end/VBG/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O cf./cf./VBP/O German/german/JJ/LOCATION -/-/:/O lich/lich/NN/O ;/;/:/O Swedish/Swedish/NNP/MISC -/-/:/O ligt/ligt/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O adjectives/adjective/NNS/O and/and/CC/O adverbs/adverb/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O inflected/inflect/VBN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O comparative/comparative/JJ/O and/and/CC/O superlative/superlative/JJ/O using/use/VBG/O -/-/:/O er/er/NN/O and/and/CC/O -/-/:/O est/est/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O hard\/harder\/hardest/hard\/harder\/hardest/JJS/O ;/;/:/O cf./cf./VB/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC hard\/harder\/hardst/hard\/harder\/hardst/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O or/or/CC/O through/through/IN/O a/a/DT/O combination/combination/NN/O with/with/IN/O more/more/JJR/O and/and/CC/O most/most/RBS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O cf./cf./VBP/O Swedish/swedish/JJ/MISC mer/mer/NN/O and/and/CC/O mest/mest/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
These/these/DT/O particles/particle/NNS/O append/append/VBP/O freely/freely/RB/O to/to/TO/O all/all/DT/O English/english/JJ/MISC words/word/NNS/O regardless/regardless/RB/O of/of/IN/O origin/origin/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O tsunamis/tsunami/NN/O ;/;/:/O communicates/communicate/VBZ/O ;/;/:/O to/to/TO/O buccaneer/buccaneer/NN/O ;/;/:/O during/during/IN/O ;/;/:/O calmer/calmer/JJR/O ;/;/:/O bizarrely/bizarrely/RB/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O all/all/DT/O derive/derive/VBP/O from/from/IN/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
Even/even/RB/O the/the/DT/O lack/lack/NN/O or/or/CC/O absence/absence/NN/O of/of/IN/O affixes/affix/NNS/O ,/,/,/O known/know/VBN/O as/as/IN/O zero/zero/CD/NUMBER or/or/CC/O null/null/JJ/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O -/-/:/O Ø/ø/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O affixes/affix/VBZ/O ,/,/,/O derive/derive/VBP/O from/from/IN/O endings/ending/NNS/O which/which/WDT/O previously/previously/RB/DATE existed/exist/VBD/O in/in/IN/O Old/Old/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O usually/usually/RB/O -/-/:/O e/e/LS/O ,/,/,/O -/-/:/O a/a/DT/O ,/,/,/O -/-/:/O u/u/NN/O ,/,/,/O -/-/:/O o/o/NN/O ,/,/,/O -/-/:/O an/a/DT/O ,/,/,/O etc./etc./FW/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O that/that/WDT/O later/later/RB/O weakened/weaken/VBD/O to/to/TO/O -/-/:/O e/e/LS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O have/have/VBP/O since/since/IN/O ceased/cease/VBN/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O pronounced/pronounced/JJ/O and/and/CC/O spelt/spelt/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O Modern/Modern/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ``/``/``/O I/I/PRP/O sing/sing/VBP/O ''/''/''/O =/=/JJ/O I/i/CD/NUMBER sing-Ø/sing-ø/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O I/I/PRP/O singe/singe/VBP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Old/old/JJ/O English/english/JJ/MISC ic/ic/JJ/O singe/singe/NN/O ;/;/:/O ``/``/``/O we/we/PRP/O thought/think/VBD/O ''/''/''/O =/=/JJ/O we/we/PRP/O thought-Ø/thought-ø/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O we/we/PRP/O thoughte/thoughte/VBP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O n/n/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Old/old/JJ/O English/english/JJ/MISC wē/wē/NN/O þōhton/þōhton/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Viking/viking/JJ/O colonisation/colonisation/NN/O and/and/CC/O influence/influence/NN/O of/of/IN/O Old/Old/NNP/MISC Norse/Norse/NNP/MISC upon/upon/IN/O Middle/Middle/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC syntax/syntax/NN/O follows/follow/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O pattern/pattern/NN/O similar/similar/JJ/O to/to/TO/O that/that/DT/O of/of/IN/O North/north/JJ/MISC Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Danish/danish/JJ/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Swedish/swedish/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O etc./etc./FW/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O contrast/contrast/NN/O to/to/TO/O other/other/JJ/O West/West/NNP/MISC Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC ./././O
This/this/DT/O is/be/VBZ/O especially/especially/RB/O evident/evident/JJ/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O order/order/NN/O and/and/CC/O placement/placement/NN/O of/of/IN/O verbs/verb/NNS/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O example/example/NN/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC ``/``/``/O I/I/PRP/O will/will/MD/O never/never/RB/O see/see/VB/O you/you/PRP/O again/again/RB/O ''/''/''/O =/=/JJ/O Danish/danish/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Jeg/Jeg/NNP/PERSON vil/vil/NNP/O aldrig/aldrig/FW/O se/se/FW/O dig/dig/NN/O igen/igen/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC ''/''/''/O Ég/ég/NN/O mun/mun/NN/O aldrei/aldreus/NN/O sjá/sjá/NN/O þig/þig/NN/O aftur/aftur/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O whereas/whereas/IN/O in/in/IN/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC the/the/DT/O main/main/JJ/O verb/verb/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O placed/place/VBN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O end/end/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Ik/ik/NN/O zal/zal/NN/O je/je/NN/O nooit/nooit/NN/O weer/weer/NN/O zien/zien/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O German/german/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Ich/ich/NN/O werde/werde/NN/O dich/dich/NN/O nie/nie/NN/O wieder/wieder/NN/O sehen/sehen/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O literally/literally/RB/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O I/I/PRP/O will/will/MD/O you/you/PRP/O never/never/RB/O again/again/RB/O see/see/VB/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O is/be/VBZ/O also/also/RB/O observable/observable/JJ/O in/in/IN/O perfect/perfect/JJ/O tense/tense/JJ/O constructions/construction/NNS/O ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ``/``/``/O I/I/PRP/O have/have/VBP/O never/never/RB/O seen/see/VBN/O anything/anything/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O square/square/NN/O ''/''/''/O =/=/JJ/O Danish/danish/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Jeg/Jeg/NNP/PERSON har/har/NN/O aldrig/aldrig/NN/O set/set/VBD/O noget/noget/JJ/O på/på/NN/O torvet/torvet/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC ''/''/''/O Ég/ég/NN/O hef/hef/NN/O aldrei/aldreus/NN/O séð/séð/NN/O neitt/neitt/NN/O á/á/NN/O torginu/torginu/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC place/place/NN/O the/the/DT/DATE past/past/JJ/DATE participle/participle/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O end/end/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Ik/ik/NN/O heb/heb/NN/O nooit/nooit/NN/O iets/iet/NNS/O op/op/VBP/O het/het/NN/O plein/plein/NN/O gezien/gezien/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O German/german/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Ich/ich/NN/O habe/habe/NN/O nie/nie/NN/O etwas/etwas/FW/O auf/auf/FW/O dem/dem/DT/O Platz/platz/NN/O gesehen/gesehen/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O literally/literally/RB/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O I/I/PRP/O have/have/VBP/O never/never/RB/O anything/anything/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O square/square/JJ/O seen/see/VBN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
As/as/IN/O in/in/IN/O most/most/JJS/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC adjectives/adjective/VBZ/O usually/usually/RB/O come/come/VBN/O before/before/IN/O the/the/DT/O noun/noun/NN/O they/they/PRP/O modify/modify/VBP/O ,/,/,/O even/even/RB/O when/when/WRB/O the/the/DT/O adjective/adjective/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O of/of/IN/O Latinate/latinate/JJ/MISC origin/origin/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O medical/medical/JJ/O emergency/emergency/NN/O ,/,/,/O national/national/JJ/O treasure/treasure/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Also/also/RB/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC continues/continue/VBZ/O to/to/TO/O make/make/VB/O extensive/extensive/JJ/O use/use/NN/O of/of/IN/O self-explaining/self-explaining/JJ/O compounds/compound/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O streetcar/streetcar/FW/O ,/,/,/O classroom/classroom/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O nouns/noun/NNS/O which/which/WDT/O serve/serve/VBP/O as/as/IN/O modifiers/modifier/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O lamp/lamp/NN/O post/post/NN/O ,/,/,/O life/life/NN/O insurance/insurance/NN/O company/company/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O traits/trait/NNS/O inherited/inherit/VBN/O from/from/IN/O Old/old/JJ/MISC English/english/JJ/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O See/see/VB/O also/also/RB/O Kenning/ken/VBG/PERSON -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O kinship/kinship/NN/O with/with/IN/O other/other/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O can/can/MD/O also/also/RB/O be/be/VB/O seen/see/VBN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O tensing/tensing/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC verbs/verb/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O English/english/JJ/MISC fall\/fell\/fallen/fall\/fell\/fallen/NN/O \//\//:/O will/will/MD/O or/or/CC/O shall/shall/MD/O fall/fall/VB/O ,/,/,/O West/West/NNP/LOCATION Frisian/frisian/JJ/LOCATION fal\/foel\/fallen/fal\/foel\/fallen/NN/O \//\//:/O sil/sil/NN/O falle/falle/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC vallen\/viel\/gevallen/vallen\/viel\/gevallen/NN/O \//\//:/O zullen/zullen/NN/O vallen/vallen/NN/O ,/,/,/O German/german/JJ/MISC fallen\/fiel\/gefallen/fallen\/fiel\/gefallen/NN/O \//\//:/O werden/werden/JJ/O fallen/fall/VBN/O ,/,/,/O Norwegian/norwegian/JJ/MISC faller\/falt\/falt/faller\/falt\/falt/NN/O or/or/CC/O falne\/vil/falne\/vil/NN/O or/or/CC/O skal/skal/JJ/O falle/falle/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O comparatives/comparative/NNS/O of/of/IN/O adjectives/adjective/NNS/O and/and/CC/O adverbs/adverb/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O English/english/JJ/MISC good\/better\/best/good\/better\/best/NN/O ,/,/,/O West/West/NNP/MISC Frisian/frisian/JJ/MISC goed\/better\/best/goed\/better\/best/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC goed\/beter\/best/goed\/beter\/best/NN/O ,/,/,/O German/german/JJ/MISC gut\/besser\/best/gut\/besser\/best/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O treatment/treatment/NN/O of/of/IN/O nouns/noun/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O English/english/JJ/MISC shoemaker/shoemaker/NN/O ,/,/,/O shoemaker/shoemaker/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O ,/,/,/O shoemakers/shoemaker/NNS/O ,/,/,/O shoemakers/shoemaker/NNS/O '/'/POS/O ;/;/:/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC schoenmaker/schoenmaker/NN/O ,/,/,/O schoenmakers/schoenmaker/NNS/O ,/,/,/O schoenmakers/schoenmaker/NNS/O ,/,/,/O schoenmakeren/schoenmakeren/NN/O ;/;/:/O Swedish/Swedish/NNP/MISC skomakare/skomakare/NNP/O ,/,/,/O skomakares/skomakare/NNS/O ,/,/,/O skomakare/skomakare/NN/O ,/,/,/O skomakares/skomakare/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O large/large/JJ/O amount/amount/NN/O of/of/IN/O cognates/cognate/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O English/english/JJ/MISC wet/wet/JJ/O ,/,/,/O Scots/scots/JJ/ORGANIZATION weet/weet/NN/O ,/,/,/O West/West/NNP/LOCATION Frisian/Frisian/NNP/LOCATION wiet/wiet/NNP/O ,/,/,/O Swedish/Swedish/NNP/MISC våt/våt/NN/O ;/;/:/O English/English/NNP/MISC send/send/VB/O ,/,/,/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC zenden/zenden/NN/O ,/,/,/O German/german/JJ/MISC senden/senden/NN/O ;/;/:/O English/English/NNP/MISC meaning/mean/VBG/O ,/,/,/O Swedish/swedish/JJ/MISC mening/mening/NN/O ,/,/,/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC meining/meining/NN/O ,/,/,/O etc./etc./NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O also/also/RB/O gives/give/VBZ/O rise/rise/NN/O to/to/TO/O false/false/JJ/O friends/friend/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O English/english/JJ/MISC time/time/NN/O vs/vs/CC/O Norwegian/norwegian/JJ/MISC time/time/NN/O ,/,/,/O meaning/mean/VBG/O ``/``/``/O hour/hour/NN/DURATION ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O English/English/NNP/MISC gift/gift/NN/O vs/vs/CC/O German/german/JJ/MISC Gift/gift/NN/O ,/,/,/O meaning/mean/VBG/O ``/``/``/O poison/poison/NN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O while/while/IN/O differences/difference/NNS/O in/in/IN/O phonology/phonology/NN/O can/can/MD/O obscure/obscure/VB/O words/word/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O really/really/RB/O are/be/VBP/O related/related/JJ/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O tooth/tooth/NN/O vs./vs./JJ/O German/german/JJ/MISC Zahn/zahn/NN/O ;/;/:/O compare/compare/VB/O also/also/RB/O Danish/danish/JJ/MISC tand/tand/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Sometimes/sometimes/RB/O both/both/DT/O semantics/semantics/NNS/O and/and/CC/O phonology/phonology/NN/O are/be/VBP/O different/different/JJ/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O German/german/JJ/MISC Zeit/zeit/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O ``/``/``/O time/time/NN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O is/be/VBZ/O related/relate/VBN/O to/to/TO/O English/English/NNP/MISC ``/``/``/O tide/tide/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC word/word/NN/O ,/,/,/O through/through/IN/O a/a/DT/O transitional/transitional/JJ/O phase/phase/NN/O of/of/IN/O meaning/mean/VBG/O ``/``/``/O period/period/NN/O ''/''/''/O \//\//:/O ``/``/``/O interval/interval/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O has/have/VBZ/O come/come/VBN/O primarily/primarily/RB/O to/to/TO/O mean/mean/VB/O gravitational/gravitational/JJ/O effects/effect/NNS/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O ocean/ocean/NN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O moon/moon/NN/LOCATION ,/,/,/O though/though/IN/O the/the/DT/O original/original/JJ/O meaning/meaning/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O preserved/preserve/VBN/O in/in/IN/O forms/form/NNS/O like/like/IN/O tidings/tiding/NNS/O and/and/CC/O betide/betide/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O phrases/phrase/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O to/to/TO/O tide/tide/NN/O over/over/IN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
-LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O citation/citation/NN/O needed/need/VBN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Many/many/JJ/O North/north/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O entered/enter/VBD/O English/English/NNP/MISC due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O settlement/settlement/NN/O of/of/IN/O Viking/viking/JJ/O raiders/raider/NNS/O and/and/CC/O Danish/danish/JJ/MISC invasions/invasion/NNS/O which/which/WDT/O began/begin/VBD/O around/around/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 9th/9th/JJ/DATE century/century/NN/DATE -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O see/see/VB/O Danelaw/Danelaw/NNP/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Many/many/JJ/O of/of/IN/O these/these/DT/O words/word/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O common/common/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O ,/,/,/O often/often/RB/O mistaken/mistaken/JJ/O for/for/IN/O being/be/VBG/O native/native/JJ/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O shows/show/VBZ/O how/how/WRB/O close-knit/close-knit/JJ/O the/the/DT/O relations/relation/NNS/O between/between/IN/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O Scandinavian/scandinavian/JJ/MISC settlers/settler/NNS/O were/be/VBD/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O See/see/VB/O below/below/IN/O :/:/:/O Old/Old/NNP/MISC Norse/Norse/NNP/MISC origins/origin/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O Low/low/JJ/PERSON German/german/JJ/PERSON also/also/RB/O had/have/VBD/O a/a/DT/O considerable/considerable/JJ/O influence/influence/NN/O on/on/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O ,/,/,/O contributing/contribute/VBG/O common/common/JJ/O everyday/everyday/JJ/O terms/term/NNS/O and/and/CC/O many/many/JJ/O nautical/nautical/JJ/O and/and/CC/O trading/trading/NN/O terms/term/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O See/see/VB/O below/below/IN/O :/:/:/O Dutch/Dutch/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O Low/low/JJ/O German/german/JJ/MISC origins/origin/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Finally/finally/RB/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC has/have/VBZ/O been/be/VBN/O forming/form/VBG/O compound/compound/NN/O words/word/NNS/O and/and/CC/O affixing/affix/VBG/O existing/exist/VBG/O words/word/NNS/O separately/separately/RB/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O other/other/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O for/for/IN/O over/over/IN/O 1500/1500/CD/DURATION years/year/NNS/NUMBER and/and/CC/O has/have/VBZ/O different/different/JJ/O habits/habit/NNS/O in/in/IN/O that/that/DT/O regard/regard/NN/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O instance/instance/NN/O ,/,/,/O abstract/abstract/JJ/O nouns/noun/NNS/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC may/may/MD/O be/be/VB/O formed/form/VBN/O from/from/IN/O native/native/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O suffixes/suffix/NNS/O ''/''/''/O hood/hood/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O ship/ship/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O dom/dom/NN/O ''/''/''/O and/and/CC/O ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O ness/ness/NN/O ''/''/''/O ./././O
All/all/DT/O of/of/IN/O these/these/DT/O have/have/VBP/O cognate/cognate/JJ/O suffixes/suffix/NNS/O in/in/IN/O most/most/JJS/O or/or/CC/O all/all/DT/O other/other/JJ/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O their/they/PRP$/O usage/usage/NN/O patterns/pattern/NNS/O have/have/VBP/O diverged/diverge/VBN/O ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O German/german/JJ/MISC ``/``/``/O Freiheit/freiheit/NN/O ''/''/''/O vs./vs./CC/O English/English/NNP/MISC ``/``/``/O freedom/freedom/NN/O ''/''/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O the/the/DT/O suffix/suffix/NN/O ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O heit/heit/NN/O ''/''/''/O being/be/VBG/O cognate/cognate/JJ/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O hood/hood/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O while/while/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O dom/dom/NN/O ''/''/''/O is/be/VBZ/O cognate/cognate/JJ/O with/with/IN/O German/german/JJ/MISC ''/''/''/O -/-/:/O tum/tum/NN/O ''/''/''/O ;/;/:/O compare/compare/VB/O also/also/RB/O North/north/JJ/MISC Frisian/frisian/JJ/MISC fridoem/fridoem/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dutch/dutch/JJ/MISC vrijdom/vrijdom/NN/O ,/,/,/O Norwegian/norwegian/JJ/MISC fridom/fridom/NN/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O freedom/freedom/NN/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O Icelandic/icelandic/JJ/MISC and/and/CC/O Faroese/Faroese/NNP/MISC also/also/RB/O follow/follow/VBP/O English/English/NNP/MISC in/in/IN/O this/this/DT/O respect/respect/NN/O ,/,/,/O since/since/IN/O ,/,/,/O like/like/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O they/they/PRP/O developed/develop/VBD/O independent/independent/JJ/O of/of/IN/O German/german/JJ/MISC influences/influence/NNS/O ./././O
Many/many/JJ/O French/french/JJ/MISC words/word/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O also/also/RB/O intelligible/intelligible/JJ/O to/to/TO/O an/a/DT/O English/english/JJ/MISC speaker/speaker/NN/O ,/,/,/O especially/especially/RB/O when/when/WRB/O they/they/PRP/O are/be/VBP/O seen/see/VBN/O in/in/IN/O writing/write/VBG/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O as/as/IN/O pronunciations/pronunciation/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O often/often/RB/O quite/quite/RB/O different/different/JJ/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O because/because/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC absorbed/absorb/VBD/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O from/from/IN/O Norman/Norman/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O French/French/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O via/via/IN/O Anglo-Norman/Anglo-Norman/NNP/PERSON after/after/IN/O the/the/DT/O Norman/Norman/NNP/MISC Conquest/Conquest/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O directly/directly/RB/O from/from/IN/O French/french/JJ/MISC in/in/IN/O subsequent/subsequent/JJ/O centuries/century/NNS/DURATION ./././O
As/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O result/result/NN/O ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O portion/portion/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O derived/derive/VBN/O from/from/IN/O French/french/JJ/LOCATION ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O some/some/DT/O minor/minor/JJ/O spelling/spelling/NN/O differences/difference/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O e.g./e.g./FW/O inflectional/inflectional/JJ/O endings/ending/NNS/O ,/,/,/O use/use/NN/O of/of/IN/O old/old/JJ/O French/french/JJ/LOCATION spellings/spelling/NNS/O ,/,/,/O lack/lack/NN/O of/of/IN/O diacritics/diacritic/NNS/O ,/,/,/O etc./etc./FW/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O occasional/occasional/JJ/O divergences/divergence/NNS/O in/in/IN/O meaning/meaning/NN/O of/of/IN/O so-called/so-called/JJ/O false/false/JJ/O friends/friend/NNS/O :/:/:/O for/for/IN/O example/example/NN/O ,/,/,/O compare/compare/VB/O ``/``/``/O library/library/NN/O ''/''/''/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O French/french/JJ/LOCATION librairie/librairie/NN/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O means/mean/VBZ/O bookstore/bookstore/NN/O ;/;/:/O in/in/IN/O French/French/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O word/word/NN/O for/for/IN/O ``/``/``/O library/library/NN/O ''/''/''/O is/be/VBZ/O bibliothèque/bibliothèque/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O pronunciation/pronunciation/NN/O of/of/IN/O most/most/JJS/O French/french/JJ/MISC loanwords/loanword/NNS/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O exception/exception/NN/O of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O handful/handful/NN/O of/of/IN/O more/more/RBR/O recently/recently/RB/DATE borrowed/borrow/VBN/O words/word/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O mirage/mirage/NN/O ,/,/,/O genre/genre/NN/O ,/,/,/O café/café/NN/O ;/;/:/O or/or/CC/O phrases/phrase/NNS/O like/like/IN/O coup/coup/NN/O d'état/d'état/NN/O ,/,/,/O rendez-vous/rendez-vous/JJ/O ,/,/,/O etc./etc./FW/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O has/have/VBZ/O become/become/VBN/O largely/largely/RB/O anglicised/anglicised/JJ/O and/and/CC/O follows/follow/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O typically/typically/RB/O English/english/JJ/MISC phonology/phonology/NN/O and/and/CC/O pattern/pattern/NN/O of/of/IN/O stress/stress/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O compare/compare/VB/O English/English/NNP/MISC ``/``/``/O nature/nature/NN/O ''/''/''/O vs./vs./CC/O French/french/JJ/MISC nature/nature/NN/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O button/button/NN/O ''/''/''/O vs./vs./FW/O bouton/bouton/FW/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O table/table/NN/O ''/''/''/O vs./vs./CC/O table/table/NN/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O hour/hour/NN/DURATION ''/''/''/O vs./vs./FW/O heure/heure/FW/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O reside/reside/VBP/O ''/''/''/O vs./vs./FW/O résider/résider/FW/O ,/,/,/O etc./etc./FW/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Geographical/geographical/JJ/O distribution/distribution/NN/O ./././O
Approximately/approximately/RB/O 375/375/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER people/people/NNS/O speak/speak/VBP/O English/English/NNP/MISC as/as/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL language/language/NN/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC today/today/NN/DATE is/be/VBZ/O probably/probably/RB/O the/the/DT/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL largest/largest/JJS/O language/language/NN/O by/by/IN/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O native/native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O Mandarin/Mandarin/NNP/O Chinese/Chinese/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O Spanish/Spanish/NNP/MISC ./././O
However/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O when/when/WRB/O combining/combine/VBG/O native/native/JJ/O and/and/CC/O non-native/non-native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O it/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O probably/probably/RB/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O commonly/commonly/RB/O spoken/speak/VBN/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O though/though/IN/O possibly/possibly/RB/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O combination/combination/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Chinese/chinese/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O depending/depend/VBG/O on/on/IN/O whether/whether/IN/O or/or/CC/O not/not/RB/O distinctions/distinction/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O latter/latter/JJ/O are/be/VBP/O classified/classify/VBN/O as/as/IN/O ``/``/``/O languages/language/NNS/O ''/''/''/O or/or/CC/O ``/``/``/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Estimates/estimate/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O include/include/VBP/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL language/language/NN/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O vary/vary/VBP/O greatly/greatly/RB/O from/from/IN/O 470/470/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER to/to/TO/O over/over/IN/O a/a/DT/O billion/billion/CD/NUMBER depending/depend/VBG/O on/on/IN/O how/how/WRB/O literacy/literacy/NN/O or/or/CC/O mastery/mastery/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O defined/define/VBN/O and/and/CC/O measured/measure/VBN/O ./././O
Linguistics/linguistics/NNS/O professor/professor/NN/O David/David/NNP/PERSON Crystal/Crystal/NNP/PERSON calculates/calculate/VBZ/O that/that/IN/O non-native/non-native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O now/now/RB/DATE outnumber/outnumber/VBP/O native/native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O ratio/ratio/NN/O of/of/IN/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER to/to/TO/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER ./././O
The/the/DT/O countries/country/NNS/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O highest/highest/JJS/O populations/population/NNS/O of/of/IN/O native/native/JJ/O English/english/JJ/MISC speakers/speaker/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O descending/descend/VBG/O order/order/NN/O :/:/:/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 215/215/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 61/61/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O Canada/Canada/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 18.2/18.2/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O Australia/Australia/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 15.5/15.5/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O Nigeria/Nigeria/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O Ireland/Ireland/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 3.8/3.8/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION Africa/Africa/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 3.7/3.7/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION Zealand/Zealand/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 3.6/3.6/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE Census/Census/NNP/O ./././O
Countries/country/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O Philippines/Philippines/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Nigeria/Nigeria/NNP/LOCATION also/also/RB/O have/have/VBP/O millions/million/NNS/O of/of/IN/O native/native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O of/of/IN/O dialect/dialect/NN/O continua/continuum/NN/O ranging/range/VBG/O from/from/IN/O an/a/DT/O English-based/english-based/JJ/MISC creole/creole/NN/O to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O more/more/RBR/O standard/standard/JJ/O version/version/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
Of/of/IN/O those/those/DT/O nations/nation/NNS/O where/where/WRB/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O spoken/speak/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/DURATION second/second/JJ/DURATION language/language/NN/O ,/,/,/O India/India/NNP/LOCATION has/have/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O such/such/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O `/`/``/O Indian/indian/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC '/'/POS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Crystal/Crystal/NNP/O claims/claim/VBZ/O that/that/IN/O ,/,/,/O combining/combine/VBG/O native/native/JJ/O and/and/CC/O non-native/non-native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O ,/,/,/O India/India/NNP/LOCATION now/now/RB/DATE has/have/VBZ/O more/more/JJR/O people/people/NNS/O who/who/WP/O speak/speak/VBP/O or/or/CC/O understand/understand/VBP/O English/english/JJ/MISC than/than/IN/O any/any/DT/O other/other/JJ/O country/country/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ./././O
Countries/country/NNS/O in/in/IN/O order/order/NN/O of/of/IN/O total/total/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O ./././O
Countries/country/NNS/O where/where/WRB/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O major/major/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O primary/primary/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O Anguilla/Anguilla/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Antigua/Antigua/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Barbuda/Barbuda/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Australia/Australia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Bahamas/Bahamas/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Barbados/Barbados/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Belize/Belize/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Bermuda/Bermuda/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/O Indian/Indian/NNP/LOCATION Ocean/Ocean/NNP/LOCATION Territory/Territory/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O British/british/JJ/LOCATION Virgin/Virgin/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Canada/Canada/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Cayman/Cayman/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Dominica/Dominica/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Falkland/Falkland/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Gibraltar/Gibraltar/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Grenada/Grenada/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Guam/Guam/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Guernsey/Guernsey/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Guyana/Guyana/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Ireland/Ireland/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Isle/Isle/NNP/MISC of/of/IN/MISC Man/Man/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Jersey/Jersey/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Montserrat/Montserrat/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Nauru/Nauru/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION Zealand/Zealand/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Pitcairn/Pitcairn/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Saint/Saint/NNP/PERSON Helena/Helena/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Ascension/Ascension/NNP/O and/and/CC/O Tristan/Tristan/NNP/O da/da/NNP/O Cunha/Cunha/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Saint/Saint/NNP/O Kitts/Kitts/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Nevis/Nevis/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Saint/Saint/NNP/PERSON Vincent/Vincent/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O Grenadines/Grenadines/NNPS/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O Singapore/Singapore/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION Georgia/Georgia/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION Sandwich/Sandwich/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Trinidad/Trinidad/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/LOCATION Tobago/Tobago/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Turks/Turks/NNPS/MISC and/and/CC/O Caicos/Caicos/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION ./././O
In/in/IN/O some/some/DT/O countries/country/NNS/O where/where/WRB/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O not/not/RB/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O spoken/speak/VBN/O language/language/NN/O ,/,/,/O it/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O an/a/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ;/;/:/O these/these/DT/O countries/country/NNS/O include/include/VBP/O Botswana/Botswana/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Cameroon/Cameroon/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Federated/Federated/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION of/of/IN/O Micronesia/Micronesia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Fiji/Fiji/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Gambia/Gambia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Ghana/Ghana/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O India/India/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Kenya/Kenya/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Kiribati/Kiribati/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Lesotho/Lesotho/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Liberia/Liberia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Madagascar/Madagascar/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Malta/Malta/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Marshall/Marshall/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Mauritius/Mauritius/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Namibia/Namibia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Nigeria/Nigeria/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Pakistan/Pakistan/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Palau/Palau/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Papua/Papua/NNP/LOCATION New/New/NNP/LOCATION Guinea/Guinea/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Philippines/Philippines/NNPS/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Philippine/philippine/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O Rwanda/Rwanda/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Saint/Saint/NNP/PERSON Lucia/Lucia/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Samoa/Samoa/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Seychelles/Seychelles/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Sierra/Sierra/NNP/LOCATION Leone/Leone/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Solomon/Solomon/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Sri/Sri/NNP/LOCATION Lanka/Lanka/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Sudan/Sudan/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION Sudan/Sudan/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Swaziland/Swaziland/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Tanzania/Tanzania/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Uganda/Uganda/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Zambia/Zambia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Zimbabwe/Zimbabwe/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Also/also/RB/O there/there/EX/O are/be/VBP/O countries/country/NNS/O where/where/WRB/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O part/part/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O territory/territory/NN/O English/English/NNP/MISC became/become/VBD/O a/a/DT/O co-official/co-official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ,/,/,/O e.g./e.g./FW/O Colombia/Colombia/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O San/San/NNP/LOCATION Andrés/Andrés/NNP/LOCATION y/y/NNP/O Providencia/Providencia/NNP/O and/and/CC/O Nicaragua/Nicaragua/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O Mosquito/Mosquito/NNP/O Coast/Coast/NNP/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O was/be/VBD/O a/a/DT/O result/result/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O influence/influence/NN/O of/of/IN/O British/british/JJ/MISC colonisation/colonisation/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O area/area/NN/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O also/also/RB/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 11/11/CD/NUMBER official/official/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O are/be/VBP/O given/give/VBN/O equal/equal/JJ/O status/status/NN/O in/in/IN/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION Africa/Africa/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O South/South/NNP/MISC African/African/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O also/also/RB/O the/the/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O current/current/JJ/DATE dependent/dependent/JJ/O territories/territory/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Australia/Australia/NNP/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Norfolk/Norfolk/NNP/LOCATION Island/Island/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Christmas/Christmas/NNP/LOCATION Island/Island/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Cocos/Cocos/NNP/LOCATION Island/Island/NNP/LOCATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O American/american/JJ/LOCATION Samoa/Samoa/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Guam/Guam/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Northern/Northern/NNP/LOCATION Mariana/Mariana/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Puerto/Puerto/NNP/LOCATION Rico/Rico/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O US/US/NNP/LOCATION Virgin/Virgin/NNP/LOCATION Islands/Islands/NNP/LOCATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O former/former/JJ/O British/british/JJ/MISC colony/colony/NN/O of/of/IN/O Hong/Hong/NNP/LOCATION Kong/Kong/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
-LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O See/see/VB/O List/list/NN/O of/of/IN/O countries/country/NNS/O where/where/WRB/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O an/a/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O for/for/IN/O more/more/JJR/O details/detail/NNS/O ./././O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O
./././O
Although/although/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION federal/federal/JJ/O government/government/NN/O has/have/VBZ/O no/no/DT/O official/official/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC has/have/VBZ/O been/be/VBN/O given/give/VBN/O official/official/JJ/O status/status/NN/O by/by/IN/O 30/30/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 50/50/CD/NUMBER state/state/NN/O governments/government/NNS/O ./././O
Although/although/IN/O falling/fall/VBG/O short/short/JJ/O of/of/IN/O official/official/JJ/O status/status/NN/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O also/also/RB/O an/a/DT/O important/important/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O several/several/JJ/O former/former/JJ/O colonies/colony/NNS/O and/and/CC/O protectorates/protectorate/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O Bahrain/Bahrain/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Bangladesh/Bangladesh/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Brunei/Brunei/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Cyprus/Cyprus/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Malaysia/Malaysia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Arab/Arab/NNP/LOCATION Emirates/Emirates/NNPS/LOCATION ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O global/global/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
Because/because/IN/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O so/so/RB/O widely/widely/RB/O spoken/speak/VBN/O ,/,/,/O it/it/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O often/often/RB/O been/be/VBN/O referred/refer/VBN/O to/to/TO/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O ``/``/``/O world/world/NN/O language/language/NN/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O lingua/lingua/NN/O franca/franca/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O modern/modern/JJ/O era/era/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O while/while/IN/O it/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O not/not/RB/O an/a/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O most/most/JJS/O countries/country/NNS/O ,/,/,/O it/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O currently/currently/RB/DATE the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O most/most/RBS/O often/often/RB/O taught/teach/VBD/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O foreign/foreign/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O ,/,/,/O by/by/IN/O international/international/JJ/O treaty/treaty/NN/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O for/for/IN/O aeronautical/aeronautical/JJ/O and/and/CC/O maritime/maritime/JJ/O communications/communication/NNS/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O an/a/DT/O official/official/JJ/O language/language/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION Nations/Nations/NNPS/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O many/many/JJ/O other/other/JJ/O international/international/JJ/O organizations/organization/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O the/the/DT/O International/International/NNP/ORGANIZATION Olympic/Olympic/NNP/ORGANIZATION Committee/Committee/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O most/most/RBS/O often/often/RB/O studied/study/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O foreign/foreign/JJ/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O European/European/NNP/ORGANIZATION Union/Union/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O by/by/IN/O 89/89/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT of/of/IN/O schoolchildren/schoolchildren/NNS/O ,/,/,/O ahead/ahead/RB/O of/of/IN/O French/french/JJ/MISC at/at/IN/O 32/32/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT ,/,/,/O while/while/IN/O the/the/DT/O perception/perception/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O usefulness/usefulness/NN/O of/of/IN/O foreign/foreign/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O among/among/IN/O Europeans/Europeans/NNPS/MISC is/be/VBZ/O 68/68/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT in/in/IN/O favor/favor/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ahead/ahead/RB/O of/of/IN/O 25/25/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT for/for/IN/O French/french/JJ/MISC ./././O
Among/among/IN/O some/some/DT/O non-English-speaking/non-english-speaking/JJ/O EU/EU/NNP/LOCATION countries/country/NNS/O ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O percentage/percentage/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O adult/adult/JJ/O population/population/NN/O claims/claim/VBZ/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O able/able/JJ/O to/to/TO/O converse/converse/VB/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC --/--/:/O in/in/IN/O particular/particular/JJ/O :/:/:/O 85/85/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT in/in/IN/O Sweden/Sweden/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O 83/83/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT in/in/IN/O Denmark/Denmark/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O 79/79/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Netherlands/Netherlands/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O 66/66/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT in/in/IN/O Luxembourg/Luxembourg/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O over/over/IN/O 50/50/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT in/in/IN/O Finland/Finland/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Slovenia/Slovenia/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Austria/Austria/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Belgium/Belgium/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Germany/Germany/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Books/book/NNS/O ,/,/,/O magazines/magazine/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O newspapers/newspaper/NNS/O written/write/VBN/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC are/be/VBP/O available/available/JJ/O in/in/IN/O many/many/JJ/O countries/country/NNS/O around/around/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O commonly/commonly/RB/O used/use/VBN/O language/language/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O sciences/science/NNS/O with/with/IN/O Science/Science/NNP/O Citation/Citation/NNP/O Index/Index/NNP/O reporting/report/VBG/O as/as/RB/O early/early/RB/O as/as/IN/O 1997/1997/CD/DATE that/that/WDT/O 95/95/CD/PERCENT %/%/NN/PERCENT of/of/IN/O its/its/PRP$/O articles/article/NNS/O were/be/VBD/O written/write/VBN/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O even/even/RB/O though/though/IN/O only/only/RB/O half/half/NN/O of/of/IN/O them/they/PRP/O came/come/VBD/O from/from/IN/O authors/author/NNS/O in/in/IN/O English-speaking/english-speaking/JJ/MISC countries/country/NNS/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O increasing/increase/VBG/O use/use/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC language/language/NN/O globally/globally/RB/O has/have/VBZ/O had/have/VBN/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O impact/impact/NN/O on/on/IN/O many/many/JJ/O other/other/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O ,/,/,/O leading/lead/VBG/O to/to/TO/O language/language/NN/O shift/shift/NN/O and/and/CC/O even/even/RB/O language/language/NN/O death/death/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O to/to/TO/O claims/claim/NNS/O of/of/IN/O linguistic/linguistic/JJ/O imperialism/imperialism/NN/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC itself/itself/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O become/become/VBN/O more/more/RBR/O open/open/JJ/O to/to/TO/O language/language/NN/O shift/shift/NN/O as/as/IN/O multiple/multiple/JJ/O regional/regional/JJ/O varieties/variety/NNS/O feed/feed/VBP/O back/back/RB/O into/into/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O whole/whole/NN/O ./././O
Dialects/dialect/NNS/O and/and/CC/O varieties/variety/NNS/O ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC has/have/VBZ/O been/be/VBN/O subject/subject/JJ/O to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O degree/degree/NN/O of/of/IN/O regional/regional/JJ/O dialect/dialect/NN/O variation/variation/NN/O for/for/IN/O many/many/JJ/O centuries/century/NNS/DURATION ./././O
Its/its/PRP$/O global/global/JJ/O spread/spread/NN/O now/now/RB/DATE means/mean/VBZ/O that/that/IN/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O and/and/CC/O English-based/english-based/JJ/MISC creole/creole/NN/O languages/language/NNS/O and/and/CC/O pidgins/pidgin/NNS/O can/can/MD/O be/be/VB/O found/find/VBN/O all/all/DT/O over/over/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ./././O
Several/several/JJ/O educated/educate/VBN/O native/native/JJ/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC have/have/VBP/O wide/wide/JJ/O acceptance/acceptance/NN/O as/as/IN/O standards/standard/NNS/O in/in/IN/O much/much/JJ/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Kingdom/Kingdom/NNP/LOCATION much/much/JJ/O emphasis/emphasis/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O placed/place/VBN/O on/on/IN/O Received/receive/VBN/MISC Pronunciation/pronunciation/NN/MISC ,/,/,/O an/a/DT/O educated/educate/VBN/O dialect/dialect/NN/O of/of/IN/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION East/East/NNP/LOCATION England/England/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
General/General/NNP/O American/American/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O is/be/VBZ/O spread/spread/VBN/O over/over/IN/O most/most/JJS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION and/and/CC/O much/much/RB/O of/of/IN/O Canada/Canada/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O is/be/VBZ/O more/more/RBR/O typically/typically/RB/O the/the/DT/O model/model/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O American/american/JJ/MISC continents/continent/NNS/O and/and/CC/O areas/area/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O Philippines/Philippines/NNPS/LOCATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O that/that/WDT/O have/have/VBP/O had/have/VBN/O either/either/CC/O close/close/JJ/O association/association/NN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O or/or/CC/O a/a/DT/O desire/desire/NN/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O so/so/RB/O identified/identify/VBN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O Oceania/Oceania/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O major/major/JJ/O native/native/JJ/O dialect/dialect/NN/O of/of/IN/O Australian/australian/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O spoken/speak/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL language/language/NN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O vast/vast/JJ/O majority/majority/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O inhabitants/inhabitant/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Australian/australian/JJ/MISC continent/continent/NN/O ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O General/General/NNP/O Australian/Australian/NNP/MISC serving/serve/VBG/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O standard/standard/JJ/O accent/accent/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC of/of/IN/O neighbouring/neighbouring/JJ/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION Zealand/Zealand/NNP/LOCATION as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O that/that/DT/O of/of/IN/O South/South/NNP/LOCATION Africa/Africa/NNP/LOCATION have/have/VBP/O to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O lesser/lesser/JJR/O degree/degree/NN/O been/be/VBN/O influential/influential/JJ/O native/native/JJ/O varieties/variety/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
Aside/aside/RB/O from/from/IN/O these/these/DT/O major/major/JJ/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ,/,/,/O there/there/EX/O are/be/VBP/O numerous/numerous/JJ/O other/other/JJ/O varieties/variety/NNS/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O include/include/VBP/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O most/most/JJS/O cases/case/NNS/O ,/,/,/O several/several/JJ/O subvarieties/subvariety/NNS/O ,/,/,/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O Cockney/Cockney/NNP/O ,/,/,/O Scouse/Scouse/NNP/O and/and/CC/O Geordie/Geordie/NNP/PERSON within/within/IN/O British/British/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ;/;/:/O Newfoundland/Newfoundland/NNP/LOCATION English/English/NNP/MISC within/within/IN/O Canadian/Canadian/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ;/;/:/O and/and/CC/O African/african/JJ/MISC American/american/JJ/MISC Vernacular/Vernacular/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O ``/``/``/O Ebonics/ebonic/NNS/MISC ''/''/''/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O Southern/southern/JJ/MISC American/american/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC within/within/IN/O American/American/NNP/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O pluricentric/pluricentric/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ,/,/,/O without/without/IN/O a/a/DT/O central/central/JJ/O language/language/NN/O authority/authority/NN/O like/like/IN/O France/France/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O Académie/Académie/NNP/MISC française/française/NN/O ;/;/:/O and/and/CC/O therefore/therefore/RB/O no/no/DT/O one/one/NN/NUMBER variety/variety/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O considered/consider/VBN/O ``/``/``/O correct/correct/JJ/O ''/''/''/O or/or/CC/O ``/``/``/O incorrect/incorrect/JJ/O ''/''/''/O except/except/IN/O in/in/IN/O terms/term/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O expectations/expectation/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O particular/particular/JJ/O audience/audience/NN/O to/to/TO/O which/which/WDT/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O directed/direct/VBN/O ./././O
Scots/Scots/NNP/O has/have/VBZ/O its/its/PRP$/O origins/origin/NNS/O in/in/IN/O early/early/JJ/O Northern/northern/JJ/O Middle/middle/NN/O English/English/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O developed/develop/VBD/O and/and/CC/O changed/change/VBD/O during/during/IN/O its/its/PRP$/O history/history/NN/O with/with/IN/O influence/influence/NN/O from/from/IN/O other/other/JJ/O sources/source/NNS/O ./././O
However/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O following/follow/VBG/O the/the/DT/O Acts/act/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Union/Union/NNP/O 1707/1707/CD/DATE a/a/DT/O process/process/NN/O of/of/IN/O language/language/NN/O attrition/attrition/NN/O began/begin/VBD/O ,/,/,/O whereby/whereby/WRB/O successive/successive/JJ/O generations/generation/NNS/O adopted/adopt/VBD/O more/more/RBR/O and/and/CC/O more/more/RBR/O features/feature/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Standard/standard/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
Whether/whether/IN/O Scots/Scots/NNP/O is/be/VBZ/O now/now/RB/DATE a/a/DT/O separate/separate/JJ/O language/language/NN/O or/or/CC/O is/be/VBZ/O better/better/RBR/O described/describe/VBN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O dialect/dialect/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O i.e./i.e./FW/O part/part/NN/O of/of/IN/O Scottish/scottish/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O is/be/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O dispute/dispute/NN/O ,/,/,/O although/although/IN/O the/the/DT/O UK/UK/NNP/LOCATION government/government/NN/O accepts/accept/VBZ/O Scots/scot/NNS/ORGANIZATION as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O regional/regional/JJ/O language/language/NN/O and/and/CC/O has/have/VBZ/O recognized/recognize/VBN/O it/it/PRP/O as/as/IN/O such/such/JJ/O under/under/IN/O the/the/DT/O European/european/JJ/O Charter/Charter/NNP/O for/for/IN/O Regional/Regional/NNP/O or/or/CC/O Minority/Minority/NNP/O Languages/Languages/NNPS/O ./././O
There/there/EX/O are/be/VBP/O a/a/DT/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O regional/regional/JJ/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Scots/Scots/NNP/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O pronunciation/pronunciation/NN/O ,/,/,/O grammar/grammar/NN/O and/and/CC/O lexis/lexis/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O traditional/traditional/JJ/O forms/form/NNS/O differ/differ/VBP/O ,/,/,/O sometimes/sometimes/RB/O substantially/substantially/RB/O ,/,/,/O from/from/IN/O other/other/JJ/O varieties/variety/NNS/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
English/English/NNP/MISC speakers/speaker/NNS/O have/have/VBP/O many/many/JJ/O different/different/JJ/O accents/accent/NNS/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O often/often/RB/O signal/signal/VBP/O the/the/DT/O speaker/speaker/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O native/native/JJ/O dialect/dialect/NN/O or/or/CC/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O distinctive/distinctive/JJ/O characteristics/characteristic/NNS/O of/of/IN/O regional/regional/JJ/O accents/accent/NNS/O ,/,/,/O see/see/VBP/O Regional/Regional/NNP/O accents/accent/NNS/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O for/for/IN/O a/a/DT/O complete/complete/JJ/O list/list/NN/O of/of/IN/O regional/regional/JJ/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ,/,/,/O see/see/VBP/O List/list/NN/O of/of/IN/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC language/language/NN/O ./././O
Within/within/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O variation/variation/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O now/now/RB/DATE largely/largely/RB/O confined/confine/VBN/O to/to/TO/O pronunciation/pronunciation/NN/O rather/rather/RB/O than/than/IN/O grammar/grammar/NN/O or/or/CC/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O ./././O
At/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O time/time/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Survey/survey/NN/MISC of/of/IN/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC Dialects/Dialects/NNPS/MISC ,/,/,/O grammar/grammar/NN/O and/and/CC/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O differed/differ/VBD/O across/across/IN/O the/the/DT/O country/country/NN/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O a/a/DT/O process/process/NN/O of/of/IN/O lexical/lexical/JJ/O attrition/attrition/NN/O has/have/VBZ/O led/lead/VBN/O most/most/JJS/O of/of/IN/O this/this/DT/O variation/variation/NN/O to/to/TO/O die/die/VB/O out/out/RP/O ./././O
Just/just/RB/O as/as/IN/O English/english/JJ/MISC itself/itself/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O borrowed/borrow/VBN/O words/word/NNS/O from/from/IN/O many/many/JJ/O different/different/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O over/over/IN/O its/its/PRP$/O history/history/NN/O ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC loanwords/loanword/NNS/O now/now/RB/DATE appear/appear/VBP/O in/in/IN/O many/many/JJ/O languages/language/NNS/O around/around/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O indicative/indicative/JJ/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O technological/technological/JJ/O and/and/CC/O cultural/cultural/JJ/O influence/influence/NN/O of/of/IN/O its/its/PRP$/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O ./././O
Several/several/JJ/O pidgins/pidgin/NNS/O and/and/CC/O creole/creole/NN/O languages/language/NNS/O have/have/VBP/O been/be/VBN/O formed/form/VBN/O on/on/IN/O an/a/DT/O English/english/JJ/MISC base/base/NN/O ,/,/,/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O Jamaican/jamaican/JJ/MISC Patois/patois/NN/MISC ,/,/,/O Nigerian/nigerian/JJ/MISC Pidgin/Pidgin/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Tok/Tok/NNP/PERSON Pisin/Pisin/NNP/PERSON ./././O
There/there/EX/O are/be/VBP/O many/many/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O in/in/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC coined/coin/VBD/O to/to/TO/O describe/describe/VB/O forms/form/NNS/O of/of/IN/O particular/particular/JJ/O non-English/non-english/JJ/MISC languages/language/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O contain/contain/VBP/O a/a/DT/O very/very/RB/O high/high/JJ/O proportion/proportion/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC words/word/NNS/O ./././O
Register/Register/NNP/O effects/effect/NNS/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O well-established/well-established/JJ/O that/that/IN/O informal/informal/JJ/O speech/speech/NN/O registers/register/VBZ/O tend/tend/VB/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O made/make/VBN/O up/up/RP/O predominantly/predominantly/RB/O of/of/IN/O words/word/NNS/O of/of/IN/O Anglo-Saxon/Anglo-Saxon/NNP/O or/or/CC/O Germanic/germanic/JJ/MISC origin/origin/NN/O ,/,/,/O whereas/whereas/IN/O the/the/DT/O Latinate/latinate/JJ/MISC vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O usually/usually/RB/O reserved/reserve/VBN/O for/for/IN/O more/more/JJR/O formal/formal/JJ/O uses/use/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O legal/legal/JJ/O ,/,/,/O scientific/scientific/JJ/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O otherwise/otherwise/RB/O scholarly/scholarly/JJ/O or/or/CC/O academic/academic/JJ/O texts/text/NNS/O ./././O
Child-directed/child-directed/JJ/O speech/speech/NN/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O is/be/VBZ/O an/a/DT/O informal/informal/JJ/O speech/speech/NN/O register/register/NN/O ,/,/,/O also/also/RB/O tends/tend/VBZ/O to/to/TO/O rely/rely/VB/O heavily/heavily/RB/O on/on/IN/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O rife/rife/JJ/O in/in/IN/O words/word/NNS/O derived/derive/VBN/O from/from/IN/O Anglo-Saxon/Anglo-Saxon/NNP/MISC ./././O
The/the/DT/O speech/speech/NN/O of/of/IN/O mothers/mother/NNS/O to/to/TO/O young/young/JJ/O children/child/NNS/O has/have/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O higher/higher/JJR/O percentage/percentage/NN/O of/of/IN/O native/native/JJ/O Anglo-Saxon/anglo-saxon/JJ/MISC verb/verb/NN/O tokens/token/NNS/O than/than/IN/O speech/speech/NN/O addressed/address/VBD/O to/to/TO/O adults/adult/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O particular/particular/JJ/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O parents/parent/NNS/O '/'/POS/O child-directed/child-directed/JJ/O speech/speech/NN/O the/the/DT/O clausal/clausal/JJ/O core/core/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O built/build/VBN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O most/most/JJS/O part/part/NN/O by/by/IN/O Anglo-Saxon/anglo-saxon/JJ/MISC verbs/verb/NNS/O ,/,/,/O namely/namely/RB/O ,/,/,/O almost/almost/RB/O all/all/DT/O tokens/token/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O grammatical/grammatical/JJ/O relations/relation/NNS/O subject-verb/subject-verb/JJ/O ,/,/,/O verb-direct/verb-direct/JJ/O object/object/NN/O and/and/CC/O verb-indirect/verb-indirect/JJ/O object/object/NN/O that/that/WDT/O young/young/JJ/O children/child/NNS/O are/be/VBP/O presented/present/VBN/O with/with/IN/O ,/,/,/O are/be/VBP/O constructed/construct/VBN/O with/with/IN/O native/native/JJ/O verbs/verb/NNS/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O Anglo-Saxon/anglo-saxon/JJ/MISC verb/verb/NN/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O consists/consist/VBZ/O of/of/IN/O short/short/JJ/O verbs/verb/NNS/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O its/its/PRP$/O grammar/grammar/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O relatively/relatively/RB/O complex/complex/JJ/O ./././O
Syntactic/syntactic/JJ/MISC patterns/pattern/NNS/O specific/specific/JJ/O to/to/TO/O this/this/DT/O sub-vocabulary/sub-vocabulary/JJ/O in/in/IN/O present-day/present-day/JJ/O English/english/JJ/MISC include/include/VBP/O periphrastic/periphrastic/JJ/O constructions/construction/NNS/O for/for/IN/O tense/tense/JJ/O ,/,/,/O aspect/aspect/NN/O ,/,/,/O questioning/question/VBG/O and/and/CC/O negation/negation/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O phrasal/phrasal/JJ/O lexemes/lexeme/NNS/O functioning/function/VBG/O as/as/IN/O complex/complex/JJ/O predicates/predicate/NNS/O ,/,/,/O all/all/DT/O of/of/IN/O which/which/WDT/O also/also/RB/O occur/occur/VBP/O in/in/IN/O child-directed/child-directed/JJ/O speech/speech/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O historical/historical/JJ/O origin/origin/NN/O of/of/IN/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O items/item/NNS/O affects/affect/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O order/order/NN/O of/of/IN/O acquisition/acquisition/NN/O of/of/IN/O various/various/JJ/O aspects/aspect/NNS/O of/of/IN/O language/language/NN/O development/development/NN/O in/in/IN/O English-speaking/english-speaking/JJ/MISC children/child/NNS/O ./././O
Latinate/latinate/JJ/MISC vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O general/general/JJ/O a/a/DT/O later/later/JJ/O acquisition/acquisition/NN/O in/in/IN/O children/child/NNS/O than/than/IN/O the/the/DT/O native/native/JJ/O Anglo-Saxon/Anglo-Saxon/NNP/MISC one/one/CD/NUMBER ./././O
Young/young/JJ/O children/child/NNS/O almost/almost/RB/O exclusively/exclusively/RB/O use/use/VB/O the/the/DT/O native/native/JJ/O verb/verb/NN/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O in/in/IN/O constructing/construct/VBG/O basic/basic/JJ/O grammatical/grammatical/JJ/O relations/relation/NNS/O ,/,/,/O apparently/apparently/RB/O mastering/master/VBG/O its/its/PRP$/O analytic/analytic/JJ/O aspects/aspect/NNS/O at/at/IN/O an/a/DT/O early/early/JJ/O stage/stage/NN/O ./././O
Formal/formal/JJ/O written/write/VBN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
A/a/DT/O version/version/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O almost/almost/RB/O universally/universally/RB/O agreed/agree/VBN/O upon/upon/IN/O by/by/IN/O educated/educate/VBN/O English/English/NNP/MISC speakers/speaker/NNS/O around/around/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O called/call/VBN/O formal/formal/JJ/O written/write/VBN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
It/it/PRP/O takes/take/VBZ/O virtually/virtually/RB/O the/the/DT/O same/same/JJ/O form/form/NN/O regardless/regardless/RB/O of/of/IN/O where/where/WRB/O it/it/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O written/write/VBN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O contrast/contrast/NN/O to/to/TO/O spoken/speak/VBN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O differs/differ/VBZ/O significantly/significantly/RB/O between/between/IN/O dialects/dialect/NNS/O ,/,/,/O accents/accent/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O varieties/variety/NNS/O of/of/IN/O slang/slang/NN/O and/and/CC/O of/of/IN/O colloquial/colloquial/JJ/O and/and/CC/O regional/regional/JJ/O expressions/expression/NNS/O ./././O
Local/local/JJ/O variations/variation/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O formal/formal/JJ/O written/write/VBN/O version/version/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O are/be/VBP/O quite/quite/RB/O limited/limited/JJ/O ,/,/,/O being/be/VBG/O restricted/restrict/VBN/O largely/largely/RB/O to/to/TO/O minor/minor/JJ/O spelling/spelling/NN/O ,/,/,/O lexical/lexical/JJ/O and/and/CC/O grammatical/grammatical/JJ/O differences/difference/NNS/O between/between/IN/O British/british/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O American/american/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O other/other/JJ/O national/national/JJ/O varieties/variety/NNS/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
Simplified/simplify/VBN/O and/and/CC/O constructed/construct/VBN/O varieties/variety/NNS/O ./././O
Artificially/artificially/RB/O simplified/simplify/VBN/O versions/version/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O language/language/NN/O have/have/VBP/O been/be/VBN/O created/create/VBN/O that/that/WDT/O are/be/VBP/O easier/easier/JJR/O for/for/IN/O non-native/non-native/JJ/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O to/to/TO/O read/read/VB/O ./././O
Basic/basic/JJ/O English/English/NNP/MISC is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O constructed/construct/VBN/O language/language/NN/O ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O restricted/restricted/JJ/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O words/word/NNS/O ,/,/,/O created/create/VBN/O by/by/IN/O Charles/Charles/NNP/PERSON Kay/Kay/NNP/PERSON Ogden/Ogden/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O described/describe/VBN/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O book/book/NN/O Basic/basic/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC :/:/:/O A/A/NNP/O General/General/NNP/O Introduction/introduction/NN/O with/with/IN/O Rules/rule/NNS/MISC and/and/CC/O Grammar/grammar/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 1930/1930/CD/DATE -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
Ogden/Ogden/NNP/PERSON said/say/VBD/O that/that/IN/O it/it/PRP/O would/would/MD/O take/take/VB/O seven/seven/CD/DURATION years/year/NNS/NUMBER to/to/TO/O learn/learn/VB/O English/English/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O seven/seven/CD/DURATION months/month/NNS/NUMBER for/for/IN/O Esperanto/esperanto/JJ/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O seven/seven/CD/DURATION weeks/week/NNS/NUMBER for/for/IN/O Basic/basic/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC ./././O
-LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O citation/citation/NN/O needed/need/VBN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O Thus/thus/RB/O ,/,/,/O Basic/basic/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC may/may/MD/O be/be/VB/O employed/employ/VBN/O by/by/IN/O companies/company/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O need/need/VBP/O to/to/TO/O make/make/VB/O complex/complex/JJ/O books/book/NNS/O for/for/IN/O international/international/JJ/O use/use/NN/O ,/,/,/O as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O by/by/IN/O language/language/NN/O schools/school/NNS/O that/that/WDT/O need/need/VBP/O to/to/TO/O impart/impart/VB/O some/some/DT/O knowledge/knowledge/NN/O of/of/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O short/short/JJ/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
Ogden/Ogden/NNP/PERSON did/do/VBD/O not/not/RB/O include/include/VB/O any/any/DT/O words/word/NNS/O in/in/IN/O Basic/basic/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC that/that/WDT/O could/could/MD/O be/be/VB/O said/say/VBN/O instead/instead/RB/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O combination/combination/NN/O of/of/IN/O other/other/JJ/O words/word/NNS/O already/already/RB/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Basic/basic/JJ/MISC English/English/NNP/MISC lexicon/lexicon/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O he/he/PRP/O worked/work/VBD/O to/to/TO/O make/make/VB/O the/the/DT/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O suitable/suitable/JJ/O for/for/IN/O speakers/speaker/NNS/O of/of/IN/O any/any/DT/O other/other/JJ/O language/language/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O put/put/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O vocabulary/vocabulary/NN/O selections/selection/NNS/O through/through/IN/O a/a/DT/O large/large/JJ/O number/number/NN/O of/of/IN/O tests/test/NNS/O and/and/CC/O adjustments/adjustment/NNS/O ./././O
Ogden/Ogden/NNP/PERSON also/also/RB/O simplified/simplify/VBD/O the/the/DT/O grammar/grammar/NN/O but/but/CC/O tried/try/VBD/O to/to/TO/O keep/keep/VB/O it/it/PRP/O normal/normal/JJ/O for/for/IN/O English/English/NNP/MISC users/user/NNS/O ./././O
