Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Clinton/Clinton/NNP/PERSON Drew/Drew/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O born/bear/VBN/O March/March/NNP/DATE 9/9/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 1983/1983/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O is/be/VBZ/O an/a/DT/O American/american/JJ/MISC soccer/soccer/NN/O player/player/NN/O who/who/WP/O plays/play/VBZ/O for/for/IN/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/Hotspur/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION national/national/JJ/O team/team/NN/O ./././O
Growing/grow/VBG/O up/up/RP/O in/in/IN/O Nacogdoches/Nacogdoches/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Texas/Texas/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON played/play/VBD/O for/for/IN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O top/top/JJ/O youth/youth/NN/O soccer/soccer/NN/O clubs/club/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O state/state/NN/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O Dallas/Dallas/NNP/LOCATION Texans/Texans/NNPS/MISC ,/,/,/O before/before/IN/O playing/play/VBG/O for/for/IN/O Furman/Furman/NNP/ORGANIZATION University/University/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O men/man/NNS/O 's/'s/POS/O soccer/soccer/NN/O team/team/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O 2004/2004/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O drafted/draft/VBN/O by/by/IN/O Major/Major/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION Soccer/Soccer/NNP/ORGANIZATION club/club/NN/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION England/England/NNP/LOCATION Revolution/Revolution/NNP/O ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O quickly/quickly/RB/O integrated/integrate/VBD/O himself/himself/PRP/O into/into/IN/O the/the/DT/O starting/start/VBG/O lineup/lineup/NN/O ./././O
Hindered/hinder/VBN/O initially/initially/RB/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O jaw/jaw/NN/O injury/injury/NN/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O would/would/MD/O eventually/eventually/RB/O score/score/VB/NUMBER 25/25/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O 71/71/CD/NUMBER appearances/appearance/NNS/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O Revolution/revolution/NN/O ./././O
Between/between/IN/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE and/and/CC/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON played/play/VBD/O for/for/IN/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION team/team/NN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O highest/highest/JJS/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC goalscorer/goalscorer/NN/O of/of/IN/O all/all/DT/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON first/first/RB/ORDINAL represented/represent/VBD/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2003/2003/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/ORGANIZATION Youth/Youth/NNP/ORGANIZATION Championship/Championship/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Arab/Arab/NNP/LOCATION Emirates/Emirates/NNPS/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL appearance/appearance/NN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O senior/senior/JJ/O team/team/NN/O on/on/IN/O November/November/NNP/DATE 17/17/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2004/2004/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O against/against/IN/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION ;/;/:/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O then/then/RB/O named/name/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O squad/squad/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O only/only/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O tournament/tournament/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON recorded/record/VBD/O the/the/DT/O fastest/fastest/JJS/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC qualifying/qualify/VBG/O history/history/NN/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O after/after/IN/O 53/53/CD/DURATION seconds/seconds/NNS/NUMBER of/of/IN/O an/a/DT/O eventual/eventual/JJ/O 8/8/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O of/of/IN/O Barbados/Barbados/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O later/later/RB/O bested/best/VBD/O that/that/IN/O feat/feat/NN/O in/in/IN/O 2012/2012/CD/DATE scoring/score/VBG/O just/just/RB/O 36/36/CD/DURATION seconds/seconds/NNS/NUMBER into/into/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER qualifying/qualify/VBG/O loss/loss/NN/O at/at/IN/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cup/Cup/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O against/against/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL American/American/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O multiple/multiple/JJ/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC tournaments/tournament/NNS/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL American/american/JJ/MISC player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O English/English/NNP/MISC Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Newcastle/Newcastle/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O January/January/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ./././O
Youth/youth/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O born/bear/VBN/O in/in/IN/O Nacogdoches/Nacogdoches/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Texas/Texas/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O ,/,/,/O for/for/IN/O much/much/JJ/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O childhood/childhood/NN/O ,/,/,/O his/he/PRP$/O family/family/NN/O lived/live/VBD/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O trailer/trailer/NN/O park/park/NN/O ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O and/and/CC/O his/he/PRP$/O siblings/sibling/NNS/O grew/grow/VBD/O up/up/RP/O playing/play/VBG/O soccer/soccer/NN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O local/local/JJ/O children/child/NNS/O or/or/CC/O anyone/anyone/NN/O they/they/PRP/O could/could/MD/O find/find/VB/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O older/older/JJR/O brother/brother/NN/O Ryan/Ryan/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O offered/offer/VBN/O a/a/DT/O tryout/tryout/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O Dallas/Dallas/NNP/LOCATION Texans/Texans/NNPS/MISC ,/,/,/O an/a/DT/O elite/elite/JJ/O youth/youth/NN/O soccer/soccer/NN/O club/club/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O brought/bring/VBD/O Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O was/be/VBD/O noticed/notice/VBN/O and/and/CC/O recruited/recruit/VBN/O while/while/IN/O passing/pass/VBG/O time/time/NN/O juggling/juggle/VBG/O a/a/DT/O ball/ball/NN/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O sidelines/sideline/NNS/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O a/a/DT/O standout/standout/NN/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O at/at/IN/O an/a/DT/O early/early/JJ/O age/age/NN/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O had/have/VBD/O to/to/TO/O quit/quit/VB/O due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O his/he/PRP$/O family/family/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O time/time/NN/O and/and/CC/O money/money/NN/O constraints/constraint/NNS/O as/as/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O eldest/eldest/JJ/O sister/sister/NN/O Jennifer/Jennifer/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O becoming/become/VBG/O a/a/DT/O ranked/rank/VBN/O youth/youth/NN/O tennis/tennis/NN/O player/player/NN/O ./././O
Several/several/JJ/O parents/parent/NNS/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O teammates/teammate/NNS/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O Texans/Texans/NNPS/MISC offered/offer/VBD/O to/to/TO/O assist/assist/VB/O the/the/DT/O Dempseys/Dempseys/NNPS/ORGANIZATION with/with/IN/O expenses/expense/NNS/O and/and/CC/O travel/travel/NN/O ,/,/,/O allowing/allow/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O rejoin/rejoin/VB/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O November/November/NNP/DATE 27/27/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 1995/1995/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON lost/lose/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O then/then/RB/O 16-year-old/16-year-old/JJ/DURATION sister/sister/NN/O Jennifer/Jennifer/NNP/PERSON to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O brain/brain/NN/O aneurysm/aneurysm/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O devastated/devastate/VBN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O family/family/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O loss/loss/NN/O and/and/CC/O later/later/RB/O explained/explain/VBD/O that/that/IN/O this/this/DT/O event/event/NN/O helped/help/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O developed/develop/VBD/O a/a/DT/O deeper/deeper/JJR/O motivation/motivation/NN/O to/to/TO/O pursue/pursue/VB/O soccer/soccer/NN/O ;/;/:/O in/in/IN/O honor/honor/NN/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O sister/sister/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O went/go/VBD/O on/on/IN/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O the/the/DT/O captain/captain/NN/O and/and/CC/O high/high/JJ/O scorer/scorer/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Texans/Texans/NNPS/MISC and/and/CC/O was/be/VBD/O honored/honor/VBN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O MVP/mvp/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Tampa/Tampa/NNP/LOCATION Bay/Bay/NNP/LOCATION Sun/Sun/NNP/LOCATION Bowl/Bowl/NNP/LOCATION tournament/tournament/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON studied/study/VBD/O the/the/DT/O play/play/NN/O of/of/IN/O Argentina/Argentina/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O national/national/JJ/O team/team/NN/O ,/,/,/O especially/especially/RB/O Diego/diego/JJ/PERSON Maradona/Maradona/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O heartbroken/heartbroken/VBN/O when/when/WRB/O the/the/DT/O news/news/NN/O came/come/VBD/O to/to/TO/O Nacogdoches/nacogdoch/NNS/LOCATION that/that/WDT/O Maradona/Maradona/NNP/PERSON would/would/MD/O not/not/RB/O be/be/VB/O playing/play/VBG/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 1994/1994/CD/DATE World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC game/game/NN/O played/play/VBD/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Cotton/Cotton/NNP/O Bowl/Bowl/NNP/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O attended/attend/VBD/O Furman/Furman/NNP/ORGANIZATION University/University/NNP/ORGANIZATION as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O health/health/NN/O and/and/CC/O exercise/exercise/NN/O major/major/JJ/O and/and/CC/O a/a/DT/O key/key/JJ/O player/player/NN/O for/for/IN/O Paladins/Paladins/NNPS/O football/football/NN/O ./././O
Club/Club/NNP/O career/career/NN/O ./././O
New/New/NNP/O England/England/NNP/O Revolution/Revolution/NNP/O ./././O
New/New/NNP/O England/England/NNP/O Revolution/Revolution/NNP/O selected/select/VBD/O Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON eighth/eighth/JJ/ORDINAL overall/overall/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2004/2004/CD/DATE MLS/MLS/NNP/MISC SuperDraft/SuperDraft/NNP/MISC ./././O
In/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O rookie/rookie/NN/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O started/start/VBD/O 23/23/CD/TIME of/of/IN/TIME 24/24/CD/TIME matches/match/NNS/O scoring/score/VBG/O seven/seven/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON helped/help/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Revolution/revolution/NN/MISC to/to/TO/MISC the/the/DT/MISC Eastern/Eastern/NNP/MISC Conference/Conference/NNP/MISC Finals/Finals/NNP/MISC and/and/CC/O earned/earn/VBD/O 2004/2004/CD/DATE MLS/MLS/NNP/O Rookie/rookie/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE Honors/honor/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON contributed/contribute/VBD/O ten/ten/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O and/and/CC/O nine/nine/CD/NUMBER assists/assist/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O 26/26/CD/NUMBER games/game/NNS/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O game-winning/game-winning/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Eastern/Eastern/NNP/O Conference/Conference/NNP/O Final/Final/NNP/O on/on/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O way/way/NN/O to/to/TO/O an/a/DT/O appearance/appearance/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O MLS/MLS/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC Final/Final/NNP/MISC ./././O
In/in/IN/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON added/add/VBD/O 8/8/CD/NUMBER more/more/JJR/O goals/goal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O missed/miss/VBD/O significant/significant/JJ/O time/time/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O playoffs/playoff/NNS/O due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O injury/injury/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O came/come/VBD/O on/on/IN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O substitute/substitute/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O MLS/MLS/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC Final/Final/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O the/the/DT/O Revolution/revolution/NN/O lost/lose/VBD/O their/they/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL straight/straight/JJ/O final/final/JJ/O ,/,/,/O this/this/DT/O time/time/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O penalty/penalty/NN/O shoot-out/shoot-out/NN/O ./././O
Fulham/Fulham/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
2006/2006/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 07/07/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O English/English/NNP/MISC club/club/NN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION offered/offer/VBD/O MLS/MLS/NNP/O $/$/$/MONEY 4/4/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O transfer/transfer/NN/O of/of/IN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O then/then/RB/O the/the/DT/O largest/largest/JJS/O amount/amount/NN/O ever/ever/RB/O offered/offer/VBN/O for/for/IN/O an/a/DT/O MLS/ml/NN/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O and/and/CC/O became/become/VBD/O another/another/DT/O American/american/JJ/MISC addition/addition/NN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Cottagers/Cottagers/NNPS/O roster/roster/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O January/January/NNP/DATE 11/11/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2007/2007/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O granted/grant/VBN/O a/a/DT/O work/work/NN/O permit/permit/NN/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O Home/Home/NNP/O Office/Office/NNP/O as/as/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION announced/announce/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O signing/signing/NN/O on/on/IN/O a/a/DT/O long-term/long-term/JJ/O deal/deal/NN/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O made/make/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O expensive/expensive/JJ/O US/US/NNP/LOCATION export/export/NN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O deal/deal/NN/O worth/worth/IN/O a/a/DT/O reported/report/VBN/O #/#/#/MONEY 2/2/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY ./././O
He/he/PRP/O made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION debut/debut/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O draw/draw/NN/O against/against/IN/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/Hotspur/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O January/January/NNP/DATE 20/20/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2007/2007/CD/DATE ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O FA/FA/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC debut/debut/NN/O followed/follow/VBD/O seven/seven/CD/DATE days/day/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Stoke/Stoke/NNP/ORGANIZATION City/City/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O for/for/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 5/5/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O struck/strike/VBD/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Liverpool/Liverpool/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
This/this/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O saved/save/VBD/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION from/from/IN/O relegation/relegation/NN/O and/and/CC/O effectively/effectively/RB/O guaranteed/guarantee/VBN/O their/they/PRP$/O place/place/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O top-flight/top-flight/JJ/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O following/follow/VBG/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
2007/2007/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 08/08/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O August/August/NNP/DATE 25/25/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 08/08/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O loss/loss/NN/O to/to/TO/O Aston/Aston/NNP/ORGANIZATION Villa/Villa/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O followed/follow/VBD/O this/this/DT/O up/up/RP/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O in/in/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O next/next/JJ/O fixture/fixture/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O draw/draw/NN/O against/against/IN/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 1/1/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ./././O
Two/two/CD/DATE weeks/week/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O opened/open/VBD/O the/the/DT/O scoring/score/VBG/O in/in/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O draw/draw/VB/O against/against/IN/O Wigan/Wigan/NNP/ORGANIZATION Athletic/Athletic/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
These/these/DT/O goals/goal/NNS/O gave/give/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON three/three/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O as/as/RB/O many/many/JJ/O games/game/NNS/O after/after/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION manager/manager/NN/O Lawrie/Lawrie/NNP/PERSON Sanchez/Sanchez/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O decision/decision/NN/O to/to/TO/O convert/convert/VB/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON into/into/IN/O a/a/DT/O striker/striker/NN/O following/follow/VBG/O an/a/DT/O injury/injury/NN/O to/to/TO/O compatriot/compatriot/NN/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON ./././O
On/on/IN/O September/September/NNP/DATE 29/29/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O involved/involve/VBN/O in/in/IN/O an/a/DT/O aerial/aerial/JJ/O collision/collision/NN/O with/with/IN/O John/John/NNP/PERSON Terry/Terry/NNP/PERSON during/during/IN/O a/a/DT/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER draw/draw/NN/O at/at/IN/O Stamford/Stamford/NNP/LOCATION Bridge/Bridge/NNP/LOCATION which/which/WDT/O resulted/result/VBD/O in/in/IN/O Terry/Terry/NNP/PERSON being/be/VBG/O substituted/substitute/VBN/O ./././O
There/there/EX/O was/be/VBD/O some/some/DT/O suggestion/suggestion/NN/O that/that/WDT/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON used/use/VBD/O a/a/DT/O deliberate/deliberate/JJ/O elbow/elbow/NN/O on/on/IN/O Terry/Terry/NNP/PERSON ;/;/:/O however/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O n't/not/RB/O punished/punish/VBN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O incident/incident/NN/O as/as/IN/O referee/referee/NN/O Martin/Martin/NNP/PERSON Atkinson/Atkinson/NNP/PERSON did/do/VBD/O n't/not/RB/O report/report/VB/O it/it/PRP/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Football/Football/NNP/ORGANIZATION Association/Association/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O November/November/NNP/DATE 3/3/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O during/during/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Reading/read/VBG/O to/to/TO/O secure/secure/VB/O just/just/RB/O a/a/DT/DURATION second/second/JJ/DURATION league/league/NN/O win/win/VB/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O last/last/JJ/O goals/goal/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O draw/draw/NN/O with/with/IN/O Wigan/Wigan/NNP/ORGANIZATION Athletic/Athletic/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O loss/loss/NN/O to/to/TO/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE ./././O
In/in/IN/O May/May/NNP/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION announced/announce/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O signed/sign/VBN/O a/a/DT/O contract/contract/NN/O extension/extension/NN/O which/which/WDT/O would/would/MD/O keep/keep/VB/O him/he/PRP/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O until/until/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE summer/summer/NN/DATE of/of/IN/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ./././O
Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION beat/beat/VBD/O Portsmouth/Portsmouth/NNP/ORGANIZATION 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/DURATION final/final/JJ/DURATION day/day/NN/DURATION of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O to/to/TO/O secure/secure/VB/O Premier/Premier/NNP/O League/League/NNP/O status/status/NN/O for/for/IN/O another/another/DT/DURATION year/year/NN/DURATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O ended/end/VBD/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O as/as/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O top/top/JJ/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION goalscorer/goalscorer/NN/O with/with/IN/O six/six/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ./././O
2008/2008/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 09/09/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2008/2008/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 09/09/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O draw/draw/VB/O at/at/IN/O Portsmouth/Portsmouth/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O October/October/NNP/DATE 26/26/CD/DATE ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL home/home/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O came/come/VBD/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Middlesbrough/Middlesbrough/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE 20/20/CD/DATE ./././O
Eight/eight/CD/DATE days/day/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O twice/twice/RB/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O West/West/NNP/LOCATION London/London/NNP/LOCATION derby/derby/NN/O against/against/IN/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION which/which/WDT/O included/include/VBD/O a/a/DT/O last-minute/last-minute/JJ/O equaliser/equaliser/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O draw/draw/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O February/February/NNP/DATE 24/24/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL FA/FA/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O career/career/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Swansea/Swansea/NNP/LOCATION City/City/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O fifth-round/fifth-round/JJ/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O final/final/JJ/O home/home/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O came/come/VBD/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O to/to/TO/O Blackburn/Blackburn/NNP/ORGANIZATION Rovers/Rovers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O March/March/NNP/DATE 11/11/CD/DATE ./././O
Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION came/come/VBD/O from/from/IN/O a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O down/down/IN/O to/to/TO/O beat/beat/VB/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION City/City/NNP/ORGANIZATION 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O from/from/IN/O home/home/NN/O as/as/IN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O on/on/IN/O April/April/NNP/DATE 12/12/CD/DATE ./././O
For/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL successive/successive/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON ended/end/VBD/O as/as/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O top/top/JJ/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION goalscorer/goalscorer/NN/O joint/joint/NN/O with/with/IN/O Andrew/Andrew/NNP/PERSON Johnson/Johnson/NNP/PERSON with/with/IN/O seven/seven/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ./././O
These/these/DT/O goals/goal/NNS/O helped/help/VBD/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION secure/secure/VB/O a/a/DT/O seventh-place/seventh-place/JJ/O finish/finish/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O highest/highest/JJS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O history/history/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O confirmed/confirm/VBD/O their/they/PRP$/O qualification/qualification/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O newly/newly/RB/O formed/form/VBN/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Europa/Europa/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O following/follow/VBG/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
2009/2009/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 10/10/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 13/13/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON signed/sign/VBD/O a/a/DT/O contract/contract/NN/O extension/extension/NN/O to/to/TO/O remain/remain/VB/O with/with/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION through/through/IN/O 2013/2013/CD/DATE ./././O
On/on/IN/O August/August/NNP/DATE 20/20/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O European/european/JJ/MISC competition/competition/NN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O newly/newly/RB/O formed/form/VBN/O Europa/Europa/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O netting/net/VBG/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Amkar/Amkar/NNP/ORGANIZATION Perm/Perm/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O play-off/play-off/JJ/O round/round/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE 30/30/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Gazzetta/Gazzetta/NNP/LOCATION dello/dello/NNP/O Sport/Sport/NNP/O named/name/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON as/as/IN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O top/top/JJ/O eleven/eleven/NNS/NUMBER Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION players/player/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O January/January/NNP/DATE 17/17/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON suffered/suffer/VBD/O a/a/DT/O suspected/suspect/VBN/O cruciate/cruciate/JJ/O knee/knee/NN/O ligament/ligament/NN/O injury/injury/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O defeat/defeat/VB/O to/to/TO/O Blackburn/Blackburn/NNP/ORGANIZATION Rovers/Rovers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O March/March/NNP/DATE 11/11/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON returned/return/VBD/O ,/,/,/O coming/come/VBG/O on/on/IN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE last/last/JJ/DATE minute/minute/NN/DATE of/of/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O loss/loss/NN/O away/away/RB/O to/to/TO/O Juventus/Juventus/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O then/then/RB/O completed/complete/VBD/O 72/72/CD/DURATION minutes/minute/NNS/NUMBER of/of/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O away/away/RB/O loss/loss/NN/O to/to/TO/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O league/league/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O March/March/NNP/DATE 18/18/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON came/come/VBD/O off/off/RP/O the/the/DT/O bench/bench/NN/O against/against/IN/O Juventus/Juventus/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O second-leg/second-leg/NN/O ,/,/,/O last-16/last-16/JJ/O tie/tie/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Europa/Europa/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O winner/winner/NN/O on/on/IN/O a/a/DT/O long/long/JJ/O chip/chip/NN/O shot/shot/NN/O ./././O
Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O game/game/NN/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER and/and/CC/O this/this/DT/O game/game/NN/O resulted/result/VBD/O in/in/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/LOCATION winning/win/VBG/O an/a/DT/O award/award/NN/O ,/,/,/O as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON receiving/receive/VBG/O an/a/DT/O award/award/NN/O for/for/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O `/`/``/O Wonderful/wonderful/JJ/O '/'/''/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O Quote/Quote/NNP/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O commentator/commentator/NN/O on/on/IN/O ESPN/ESPN/NNP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O goal/goal/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O Guardian/Guardian/NNP/MISC suggested/suggest/VBD/O that/that/IN/O the/the/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O ``/``/``/O might/might/MD/O become/become/VB/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O famous/famous/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O history/history/NN/O ''/''/''/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O May/May/NNP/DATE 12/12/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON replaced/replace/VBD/O Bobby/Bobby/NNP/PERSON Zamora/Zamora/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 55th/55th/JJ/ORDINAL minute/minute/NN/DURATION of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Europa/Europa/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION Final/Final/NNP/O ,/,/,/O thus/thus/RB/O making/make/VBG/O history/history/NN/O in/in/IN/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL ever/ever/RB/O American/american/JJ/MISC to/to/TO/O appear/appear/VB/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O major/major/JJ/O European/european/JJ/LOCATION final/final/JJ/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O end/end/NN/O ,/,/,/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION lost/lose/VBD/O the/the/DT/O match/match/NN/O ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O Atlético/Atlético/NNP/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O Diego/Diego/NNP/PERSON Forlán/Forlán/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 116th/116th/JJ/DATE minute/minute/NN/DATE of/of/IN/O extra/extra/JJ/O time/time/NN/O ,/,/,/O giving/give/VBG/O Atlético/Atlético/NNP/ORGANIZATION a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O performances/performance/NNS/O throughout/throughout/IN/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 10/10/CD/NUMBER earned/earn/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O designation/designation/NN/O of/of/IN/O Most/most/JJS/O Valuable/Valuable/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O among/among/IN/O Americans/Americans/NNPS/MISC in/in/IN/O Europe/Europe/NNP/LOCATION by/by/IN/O SoccerOverThere.com/SoccerOverThere.com/NNP/O ,/,/,/O among/among/IN/O other/other/JJ/O sources/source/NNS/O ./././O
2010/2010/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 11/11/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON remained/remain/VBD/O a/a/DT/O regular/regular/JJ/O starter/starter/JJ/O ,/,/,/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O only/only/RB/O five/five/CD/NUMBER Americans/Americans/NNPS/MISC in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC to/to/TO/O do/do/VB/O so/so/RB/O currently/currently/RB/DATE ./././O
On/on/IN/O September/September/NNP/DATE 18/18/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O an/a/DT/O equalising/equalise/VBG/O goal/goal/NN/O on/on/IN/O 56/56/CD/DURATION minutes/minute/NNS/NUMBER with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O header/header/NN/O against/against/IN/O Blackburn/Blackburn/NNP/ORGANIZATION Rovers/Rovers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION at/at/IN/O Ewood/Ewood/NNP/LOCATION Park/Park/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER draw/draw/NN/O and/and/CC/O continue/continue/VB/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O undefeated/undefeated/JJ/O streak/streak/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Barclays/Barclays/NNP/ORGANIZATION Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O October/October/NNP/DATE 2/2/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O against/against/IN/O West/West/NNP/ORGANIZATION Ham/Ham/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION past/past/IN/DATE Robert/Robert/NNP/PERSON Green/Green/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O same/same/JJ/O keeper/keeper/NN/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O scored/score/VBN/O against/against/IN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC ./././O
He/he/PRP/O then/then/RB/O continued/continue/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O form/form/NN/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O against/against/IN/O Wigan/Wigan/NNP/ORGANIZATION Athletic/Athletic/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O October/October/NNP/DATE 30/30/CD/DATE as/as/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION ran/run/VBD/O out/out/RP/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER winners/winner/NNS/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O January/January/NNP/DATE 22/22/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O another/another/DT/O double/double/JJ/O versus/versus/CC/O Stoke/Stoke/NNP/O ,/,/,/O putting/put/VBG/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION temporarily/temporarily/RB/O out/out/IN/O of/of/IN/O relegation/relegation/NN/O contention/contention/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O March/March/NNP/DATE 19/19/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL American/american/JJ/MISC to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER 10/10/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O beating/beat/VBG/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O previous/previous/JJ/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O nine/nine/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O also/also/RB/O set/set/VBN/O while/while/IN/O at/at/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 06/06/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O and/and/CC/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 07/07/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON broke/break/VBD/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION goalscoring/goalscoring/NN/O record/record/NN/O by/by/IN/O netting/net/VBG/O twice/twice/RB/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Bolton/Bolton/NNP/PERSON on/on/IN/O April/April/NNP/DATE 27/27/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O scored/score/VBN/O a/a/DT/O total/total/NN/O of/of/IN/O 33/33/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O topping/top/VBG/O both/both/CC/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Steed/Steed/NNP/PERSON Malbranque/Malbranque/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O each/each/DT/O with/with/IN/O 32/32/CD/NUMBER ./././O
With/with/IN/O these/these/DT/O goals/goal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O for/for/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 11/11/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
At/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O end/end/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O voted/vote/VBN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION fans/fan/NNS/O and/and/CC/O his/he/PRP$/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC strikes/strike/VBZ/O meant/mean/VBN/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O leading/lead/VBG/O goalscorer/goalscorer/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O campaign/campaign/NN/O ./././O
2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON marked/mark/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O return/return/NN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL team/team/NN/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O a/a/DT/O brace/brace/VB/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O of/of/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O Europa/Europa/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION play-off/play-off/NN/O clash/clash/NN/O against/against/IN/O Dnipro/Dnipro/NNP/ORGANIZATION Dnipropetrovsk/Dnipropetrovsk/NNP/ORGANIZATION at/at/IN/O Craven/Craven/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cottage/Cottage/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON ended/end/VBD/O with/with/IN/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O as/as/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION ran/run/VBD/O out/out/RP/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER winners/winner/NNS/O ,/,/,/O setting/set/VBG/O up/up/RP/O a/a/DT/O comfortable/comfortable/JJ/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O in/in/IN/O Ukraine/Ukraine/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE 5/5/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 85th/85th/JJ/ORDINAL minute/minute/NN/DURATION to/to/TO/O secure/secure/VB/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Liverpool/Liverpool/NNP/ORGANIZATION at/at/IN/O Craven/Craven/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cottage/Cottage/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
The/the/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O propelled/propel/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON to/to/TO/O become/become/VB/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O prolific/prolific/JJ/O American/american/JJ/MISC goalscorer/goalscorer/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O passing/pass/VBG/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION legend/legend/NN/O and/and/CC/O fellow/fellow/JJ/O American/american/JJ/MISC Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O fifth/fifth/JJ/ORDINAL Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O campaign/campaign/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O header/header/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Bolton/Bolton/NNP/PERSON on/on/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE 17/17/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O lifting/lift/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O side/side/NN/O six/six/CD/NUMBER points/point/NNS/O clear/clear/JJ/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O drop/drop/NN/O zone/zone/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O West/West/NNP/LOCATION London/London/NNP/LOCATION derby/derby/NN/O against/against/IN/O rivals/rival/NNS/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O Boxing/Boxing/NNP/MISC Day/Day/NNP/DURATION ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O equalizing/equalize/VBG/O goal/goal/NN/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O game/game/NN/O ended/end/VBN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER draw/draw/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O then/then/RB/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O career/career/NN/O on/on/IN/O January/January/NNP/DATE 7/7/CD/DATE against/against/IN/O Charlton/Charlton/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O FA/FA/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC Third/Third/NNP/ORDINAL Round/Round/NNP/MISC game/game/NN/O which/which/WDT/O ended/end/VBD/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 21/21/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O another/another/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O against/against/IN/O Newcastle/Newcastle/NNP/ORGANIZATION while/while/IN/O the/the/DT/O game/game/NN/O ended/end/VBN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VB/O for/for/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O sent/send/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O goal/goal/NN/O tally/tally/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION to/to/TO/O nine/nine/CD/NUMBER for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
With/with/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O against/against/IN/O Newcastle/Newcastle/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL ever/ever/RB/O American/american/JJ/MISC player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 10th/10th/JJ/ORDINAL Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O sixteenth/sixteenth/NN/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER draw/draw/NN/O against/against/IN/O former/former/JJ/O manager/manager/NN/O Roy/Roy/NNP/PERSON Hodgson/Hodgson/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O West/West/NNP/LOCATION Brom/Brom/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O February/February/NNP/DATE 1/1/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ./././O
This/this/DT/O recent/recent/JJ/O run/run/NN/O of/of/IN/O good/good/JJ/O form/form/NN/O has/have/VBZ/O seen/see/VBN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON play/play/VB/O higher-up/higher-up/NN/O the/the/DT/O field/field/NN/O into/into/IN/O an/a/DT/O orthodox/orthodox/JJ/O striker/striker/NN/O position/position/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O ``/``/``/O assisted/assist/VBN/O ''/''/''/O another/another/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Stoke/Stoke/NNP/ORGANIZATION City/City/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O February/February/NNP/DATE 11/11/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O 28th-minute/28th-minute/JJ/O shot/shot/NN/O hit/hit/VBD/O the/the/DT/O crossbar/crossbar/NN/O and/and/CC/O was/be/VBD/O deflected/deflect/VBN/O by/by/IN/O Stoke/Stoke/NNP/O goalkeeper/goalkeeper/NNP/O Thomas/Thomas/NNP/PERSON Sørensen/Sørensen/NNP/PERSON ./././O
It/it/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O therefore/therefore/RB/O awarded/award/VBN/O as/as/IN/O an/a/DT/O own/own/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O off/off/IN/O the/the/DT/O goalie/goalie/NN/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O form/form/NN/O this/this/DT/O season/season/NN/O continued/continue/VBN/O against/against/IN/O Wolverhampton/Wolverhampton/NNP/ORGANIZATION Wanderers/Wanderers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION where/where/WRB/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O twice/twice/RB/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O for/for/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 8/8/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE the/the/DT/DATE day/day/NN/DATE before/before/IN/DATE Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O 29th/29th/JJ/DATE birthday/birthday/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION manager/manager/NN/O Martin/Martin/NNP/PERSON Jol/Jol/NNP/PERSON revealed/reveal/VBD/O that/that/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O have/have/VBP/O opened/open/VBN/O talks/talk/NNS/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O American/american/JJ/MISC over/over/IN/O a/a/DT/O new/new/JJ/O three-year/three-year/JJ/DURATION contract/contract/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O fourteenth/fourteenth/NN/ORDINAL and/and/CC/ORDINAL fifteenth/fifteenth/NN/ORDINAL Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC goals/goal/NNS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O campaign/campaign/NN/O ,/,/,/O bringing/bring/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O tally/tally/NN/O to/to/TO/O twenty-one/twenty-one/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Bolton/Bolton/NNP/ORGANIZATION Wanderers/Wanderers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O April/April/NNP/DATE 7/7/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL a/a/DT/O free/free/JJ/O kick/kick/NN/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL a/a/DT/O header/header/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O strikes/strike/NNS/O moved/move/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON past/past/IN/DATE Louis/Louis/NNP/PERSON Saha/Saha/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O thirteen/thirteen/CD/NUMBER Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION goals/goal/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON finished/finish/VBD/O fourth/fourth/JJ/ORDINAL on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O FWA/FWA/NNP/O Footballer/footballer/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE list/list/NN/O behind/behind/IN/O winner/winner/NN/O Robin/Robin/NNP/PERSON van/van/NNP/PERSON Persie/Persie/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION pair/pair/NN/O Wayne/Wayne/NNP/PERSON Rooney/Rooney/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Paul/Paul/NNP/PERSON Scholes/Scholes/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O came/come/VBD/O in/in/IN/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/ORDINAL third/third/JJ/ORDINAL ,/,/,/O respectively/respectively/RB/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL American/american/JJ/MISC to/to/TO/O reach/reach/VB/O the/the/DT/O milestone/milestone/NN/O of/of/IN/O fifty/fifty/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O free-kick/free-kick/NN/O against/against/IN/O Sunderland/Sunderland/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O last/last/JJ/O home/home/NN/O game/game/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 7/7/CD/DATE June/June/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O voted/vote/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION `/`/``/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Season/season/NN/O '/'/''/O by/by/IN/O fans/fan/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL straight/straight/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 31/31/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION confirmed/confirm/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O transfer/transfer/NN/O to/to/TO/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/Hotspur/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/Hotspur/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 31/31/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON joined/join/VBD/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/Hotspur/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O a/a/DT/O three-year/three-year/JJ/DURATION contract/contract/NN/O for/for/IN/O a/a/DT/O fee/fee/NN/O believed/believe/VBN/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O region/region/NN/O of/of/IN/O #/#/#/MONEY 6/6/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O $/$/$/MONEY 9.5/9.5/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O deal/deal/NN/O made/make/VBD/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON the/the/DT/O highest/highest/JJS/O salaried/salaried/JJ/O US/US/NNP/LOCATION football/football/NN/O player/player/NN/O of/of/IN/O all/all/DT/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
With/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O 23/23/CD/NUMBER shirt/shirt/NN/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O wore/wear/VBD/O at/at/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O number/number/NN/O 8/8/CD/NUMBER that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O usually/usually/RB/O wears/wear/VBZ/O on/on/IN/O international/international/JJ/O duty/duty/NN/O unavailable/unavailable/JJ/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O opted/opt/VBD/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O number/number/NN/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER jersey/jersey/NN/O which/which/WDT/O he/he/PRP/O wore/wear/VBD/O at/at/IN/O Furman/Furman/NNP/ORGANIZATION University/University/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O game-winning/game-winning/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O for/for/IN/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
It/it/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL time/time/NN/O in/in/IN/O 23/23/CD/DURATION years/year/NNS/NUMBER that/that/WDT/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION had/have/VBD/O won/win/VBN/O at/at/IN/O Old/Old/NNP/LOCATION Trafford/Trafford/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O for/for/IN/O Spurs/Spurs/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 39th/39th/JJ/ORDINAL minute/minute/NN/DURATION in/in/IN/O an/a/DT/O away/away/RB/O game/game/NN/O at/at/IN/O Southampton/Southampton/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O October/October/NNP/DATE ./././O
Dempsay/dempsay/JJ/PERSON 3rd/3rd/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O was/be/VBD/O scored/score/VBN/O against/against/IN/O Reading/read/VBG/O on/on/IN/O New/New/NNP/DATE Year/Year/NNP/DATE 's/'s/POS/DATE day/day/NN/DATE 2013/2013/CD/DATE to/to/TO/O help/help/VB/O his/he/PRP$/O Spurs/Spurs/NNP/ORGANIZATION side/side/NN/O win/win/VB/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O FA/FA/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC 3rd/3rd/JJ/ORDINAL round/round/NN/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O double/double/JJ/O against/against/IN/O Coventry/Coventry/NNP/O ./././O
International/International/NNP/O career/career/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON first/first/RB/ORDINAL played/play/VBD/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION national/national/JJ/O team/team/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2003/2003/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/ORGANIZATION Youth/Youth/NNP/ORGANIZATION Championship/Championship/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION Arab/Arab/NNP/LOCATION Emirates/Emirates/NNPS/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL appearance/appearance/NN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O senior/senior/JJ/O team/team/NN/O on/on/IN/O November/November/NNP/DATE 17/17/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2004/2004/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O against/against/IN/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O frequently/frequently/RB/O lined/line/VBN/O up/up/RP/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O striker/striker/NN/O due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O his/he/PRP$/O scoring/score/VBG/O threat/threat/NN/O and/and/CC/O aerial/aerial/JJ/O ability/ability/NN/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O his/he/PRP$/O preferred/preferred/JJ/O and/and/CC/O more/more/RBR/O normal/normal/JJ/O role/role/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O off/off/IN/O the/the/DT/O striker/striker/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O highest/highest/JJS/O individual/individual/JJ/O honor/honor/NN/O in/in/IN/O football/football/NN/O in/in/IN/O America/America/NNP/LOCATION when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O named/name/VBN/O Honda/Honda/NNP/ORGANIZATION Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE for/for/IN/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O beating/beat/VBG/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION teammates/teammate/NNS/O Kasey/Kasey/NNP/PERSON Keller/Keller/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O poll/poll/NN/O of/of/IN/O sportswriters/sportswriter/NNS/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON received/receive/VBD/O 237/237/CD/NUMBER points/point/NNS/O in/in/IN/O voting/voting/NN/O by/by/IN/O 207/207/CD/NUMBER sports/sport/NNS/O journalists/journalist/NNS/O to/to/TO/O claim/claim/VB/O the/the/DT/O award/award/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O May/May/NNP/DATE 2/2/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O named/name/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION roster/roster/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC in/in/IN/O Germany/Germany/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O American/american/JJ/MISC player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O tournament/tournament/NN/O with/with/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O equalizing/equalize/VBG/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Americans/Americans/NNPS/MISC '/'/POS/O eventual/eventual/JJ/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER loss/loss/NN/O to/to/TO/O Ghana/Ghana/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION '/'/POS/O opening/opening/NN/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC qualifier/qualifier/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON recorded/record/VBD/O the/the/DT/O then/then/RB/O fastest/fastest/JJS/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION qualifying/qualify/VBG/O history/history/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O chest/chest/NN/O trap/trap/NN/O and/and/CC/O sliding/slide/VBG/O shot/shot/NN/O 53/53/CD/DURATION seconds/seconds/NNS/NUMBER into/into/IN/O a/a/DT/O 8/8/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O of/of/IN/O Barbados/Barbados/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
But/but/CC/O thereafter/thereafter/RB/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON experienced/experience/VBD/O a/a/DT/O dip/dip/NN/O in/in/IN/O form/form/NN/O leading/lead/VBG/O some/some/DT/O to/to/TO/O doubt/doubt/VB/O his/he/PRP$/O first-choice/first-choice/JJ/O status/status/NN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O national/national/JJ/O team/team/NN/O ./././O
However/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON turned/turn/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O fortunes/fortune/NNS/O around/around/IN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Confederations/Confederations/NNPS/O Cup/Cup/NNP/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O final/final/JJ/O group/group/NN/O stage/stage/NN/O match/match/NN/O against/against/IN/O Egypt/Egypt/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O trademark/trademark/NN/O diving/diving/NN/O header/header/NN/O off/off/IN/O a/a/DT/O Jonathan/Jonathan/NNP/PERSON Spector/Spector/NNP/PERSON cross/cross/VB/O ,/,/,/O making/make/VBG/O the/the/DT/O final/final/JJ/O result/result/NN/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER ./././O
This/this/DT/O ,/,/,/O combined/combine/VBN/O with/with/IN/O Brazil/Brazil/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O against/against/IN/O Italy/Italy/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O other/other/JJ/O group/group/NN/O match/match/NN/O that/that/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O being/be/VBG/O played/play/VBN/O simultaneously/simultaneously/RB/O ,/,/,/O put/put/VBD/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION through/through/IN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O semifinals/semifinal/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O semi-final/semi-final/JJ/O match/match/NN/O against/against/IN/O Spain/Spain/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O to/to/TO/O put/put/VB/O the/the/DT/O USA/USA/NNP/LOCATION up/up/IN/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER to/to/TO/O send/send/VB/O them/they/PRP/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O finals/final/NNS/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O named/name/VBN/O the/the/DT/O Man/man/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Match/Match/NNP/O for/for/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O performance/performance/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL straight/straight/JJ/O game/game/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Confederations/Confederations/NNPS/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC Final/Final/NNP/MISC against/against/IN/O Brazil/Brazil/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O redirecting/redirect/VBG/O a/a/DT/O similar/similar/JJ/O cross/cross/NN/O from/from/IN/O Spector/Spector/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 10th/10th/JJ/ORDINAL minute/minute/NN/DURATION to/to/TO/O open/open/VB/O the/the/DT/O scoring/score/VBG/O ./././O
Following/follow/VBG/O the/the/DT/O loss/loss/NN/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O awarded/award/VBN/O the/the/DT/O Bronze/bronze/NN/O Ball/Ball/NNP/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O tournament/tournament/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O 3rd/3rd/JJ/ORDINAL best/best/JJS/O performer/performer/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O ended/end/VBD/O the/the/DT/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC qualifying/qualify/VBG/O campaign/campaign/NN/O tied/tie/VBN/O with/with/IN/O Landon/Landon/NNP/PERSON Donovan/Donovan/NNP/PERSON as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL top/top/JJ/O scorer/scorer/NN/O ,/,/,/O behind/behind/IN/O Jozy/Jozy/NNP/PERSON Altidore/Altidore/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O five/five/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O thirteen/thirteen/CD/NUMBER matches/match/NNS/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O June/June/NNP/DATE 12/12/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL American/american/JJ/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O after/after/IN/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER in/in/IN/O more/more/JJR/O than/than/IN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER World/world/NN/MISC Cup/cup/NN/MISC when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O equalizer/equalizer/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O against/against/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Americans/Americans/NNPS/MISC '/'/POS/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL game/game/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC after/after/IN/O the/the/DT/O West/West/NNP/LOCATION Ham/Ham/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION goalkeeper/goalkeeper/NN/O Robert/Robert/NNP/PERSON Green/Green/NNP/PERSON made/make/VBD/O a/a/DT/O major/major/JJ/O error/error/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O disallowed/disallow/VBN/O goal/goal/NN/O later/later/RB/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O tournament/tournament/NN/O vs./vs./FW/O Algeria/Algeria/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O group/group/NN/O stage/stage/NN/O was/be/VBD/O very/very/RB/O controversial/controversial/JJ/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O called/call/VBN/O offside/offside/NN/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O the/the/DT/O replay/replay/NN/O showed/show/VBD/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O most/most/RBS/O likely/likely/JJ/O not/not/RB/O offside/offside/NN/O ./././O
Despite/despite/IN/O this/this/DT/O call/call/NN/O ,/,/,/O his/he/PRP$/O teammate/teammate/NN/O Landon/Landon/NNP/PERSON Donovan/Donovan/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O late/late/JJ/O stoppage/stoppage/NN/O time/time/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O the/the/DT/O game/game/NN/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER ./././O
During/during/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE Gold/Gold/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON played/play/VBD/O a/a/DT/O key/key/JJ/O role/role/NN/O in/in/IN/O helping/help/VBG/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION advance/advance/NN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O finals/final/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O group/group/NN/O stages/stage/NNS/O he/he/PRP/O recorded/record/VBD/O a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Canada/Canada/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O quarterfinals/quarterfinal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON also/also/RB/O scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O semi-finals/semi-final/NNS/O against/against/IN/O Panama/Panama/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O had/have/VBD/O shockingly/shockingly/RB/O defeated/defeat/VBN/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O group/group/NN/O stage/stage/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O to/to/TO/O advance/advance/VB/O the/the/DT/O Americans/Americans/NNPS/MISC to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O final/final/JJ/O ./././O
With/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O sliding/slide/VBG/O touch/touch/NN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON redirected/redirect/VBD/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION Midfielder/Midfielder/NNP/O Landon/Landon/NNP/PERSON Donovan/Donovan/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O pass/pass/NN/O into/into/IN/O the/the/DT/O net/net/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O February/February/NNP/DATE 29/29/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O lone/lone/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O an/a/DT/O international/international/JJ/O friendly/friendly/JJ/O against/against/IN/O four/four/CD/NUMBER time/time/NN/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC Champion/Champion/NNP/O Italy/Italy/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Jozy/Jozy/NNP/PERSON Altidore/Altidore/NNP/PERSON assisted/assist/VBN/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O ,/,/,/O allowing/allow/VBG/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL time/time/NN/O against/against/IN/O Italy/Italy/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O eleven/eleven/NNS/NUMBER games/game/NNS/O played/play/VBD/O since/since/IN/O 1934/1934/CD/DATE ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON broke/break/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O own/own/JJ/O fastest-goal/fastest-goal/JJ/O record/record/NN/O in/in/IN/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC Qualifying/Qualifying/NNP/O on/on/IN/O September/September/NNP/DATE 7/7/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O just/just/RB/O 39/39/CD/DURATION seconds/seconds/NNS/NUMBER into/into/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O against/against/IN/O Jamaica/Jamaica/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O Kingston/Kingston/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
During/during/IN/O a/a/DT/O qualifying/qualify/VBG/O match/match/NN/O against/against/IN/O Guatemala/Guatemala/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O October/October/NNP/DATE 16/16/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 29th/29th/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/ORDINAL 30th/30th/JJ/ORDINAL international/international/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O ,/,/,/O tying/tie/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O with/with/IN/O Brian/Brian/NNP/PERSON McBride/McBride/NNP/PERSON for/for/IN/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL most/most/RBS/O goals/goal/NNS/O scored/score/VBD/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/ORGANIZATION National/National/NNP/ORGANIZATION Team/Team/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
The/the/DT/O goals/goal/NNS/O helped/help/VBD/O the/the/DT/O U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION advance/advance/NN/O into/into/IN/O the/the/DT/O final/final/JJ/O qualifying/qualify/VBG/O stage/stage/NN/O for/for/IN/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC 2014/2014/CD/DATE ./././O
International/International/NNP/O goals/goal/NNS/O ./././O
Playing/play/VBG/O style/style/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O versatile/versatile/JJ/O right/right/NN/O footed/foot/VBD/O withdrawn/withdraw/VBN/O forward/forward/RB/O ,/,/,/O normally/normally/RB/O playing/play/VBG/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O left/left/NN/O or/or/CC/O right/right/NN/O for/for/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION ,/,/,/O at/at/IN/O times/time/NNS/O shooting/shoot/VBG/O from/from/IN/O long/long/JJ/O distances/distance/NNS/O and/and/CC/O even/even/RB/O scoring/score/VBG/O at/at/IN/O club/club/NN/O level/level/NN/O from/from/IN/O said/say/VBD/O long/long/JJ/O range/range/NN/O shots/shot/NNS/O ./././O
However/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O also/also/RB/O proven/prove/VBN/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O more/more/JJR/O of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O threat/threat/NN/O the/the/DT/O closer/closer/JJR/O to/to/TO/O goal/goal/NN/O he/he/PRP/O gets/get/VBZ/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O goals/goal/NNS/O against/against/IN/O Egypt/Egypt/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Spain/Spain/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Confederations/Confederations/NNPS/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC came/come/VBD/O almost/almost/RB/O immediately/immediately/RB/O after/after/IN/O being/be/VBG/O moved/move/VBN/O to/to/TO/O forward/forward/RB/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O substitution/substitution/NN/O from/from/IN/O Bob/Bob/NNP/PERSON Bradley/Bradley/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Known/know/VBN/O for/for/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O toughness/toughness/NN/O and/and/CC/O resilience/resilience/NN/O ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON played/play/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER games/game/NNS/O for/for/IN/O New/New/NNP/LOCATION England/England/NNP/LOCATION Revolution/Revolution/NNP/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O broken/broken/JJ/O jaw/jaw/NN/O in/in/IN/O 2004/2004/CD/DATE before/before/IN/DATE the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O trainer/trainer/NN/O diagnosed/diagnose/VBD/O it/it/PRP/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O upon/upon/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O return/return/NN/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O played/play/VBD/O through/through/IN/O the/the/DT/O pain/pain/NN/O of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O sprained/sprain/VBN/O ankle/ankle/NN/O ./././O
Despite/despite/IN/O usually/usually/RB/O playing/play/VBG/O in/in/IN/O wide/wide/JJ/O positions/position/NNS/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O frequently/frequently/RB/O scores/score/NNS/O close-range/close-range/JJ/O goals/goal/NNS/O and/and/CC/O has/have/VBZ/O scored/score/VBN/O repeatedly/repeatedly/RB/O with/with/IN/O diving/diving/JJ/O headers/header/NNS/O in/in/IN/O crowded/crowded/JJ/O situations/situation/NNS/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O tenacity/tenacity/NN/O in/in/IN/O midfield/midfield/JJ/LOCATION combined/combine/VBN/O with/with/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O audacious/audacious/JJ/O close/close/JJ/O control/control/NN/O dribbling/dribble/VBG/O skills/skill/NNS/O frequently/frequently/RB/O results/result/VBZ/O in/in/IN/O opponents/opponent/NNS/O fouling/foul/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON has/have/VBZ/O gained/gain/VBN/O a/a/DT/O reputation/reputation/NN/O for/for/IN/O fierce/fierce/JJ/O play/play/NN/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O has/have/VBZ/O on/on/IN/O several/several/JJ/O occasions/occasion/NNS/O lapsed/lapse/VBN/O into/into/IN/O violent/violent/JJ/O conduct/conduct/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O suspended/suspend/VBN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O New/New/NNP/O England/England/NNP/O Revolution/Revolution/NNP/O for/for/IN/O two/two/CD/DATE weeks/week/NNS/DATE in/in/IN/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE for/for/IN/O a/a/DT/O fist/fist/NN/O fight/fight/NN/O with/with/IN/O teammate/teammate/NN/O Joe/Joe/NNP/PERSON Franchino/Franchino/NNP/PERSON during/during/IN/O a/a/DT/O practice/practice/NN/O game/game/NN/O and/and/CC/O was/be/VBD/O twice/twice/RB/O suspended/suspend/VBN/O by/by/IN/O MLS/ml/NN/ORGANIZATION during/during/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE season/season/NN/O for/for/IN/O violent/violent/JJ/O conduct/conduct/NN/O against/against/IN/O opponents/opponent/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O an/a/DT/O elbow/elbow/NN/O that/that/WDT/O broke/break/VBD/O the/the/DT/O jaw/jaw/NN/O of/of/IN/O national/national/JJ/O teammate/teammate/NN/O Jimmy/Jimmy/NNP/PERSON Conrad/Conrad/NNP/PERSON ./././O
In/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O similar/similar/JJ/O incident/incident/NN/O with/with/IN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON accidentally/accidentally/RB/O broke/break/VBD/O the/the/DT/O cheekbone/cheekbone/NN/O of/of/IN/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION defender/defender/NN/O John/John/NNP/PERSON Terry/Terry/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O an/a/DT/O aerial/aerial/JJ/O challenge/challenge/NN/O but/but/CC/O was/be/VBD/O not/not/RB/O penalized/penalize/VBN/O ./././O
A/a/DT/O further/further/JJ/O similar/similar/JJ/O incident/incident/NN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O December/December/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O took/take/VBD/O place/place/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O match/match/NN/O against/against/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON accidentally/accidentally/RB/O elbowing/elbow/VBG/O opponent/opponent/NN/O Phil/Phil/NNP/PERSON Jones/Jones/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O side/side/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O head/head/NN/O and/and/CC/O causing/cause/VBG/O a/a/DT/O suspected/suspect/VBN/O broken/broken/JJ/O cheekbone/cheekbone/NN/O ./././O
Again/again/RB/O no/no/DT/O action/action/NN/O was/be/VBD/O taken/take/VBN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O referee/referee/NN/O ./././O
Career/Career/NNP/O statistics/statistics/NNS/O ./././O
Club/Club/NNP/O ./././O
As/as/IN/O of/of/IN/O 23:00/23:00/CD/TIME ,/,/,/TIME 24/24/CD/TIME December/December/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O UTC/utc/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
International/International/NNP/O ./././O
As/as/IN/O of/of/IN/O 17/17/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ./././O
Honors/honor/NNS/O ./././O
Club/Club/NNP/O ./././O
New/New/NNP/O England/England/NNP/O Revolution/Revolution/NNP/O ./././O
Runner-up/runner-up/NN/O ./././O
MLS/MLS/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 2/2/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE ./././O
MLS/MLS/NNP/O Supporters/supporter/NNS/O '/'/POS/O Shield/Shield/NNP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 1/1/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE ./././O
Fulham/Fulham/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Runner-up/runner-up/NN/O ./././O
UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Europa/Europa/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 1/1/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 10/10/CD/NUMBER ./././O
International/International/NNP/O ./././O
United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION ./././O
Winner/winner/NN/O ./././O
CONCACAF/CONCACAF/NNP/MISC Gold/Gold/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 2/2/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2007/2007/CD/DATE ./././O
Runner-up/runner-up/NN/O ./././O
FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Confederations/Confederations/NNPS/O Cup/Cup/NNP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 1/1/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE ./././O
Individual/individual/NN/O ./././O
MLS/MLS/NNP/O Rookie/Rookie/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE Award/award/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2004/2004/CD/DATE ./././O
Honda/Honda/NNP/ORGANIZATION Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ./././O
MLS/MLS/NNP/O Best/best/JJS/O XI/xi/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE ./././O
U.S./U.S./NNP/LOCATION Soccer/Soccer/NNP/O Athlete/Athlete/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ./././O
FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Confederations/Confederations/NNPS/O Cup/Cup/NNP/O Bronze/bronze/NN/O Ball/Ball/NNP/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 1/1/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE ./././O
Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Season/season/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O :/:/:/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 11/11/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER ./././O
Premiership/Premiership/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Season/season/NN/O :/:/:/O 4th/4th/JJ/ORDINAL place/place/NN/O in/in/IN/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER ./././O
Personal/personal/JJ/O life/life/NN/O ./././O
Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON is/be/VBZ/O married/marry/VBN/O to/to/TO/O Bethany/Bethany/NNP/PERSON Keegan/Keegan/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON ./././O
They/they/PRP/O have/have/VBP/O a/a/DT/O daughter/daughter/NN/O named/name/VBN/O Elyse/Elyse/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O a/a/DT/O son/son/NN/O named/name/VBN/O Jackson/Jackson/NNP/PERSON ./././O
-LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O citation/citation/NN/O needed/need/VBN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O In/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O spare/spare/JJ/O time/time/NN/O he/he/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O fisherman/fisherman/NN/O ./././O
Music/music/NN/O ./././O
One/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O passions/passion/NNS/O outside/outside/IN/O of/of/IN/O soccer/soccer/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O hip/hip/NN/O hop/hop/NN/O music/music/NN/O ./././O
Using/use/VBG/O the/the/DT/O alias/alias/NNS/O ``/``/``/O Deuce/Deuce/NNP/O ,/,/,/O ''/''/''/O he/he/PRP/O ,/,/,/O along/along/IN/O with/with/IN/O fellow/fellow/JJ/O Texas/Texas/NNP/LOCATION rappers/rapper/NNS/O XO/XO/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O late/late/JJ/O Houston/Houston/NNP/LOCATION rapper/rapper/NNP/O Big/Big/NNP/O Hawk/Hawk/NNP/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O Screwed/screw/VBN/O Up/up/IN/O Click/click/NN/O ,/,/,/O are/be/VBP/O featured/feature/VBN/O rapping/rap/VBG/O the/the/DT/O song/song/NN/O ``/``/``/O Do/do/VBP/O n't/not/RB/O Tread/tread/VB/O ''/''/''/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O Nike/Nike/NNP/ORGANIZATION football/football/NN/O advertising/advertising/NN/O campaign/campaign/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O intention/intention/NN/O to/to/TO/O showcase/showcase/NN/O both/both/CC/O the/the/DT/O sport/sport/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O working-class/working-class/JJ/O roots/root/NNS/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O United/United/NNP/LOCATION States/States/NNPS/LOCATION team/team/NN/O ahead/ahead/RB/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC ./././O
The/the/DT/O song/song/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O video/video/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O dedicated/dedicate/VBN/O to/to/TO/O his/he/PRP$/O sister/sister/NN/O Jennifer/Jennifer/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O ,/,/,/O at/at/IN/O age/age/NN/O sixteen/sixteen/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O was/be/VBD/O suddenly/suddenly/RB/O struck/strike/VBN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O fatal/fatal/JJ/O brain/brain/NN/O aneurysm/aneurysm/NN/O ./././O
At/at/IN/O Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O request/request/NN/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O video/video/NN/O ends/end/VBZ/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O shot/shot/NN/O of/of/IN/O him/he/PRP/O placing/place/VBG/O a/a/DT/O flower/flower/NN/O at/at/IN/O her/she/PRP$/O grave/grave/NN/O ./././O
Notes/note/NNS/O ./././O
References/reference/NNS/O ./././O
External/external/JJ/O links/link/NNS/O ./././O
Profile/Profile/NNP/O at/at/IN/O Yanks/Yanks/NNPS/O Abroad/abroad/RB/O ./././O
Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON career/career/NN/O stats/stats/NNS/O at/at/IN/O Soccerbase/Soccerbase/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON profile/profile/NN/O Fulham/Fulham/NNP/ORGANIZATION FC/FC/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON profile/profile/NN/O Transfermarkt/Transfermarkt/NNP/O ./././O
Andrea/Andrea/NNP/PERSON Scanzi/Scanzi/NNP/PERSON La/La/NNP/O palombella/palombellum/NN/O rossa/rossa/NN/O di/di/FW/O Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON La/La/NNP/PERSON Stampa/Stampa/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O 19/19/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ./././O
Premier/Premier/NNP/O League/League/NNP/O profile/profile/NN/O ./././O
Profile/Profile/NNP/O at/at/IN/O SoccerSurfer.com/SoccerSurfer.com/NNP/O ./././O
Clint/Clint/NNP/PERSON Dempsey/Dempsey/NNP/PERSON --/--/:/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION competition/competition/NN/O record/record/NN/O ./././O