Cristiano/Cristiano/NNP/PERSON Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON Cristiano/Cristiano/NNP/PERSON Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON dos/dos/NNP/PERSON Santos/Santos/NNP/PERSON Aveiro/Aveiro/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O OIH/OIH/NNP/O ,/,/,/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O born/bear/VBN/O 5/5/CD/DATE February/February/NNP/DATE 1985/1985/CD/DATE -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O commonly/commonly/RB/O known/know/VBN/O as/as/IN/O Cristiano/Cristiano/NNP/PERSON Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/LOCATION footballer/footballer/NN/O who/who/WP/O plays/play/VBZ/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O forward/forward/RB/O for/for/IN/O Spanish/spanish/JJ/ORGANIZATION La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION club/club/NN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O captain/captain/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/MISC national/national/JJ/O team/team/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O expensive/expensive/JJ/O footballer/footballer/NN/O in/in/IN/O history/history/NN/O after/after/IN/O moving/move/VBG/O from/from/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION to/to/TO/ORGANIZATION Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O transfer/transfer/NN/O worth/worth/JJ/O #/#/#/MONEY 80/80/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O $/$/$/MONEY 93.9/93.9/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY \//\//:/O $/$/$/MONEY 131.6/131.6/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O addition/addition/NN/O ,/,/,/O his/he/PRP$/O contract/contract/NN/O with/with/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O which/which/WDT/O he/he/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O paid/pay/VBN/O $/$/$/MONEY 12/12/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY per/per/IN/O year/year/NN/DURATION ,/,/,/O makes/make/VBZ/O him/he/PRP/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O highest-paid/highest-paid/JJ/O footballers/footballer/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O his/he/PRP$/O buyout/buyout/NN/O clause/clause/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O valued/value/VBN/O at/at/IN/O $/$/$/MONEY 1/1/CD/MONEY billion/billion/CD/MONEY as/as/IN/O per/per/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O contract/contract/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON began/begin/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O career/career/NN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O youth/youth/NN/O player/player/NN/O for/for/IN/O Andorinha/Andorinha/NNP/O ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O played/play/VBD/O for/for/IN/O two/two/CD/DURATION years/year/NNS/NUMBER ,/,/,/O before/before/IN/O moving/move/VBG/O to/to/TO/O C.D./C.D./NNP/PERSON Nacional/Nacional/NNP/PERSON ./././O
In/in/IN/O 1997/1997/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O made/make/VBD/O a/a/DT/O move/move/NN/O to/to/TO/O Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/LOCATION giants/giant/NNS/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION Clube/Clube/NNP/ORGANIZATION de/de/IN/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON caught/catch/VBD/O the/the/DT/O attention/attention/NN/O of/of/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION manager/manager/NN/O Alex/Alex/NNP/PERSON Ferguson/Ferguson/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O signed/sign/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O for/for/IN/O #/#/#/MONEY 12.24/12.24/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O $/$/$/MONEY 15/15/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O 2003/2003/CD/DATE ./././O
The/the/DT/O following/follow/VBG/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON won/win/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL club/club/NN/O honor/honor/NN/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O FA/FA/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O all/all/DT/O four/four/CD/NUMBER main/main/JJ/O PFA/pfa/NN/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O FWA/fwa/NN/O awards/award/NNS/O ,/,/,/O doing/do/VBG/O so/so/RB/O in/in/IN/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE ./././O
In/in/IN/O 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Ballon/Ballon/NNP/PERSON d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O placed/place/VBD/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Ballon/Ballon/NNP/O d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O in/in/IN/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE ,/,/,/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE and/and/CC/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O awarded/award/VBN/O the/the/DT/O European/european/JJ/O Golden/Golden/NNP/O Shoe/Shoe/NNP/O in/in/IN/O both/both/DT/O 2008/2008/CD/DATE and/and/CC/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ./././O
In/in/IN/O 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O won/win/VBD/O three/three/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O four/four/CD/NUMBER main/main/JJ/O PFA/pfa/NN/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O FWA/fwa/NN/O trophies/trophy/NNS/O and/and/CC/O was/be/VBD/O named/name/VBN/O the/the/DT/O FIFPro/FIFPro/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O World/World/NNP/MISC Soccer/Soccer/NNP/MISC Player/Player/NNP/MISC of/of/IN/MISC the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O Onze/onze/NN/O d'Or/d'or/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
In/in/IN/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE and/and/CC/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O named/name/VBN/O FWA/FWA/NNP/O Footballer/Footballer/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O inaugural/inaugural/JJ/O winner/winner/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Puskás/Puskás/NNP/O Award/award/NN/O in/in/IN/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON holds/hold/VBZ/O numerous/numerous/JJ/O former/former/JJ/O and/and/CC/O current/current/JJ/DATE scoring/score/VBG/O records/record/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O records/record/NNS/O for/for/IN/O most/most/JJS/O goals/goal/NNS/O scored/score/VBD/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O season/season/NN/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O most/most/JJS/O goals/goal/NNS/O scored/score/VBD/O per/per/IN/O minute/minute/NN/DURATION in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL top/top/JJ/O European/european/JJ/MISC league/league/NN/O player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O reach/reach/VB/O 40/40/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O two/two/CD/NUMBER consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O years/year/NNS/DURATION ,/,/,/O fastest/fastest/JJS/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O reach/reach/VB/O one/one/CD/NUMBER hundred/hundred/CD/NUMBER league/league/NN/O goals/goal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O ever/ever/RB/O to/to/TO/O score/score/NN/NUMBER against/against/IN/O every/every/DT/O team/team/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON is/be/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/MISC international/international/JJ/O and/and/CC/O made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O debut/debut/NN/O against/against/IN/O Kazakhstan/Kazakhstan/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O August/August/NNP/DATE 2003/2003/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O since/since/IN/O participated/participate/VBN/O in/in/IN/O five/five/CD/NUMBER major/major/JJ/O tournaments/tournament/NNS/O ;/;/:/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Euro/Euro/NNP/O 2004/2004/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cup/Cup/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Euro/Euro/NNP/O 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cup/Cup/NNP/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Euro/Euro/NNP/O 2012/2012/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL international/international/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O opening/opening/NN/O game/game/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Euro/Euro/NNP/MISC 2004/2004/CD/DATE against/against/IN/O Greece/Greece/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O addition/addition/NN/O to/to/TO/O helping/help/VBG/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION reach/reach/VB/O the/the/DT/O final/final/JJ/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O took/take/VBD/O over/over/RP/O the/the/DT/O captaincy/captaincy/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O side/side/NN/O in/in/IN/O July/July/NNP/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE and/and/CC/O went/go/VBD/O on/on/IN/O to/to/TO/O captain/captain/VB/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O semi-finals/semi-final/NNS/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Euro/Euro/NNP/MISC 2012/2012/CD/DATE and/and/CC/O finished/finish/VBD/O the/the/DT/O competition/competition/NN/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O joint/joint/JJ/O best/best/JJS/O scorer/scorer/NN/O with/with/IN/O three/three/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 16/16/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON won/win/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 100th/100th/JJ/ORDINAL cap/cap/NN/O against/against/IN/O Northern/northern/JJ/LOCATION Ireland/Ireland/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O making/make/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL highest/highest/JJS/O capped/capped/JJ/O player/player/NN/O for/for/IN/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL youngest/youngest/JJS/O European/european/JJ/MISC to/to/TO/O reach/reach/VB/O a/a/DT/DURATION century/century/NN/DURATION of/of/IN/O international/international/JJ/O appearances/appearance/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O October/October/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL sportsperson/sportsperson/NN/O to/to/TO/O reach/reach/VB/O 50/50/CD/NUMBER million/million/CD/NUMBER followers/follower/NNS/O on/on/IN/O Facebook/Facebook/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Early/early/RB/O life/life/NN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O born/bear/VBN/O in/in/IN/O Santo/Santo/NNP/LOCATION António/António/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O neighborhood/neighborhood/NN/O of/of/IN/O Funchal/Funchal/NNP/O ,/,/,/O Madeira/Madeira/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O youngest/youngest/JJS/O child/child/NN/O of/of/IN/O Maria/Maria/NNP/PERSON Dolores/Dolores/NNP/PERSON dos/dos/NNP/PERSON Santos/Santos/NNP/PERSON Aveiro/Aveiro/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O cook/cook/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O José/José/NNP/PERSON Dinis/Dinis/NNP/PERSON Aveiro/Aveiro/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O municipal/municipal/JJ/O gardener/gardener/NN/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL given/give/VBN/O name/name/NN/O ``/``/``/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ''/''/''/O was/be/VBD/O chosen/choose/VBN/O after/after/IN/O then-U.S./then-u.s./JJ/MISC president/president/NN/O Ronald/Ronald/NNP/PERSON Reagan/Reagan/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O was/be/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O father/father/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O favorite/favorite/JJ/O actor/actor/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O one/one/CD/NUMBER older/older/JJR/O brother/brother/NN/O ,/,/,/O Hugo/Hugo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O two/two/CD/NUMBER older/older/JJR/O sisters/sister/NNS/O ,/,/,/O Elma/Elma/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Liliana/Liliana/NNP/PERSON Cátia/Cátia/NNP/PERSON ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O great-grandmother/great-grandmother/NN/O Isabel/Isabel/NNP/PERSON da/da/NNP/PERSON Piedade/Piedade/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O from/from/IN/O Cape/Cape/NNP/LOCATION Verde/Verde/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Club/Club/NNP/O career/career/NN/O Early/early/JJ/O career/career/NN/O At/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O age/age/NN/O of/of/IN/O eight/eight/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON played/play/VBD/O for/for/IN/O amateur/amateur/JJ/O team/team/NN/O Andorinha/andorinha/NN/PERSON ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O his/he/PRP$/O father/father/NN/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O kit/kit/NN/O man/man/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O 1995/1995/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON signed/sign/VBD/O with/with/IN/O local/local/JJ/O club/club/NN/O Nacional/Nacional/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O a/a/DT/O title-winning/title-winning/JJ/O campaign/campaign/NN/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O went/go/VBD/O on/on/IN/O a/a/DT/O three-day/three-day/JJ/DURATION trial/trial/NN/O with/with/IN/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION CP/CP/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O subsequently/subsequently/RB/O signed/sign/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O for/for/IN/O an/a/DT/O undisclosed/undisclosed/JJ/O sum/sum/NN/O ./././O
Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION Clube/Clube/NNP/ORGANIZATION de/de/IN/ORGANIZATION Portugal/Portugal/NNP/ORGANIZATION Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/ORGANIZATION joined/join/VBD/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O other/other/JJ/O youth/youth/NN/O players/player/NNS/O who/who/WP/O trained/train/VBD/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Academia/Academia/NNP/ORGANIZATION Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O football/football/NN/O academy/academy/NN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O Alcochete/Alcochete/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O player/player/NN/O ever/ever/RB/O to/to/TO/O play/play/VB/O for/for/IN/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O under-16/under-16/NN/O ,/,/,/O under-17/under-17/NN/O ,/,/,/O under-18/under-18/NN/O ,/,/,/O B-team/b-team/NN/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL team/team/NN/O ,/,/,/O all/all/DT/O within/within/IN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O league/league/NN/O debut/debut/NN/O on/on/IN/O 7/7/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE 2002/2002/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION CP/CP/NNP/ORGANIZATION won/win/VBD/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER against/against/IN/O Moreirense/Moreirense/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O while/while/IN/O featuring/feature/VBG/O for/for/IN/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2002/2002/CD/DATE European/european/JJ/MISC Under-17/under-17/JJ/MISC Championship/Championship/NNP/MISC ./././O
At/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O age/age/NN/O of/of/IN/O 15/15/CD/NUMBER Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O diagnosed/diagnose/VBN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O racing/racing/NN/O heart/heart/NN/O ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O condition/condition/NN/O that/that/WDT/O might/might/MD/O have/have/VB/O forced/force/VBN/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O give/give/VB/O up/up/RP/O playing/play/VBG/O football/football/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/O staff/staff/NN/O were/be/VBD/O made/make/VBN/O aware/aware/JJ/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O condition/condition/NN/O and/and/CC/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O mother/mother/NN/O gave/give/VBD/O her/she/PRP$/O authorisation/authorisation/NN/O for/for/IN/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O go/go/VB/O into/into/IN/O hospital/hospital/NN/O ./././O
While/while/IN/O there/there/RB/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O an/a/DT/O operation/operation/NN/O in/in/IN/O which/which/WDT/O a/a/DT/O laser/laser/NN/O was/be/VBD/O used/use/VBN/O to/to/TO/O cauterise/cauterise/VB/O the/the/DT/O area/area/NN/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O heart/heart/NN/O that/that/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O causing/cause/VBG/O the/the/DT/O problem/problem/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O surgery/surgery/NN/O took/take/VBD/O place/place/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O morning/morning/NN/TIME and/and/CC/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O discharged/discharge/VBN/O from/from/IN/O hospital/hospital/NN/O by/by/IN/O the/the/DT/O end/end/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O afternoon/afternoon/NN/TIME ;/;/:/O he/he/PRP/O resumed/resume/VBD/O training/training/NN/O only/only/RB/O a/a/DT/DATE few/few/JJ/DATE days/day/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE ./././O
In/in/IN/O November/November/NNP/DATE 2002/2002/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O invited/invite/VBN/O to/to/TO/O Arsenal/Arsenal/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O training/training/NN/O ground/ground/NN/O ,/,/,/O London/London/NNP/LOCATION Colney/Colney/NNP/LOCATION to/to/TO/O meet/meet/VB/O manager/manager/NN/O Arsène/Arsène/NNP/PERSON Wenger/Wenger/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O his/he/PRP$/O coaching/coaching/NN/O staff/staff/NN/O ./././O
Wenger/Wenger/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O was/be/VBD/O interested/interested/JJ/O in/in/IN/O signing/sign/VBG/O the/the/DT/O midfielder/midfielder/NN/O had/have/VBD/O arranged/arrange/VBN/O to/to/TO/O meet/meet/VB/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O representatives/representative/NNS/O ,/,/,/O Formation/formation/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O who/who/WP/O suggested/suggest/VBD/O the/the/DT/O player/player/NN/O originally/originally/RB/O to/to/TO/O Gérard/Gérard/NNP/PERSON Houllier/Houllier/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O then/then/RB/O Liverpool/Liverpool/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O manager/manager/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DURATION subsequent/subsequent/JJ/DURATION months/month/NNS/DURATION to/to/TO/O discuss/discuss/VB/O a/a/DT/O transfer/transfer/NN/O arrangement/arrangement/NN/O ./././O
However/however/RB/O he/he/PRP/O came/come/VBD/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O attention/attention/NN/O of/of/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION manager/manager/NN/O Alex/Alex/NNP/PERSON Ferguson/Ferguson/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE summer/summer/NN/DATE of/of/IN/DATE 2003/2003/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O when/when/WRB/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION defeated/defeat/VBD/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O inauguration/inauguration/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Estádio/Estádio/NNP/O José/José/NNP/O Alvalade/Alvalade/NNP/O in/in/IN/O Lisbon/Lisbon/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O performance/performance/NN/O impressed/impress/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION players/player/NNS/O ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O urged/urge/VBD/O Ferguson/Ferguson/NNP/PERSON to/to/TO/O sign/sign/VB/O him/he/PRP/O ./././O
Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 2003/2003/CD/DATE --/--/:/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O first-ever/first-ever/JJ/O Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/LOCATION player/player/NN/O when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O signed/sign/VBD/O for/for/IN/O $/$/$/MONEY 15/15/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O #/#/#/MONEY 12.24/12.24/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O after/after/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2002/2002/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 03/03/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O requested/request/VBD/O the/the/DT/O number/number/NN/O 28/28/CD/NUMBER -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O his/he/PRP$/O number/number/NN/O at/at/IN/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O he/he/PRP/O did/do/VBD/O not/not/RB/O want/want/VB/O the/the/DT/O pressure/pressure/NN/O of/of/IN/O living/live/VBG/O up/up/RP/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O expectation/expectation/NN/O linked/link/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O number/number/NN/O 7/7/CD/NUMBER shirt/shirt/NN/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O had/have/VBD/O previously/previously/RB/DATE been/be/VBN/O worn/worn/JJ/O by/by/IN/O players/player/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O George/George/NNP/PERSON Best/best/JJS/PERSON ,/,/,/O Bryan/Bryan/NNP/PERSON Robson/Robson/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Eric/Eric/NNP/PERSON Cantona/Cantona/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O David/David/NNP/PERSON Beckham/Beckham/NNP/PERSON ./././O
``/``/``/O After/after/IN/O I/I/PRP/O joined/join/VBD/O ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O manager/manager/NN/O asked/ask/VBD/O me/I/PRP/O what/what/WP/O number/number/NN/O I/I/PRP/O 'd/would/MD/O like/like/VB/O ./././O
I/I/PRP/O said/say/VBD/O 28/28/CD/NUMBER ./././O
But/but/CC/O Ferguson/Ferguson/NNP/PERSON said/say/VBD/O `/`/``/O No/no/UH/O ,/,/,/O you/you/PRP/O 're/be/VBP/O going/go/VBG/O to/to/TO/O have/have/VB/O No./no./NN/O 7/7/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O '/'/''/O and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O famous/famous/JJ/O shirt/shirt/NN/O was/be/VBD/O an/a/DT/O extra/extra/JJ/O source/source/NN/O of/of/IN/O motivation/motivation/NN/O ./././O
I/I/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O forced/force/VBN/O to/to/TO/O live/live/VB/O up/up/RP/O to/to/TO/O such/such/PDT/O an/a/DT/O honor/honor/NN/O ./././O ''/''/''/O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O team/team/NN/O debut/debut/NN/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O 60th-minute/60th-minute/JJ/O substitute/substitute/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Bolton/Bolton/NNP/ORGANIZATION Wanderers/Wanderers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O for/for/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O free/free/JJ/O kick/kick/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Portsmouth/Portsmouth/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 1/1/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE 2003/2003/CD/DATE ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ended/end/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O English/english/JJ/MISC football/football/NN/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O the/the/DT/O opening/opening/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER FA/FA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cup/Cup/NNP/ORGANIZATION final/final/JJ/O victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Millwall/Millwall/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 1000th/1000th/JJ/ORGANIZATION Premier/Premier/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION goal/goal/NN/O on/on/IN/O 29/29/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE 2005/2005/CD/DATE in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER loss/loss/NN/O to/to/TO/O Middlesbrough/Middlesbrough/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O ten/ten/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O fans/fan/NNS/O voted/vote/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL FIFPro/FIFPro/NNP/O Special/special/JJ/O Young/young/NN/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE award/award/NN/O in/in/IN/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O sent/send/VBN/O off/off/RP/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/LOCATION derby/derby/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O City/city/NN/O of/of/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/LOCATION Stadium/Stadium/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 14/14/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O a/a/DT/O game/game/NN/O which/which/WDT/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION lost/lose/VBD/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/LS/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O for/for/IN/O kicking/kick/VBG/O City/City/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O former/former/JJ/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O Andrew/Andrew/NNP/PERSON Cole/Cole/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON won/win/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL trophy/trophy/NN/O in/in/IN/O English/english/JJ/MISC football/football/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2005/2005/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 06/06/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O the/the/DT/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER Football/Football/NNP/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION Cup/Cup/NNP/ORGANIZATION final/final/JJ/O victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Wigan/Wigan/NNP/ORGANIZATION Athletic/Athletic/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
2006/2006/CD/DATE --/--/:/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE The/the/DT/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE --/--/:/DATE 2007/2007/CD/DATE season/season/NN/O proved/prove/VBD/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O the/the/DT/O breakout/breakout/NN/O year/year/NN/DURATION for/for/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O as/as/IN/O he/he/PRP/O broke/break/VBD/O the/the/DT/O 20/20/CD/NUMBER goal/goal/NN/O barrier/barrier/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL time/time/NN/O and/and/CC/O picked/pick/VBD/O up/up/RP/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL league/league/NN/O title/title/NN/O with/with/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
In/in/IN/O November/November/NNP/DATE and/and/CC/O December/December/NNP/DATE 2006/2006/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON received/receive/VBD/O consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O Barclays/Barclays/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Month/Month/NNP/DATE honors/honor/NNS/O ,/,/,/O becoming/become/VBG/O only/only/RB/O the/the/DT/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O in/in/IN/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC history/history/NN/O to/to/TO/O do/do/VB/O so/so/RB/O after/after/IN/O Dennis/Dennis/NNP/PERSON Bergkamp/Bergkamp/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O 1997/1997/CD/DATE and/and/CC/O Robbie/Robbie/NNP/PERSON Fowler/Fowler/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O 1996/1996/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 50th/50th/JJ/ORDINAL Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION goal/goal/NN/O against/against/IN/O city/city/NN/O rivals/rival/NNS/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/LOCATION City/City/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 5/5/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE 2007/2007/CD/DATE as/as/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION claimed/claim/VBD/O their/they/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Premier/Premier/NNP/O League/League/NNP/O title/title/NN/O in/in/IN/O four/four/CD/DURATION years/year/NNS/NUMBER ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O voted/vote/VBN/O into/into/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O FIFPro/FIFPro/NNP/O Special/special/JJ/O Young/young/NN/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE award/award/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE end/end/NN/DATE of/of/IN/DATE the/the/DT/DATE year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
Despite/despite/IN/O rumors/rumor/NNS/O circulating/circulate/VBG/O in/in/IN/O March/March/NNP/DATE 2007/2007/CD/DATE that/that/WDT/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION were/be/VBD/O willing/willing/JJ/O to/to/TO/O pay/pay/VB/O an/a/DT/O unprecedented/unprecedented/JJ/O $/$/$/MONEY 80/80/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O #/#/#/MONEY 54/54/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O for/for/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O signed/sign/VBD/O a/a/DT/O five-year/five-year/JJ/DURATION ,/,/,/O #/#/#/MONEY 120,000-a-week/120,000-a-week/JJ/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O #/#/#/MONEY 31/31/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY total/total/NN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O extension/extension/NN/O with/with/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 13/13/CD/DATE April/April/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O making/make/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O highest-paid/highest-paid/JJ/O player/player/NN/O in/in/IN/O team/team/NN/O history/history/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON amassed/amass/VBD/O a/a/DT/O host/host/NN/O of/of/IN/O personal/personal/JJ/O awards/award/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O PFA/PFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Players/Players/NNPS/O '/'/POS/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE and/and/CC/O PFA/PFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Young/Young/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE awards/award/NNS/O ,/,/,/O joining/join/VBG/O Andy/Andy/NNP/PERSON Gray/Gray/NNP/PERSON -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O in/in/IN/O 1977/1977/CD/DATE -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O players/player/NNS/O to/to/TO/O receive/receive/VB/O this/this/DT/O honor/honor/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O April/April/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O completed/complete/VBD/O the/the/DT/O treble/treble/JJ/O by/by/IN/O winning/win/VBG/O the/the/DT/O PFA/PFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Fans/fan/NNS/O '/'/POS/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O also/also/RB/O won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O PFA/PFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Fans/fan/NNS/O '/'/POS/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE and/and/CC/O the/the/DT/O FWA/FWA/NNP/MISC Footballer/footballer/NN/MISC of/of/IN/MISC the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O all/all/DT/O four/four/CD/NUMBER main/main/JJ/O PFA/pfa/NN/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O FWA/fwa/NN/O awards/award/NNS/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O also/also/RB/O one/one/CD/TIME of/of/IN/TIME eight/eight/CD/TIME Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION players/player/NNS/O named/name/VBN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 07/07/CD/NUMBER PFA/PFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Premier/Premier/NNP/O League/League/NNP/O Team/Team/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 08/08/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O began/begin/VBD/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O red/red/JJ/O card/card/NN/O for/for/IN/O a/a/DT/O headbutt/headbutt/NN/O on/on/IN/O Portsmouth/Portsmouth/NNP/LOCATION player/player/NN/O Richard/Richard/NNP/PERSON Hughes/Hughes/NNP/PERSON during/during/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL match/match/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O for/for/IN/O which/which/WDT/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O punished/punish/VBN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O three-match/three-match/JJ/O ban/ban/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON said/say/VBD/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O ``/``/``/O learned/learn/VBD/O a/a/DT/O lot/lot/NN/O ''/''/''/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O experience/experience/NN/O and/and/CC/O would/would/MD/O not/not/RB/O let/let/VB/O players/player/NNS/O ``/``/``/O provoke/provoke/VB/O ''/''/''/O him/he/PRP/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE future/future/NN/DATE ./././O
After/after/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC away/away/RB/O match/match/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON also/also/RB/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O injury-time/injury-time/JJ/O winner/winner/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O return/return/NN/O fixture/fixture/NN/O as/as/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION topped/top/VBD/O their/they/PRP$/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC group/group/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O finished/finish/VBD/O as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O runner-up/runner-up/NN/O to/to/TO/O Kaká/Kaká/NNP/LOCATION for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE Ballon/Ballon/NNP/PERSON d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O was/be/VBD/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O running/run/VBG/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE award/award/NN/O ,/,/,/O behind/behind/IN/O Kaká/Kaká/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL hat/hat/NN/O trick/trick/NN/O for/for/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 6/6/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Newcastle/Newcastle/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION at/at/IN/O Old/Old/NNP/LOCATION Trafford/Trafford/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 12/12/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O bringing/bring/VBG/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION up/up/IN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O top/top/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC table/table/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O twenty-third/twenty-third/JJ/ORDINAL league/league/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Reading/Reading/NNP/O ,/,/,/O equalling/equal/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O entire/entire/JJ/O total/total/NN/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2006/2006/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 07/07/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
During/during/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC first/first/RB/ORDINAL knockout/knockout/JJ/O round/round/NN/O draw/draw/NN/O against/against/IN/O Lyon/Lyon/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 20/20/CD/DATE February/February/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O an/a/DT/O unidentified/unidentified/JJ/O Lyon/Lyon/NNP/ORGANIZATION supporter/supporter/NN/O continuously/continuously/RB/O aimed/aim/VBD/O a/a/DT/O green/green/JJ/O laser/laser/NN/O at/at/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION teammate/teammate/NN/O Nani/Nani/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O prompting/prompt/VBG/O an/a/DT/O investigation/investigation/NN/O by/by/IN/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
One/one/CD/DATE month/month/NN/DATE later/later/RB/DATE ,/,/,/O Lyon/Lyon/NNP/LOCATION were/be/VBD/O fined/fine/VBN/O CHF5/chf5/NN/O ,000/,000/CD/NUMBER -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O #/#/#/MONEY 2,427/2,427/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O incident/incident/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 19/19/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON captained/captain/VBD/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL time/time/NN/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O career/career/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O home/home/NN/O win/win/VB/O over/over/IN/O Bolton/Bolton/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O both/both/CC/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/DATE second/second/NN/DATE of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O goals/goal/NNS/O was/be/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 33rd/33rd/JJ/ORDINAL of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O campaign/campaign/NN/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O set/set/VBD/O a/a/DT/O new/new/JJ/O club/club/NN/O single-season/single-season/JJ/O scoring/score/VBG/O record/record/NN/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O midfielder/midfielder/NN/O and/and/CC/O thus/thus/RB/O topped/top/VBN/O George/George/NNP/PERSON Best/best/JJS/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O forty-year-old/forty-year-old/JJ/DURATION total/total/NN/O of/of/IN/O 32/32/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 1967/1967/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 68/68/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O another/another/DT/O brace/brace/VB/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Aston/Aston/NNP/ORGANIZATION Villa/Villa/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 29/29/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O time/time/NN/O gave/give/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O 35/35/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O 37/37/CD/NUMBER domestic/domestic/JJ/O and/and/CC/O European/european/JJ/MISC matches/match/NNS/O as/as/IN/O both/both/CC/O a/a/DT/O starter/starter/JJ/O and/and/CC/O substitute/substitute/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O scoring/score/VBG/O streak/streak/NN/O was/be/VBD/O rewarded/reward/VBN/O with/with/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL winger/winger/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O the/the/DT/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 08/08/CD/NUMBER European/european/JJ/ORGANIZATION Golden/Golden/NNP/ORGANIZATION Shoe/Shoe/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O finishing/finish/VBG/O eight/eight/CD/NUMBER points/point/NNS/O ahead/ahead/RB/O of/of/IN/O Mallorca/Mallorca/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O Dani/Dani/NNP/PERSON Güiza/Güiza/NNP/PERSON ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 08/08/CD/NUMBER Champions/Champions/NNPS/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION final/final/JJ/O on/on/IN/O 21/21/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE against/against/IN/O league/league/NN/O rivals/rival/NNS/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O opening/opening/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O after/after/IN/O 26/26/CD/DURATION minutes/minute/NNS/NUMBER ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O negated/negate/VBN/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION equaliser/equaliser/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 45th/45th/JJ/ORDINAL minute/minute/NN/DURATION as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O match/match/NN/O ended/end/VBD/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER after/after/IN/O extra/extra/JJ/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O misfire/misfire/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O penalty/penalty/NN/O shoot-out/shoot-out/NN/O put/put/VBD/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O position/position/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O the/the/DT/O trophy/trophy/NN/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O John/John/NNP/PERSON Terry/Terry/NNP/PERSON shot/shoot/VBD/O wide/wide/RB/O right/right/RB/O after/after/IN/O slipping/slip/VBG/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O pitch/pitch/NN/O surface/surface/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION emerged/emerge/VBD/O victorious/victorious/JJ/O 6/6/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER on/on/IN/O penalties/penalty/NNS/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O named/name/VBN/O the/the/DT/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Fans/fan/NNS/O '/'/POS/O Man/man/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Match/Match/NNP/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O wrapped/wrap/VBD/O up/up/RP/O the/the/DT/O campaign/campaign/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O career-high/career-high/JJ/O 42/42/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ,/,/,/O falling/fall/VBG/O four/four/CD/NUMBER short/short/JJ/O of/of/IN/O Denis/Denis/NNP/PERSON Law/Law/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O team-record/team-record/JJ/O mark/mark/NN/O of/of/IN/O 46/46/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 1963/1963/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 64/64/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O also/also/RB/O named/name/VBN/O best/best/JJS/O forward/forward/RB/O and/and/CC/O player/player/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O tournament/tournament/NN/O and/and/CC/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O competition/competition/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O top/top/JJ/O goalscorer/goalscorer/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 5/5/CD/DATE June/June/NNP/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Sky/Sky/NNP/O Sports/Sports/NNP/O reported/report/VBD/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O expressed/express/VBN/O an/a/DT/O interest/interest/NN/O in/in/IN/O moving/move/VBG/O to/to/TO/O Real/real/JJ/LOCATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION if/if/IN/O they/they/PRP/O offered/offer/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O same/same/JJ/O amount/amount/NN/O of/of/IN/O money/money/NN/O the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O had/have/VBD/O allegedly/allegedly/RB/O promised/promise/VBN/O him/he/PRP/O earlier/earlier/RBR/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION filed/file/VBD/O a/a/DT/O tampering/tamper/VBG/O complaint/complaint/NN/O with/with/IN/O FIFA/fifa/NN/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 9/9/CD/DATE June/June/NNP/DATE over/over/IN/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O alleged/alleged/JJ/O pursuit/pursuit/NN/O of/of/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION declined/decline/VBD/O to/to/TO/O take/take/VB/O any/any/DT/O action/action/NN/O ./././O
Speculation/speculation/NN/O that/that/IN/O a/a/DT/O transfer/transfer/NN/O would/would/MD/O happen/happen/VB/O continued/continue/VBN/O until/until/IN/O 6/6/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O when/when/WRB/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON confirmed/confirm/VBD/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O would/would/MD/O stay/stay/VB/O at/at/IN/O United/United/NNP/O for/for/IN/O at/at/IN/DURATION least/least/JJS/DURATION another/another/DT/DURATION year/year/NN/DURATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON underwent/undergo/VBD/O ankle/ankle/NN/O surgery/surgery/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Academic/Academic/NNP/ORGANIZATION Medical/Medical/NNP/ORGANIZATION Center/Center/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O Amsterdam/Amsterdam/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 7/7/CD/DATE July/July/NNP/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O returned/return/VBD/O to/to/TO/O action/action/NN/O on/on/IN/O 17/17/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE in/in/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O goalless/goalless/JJ/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Champions/Champions/NNPS/ORGANIZATION League/League/NNP/ORGANIZATION group/group/NN/O stage/stage/NN/O draw/draw/NN/O with/with/IN/O Villarreal/Villarreal/NNP/PERSON as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O substitute/substitute/NN/O for/for/IN/O Park/Park/NNP/PERSON Ji-Sung/Ji-Sung/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER League/League/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC third/third/JJ/ORDINAL round/round/NN/O win/win/VB/O over/over/IN/O Middlesbrough/Middlesbrough/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 24/24/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ./././O
In/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Stoke/Stoke/NNP/ORGANIZATION City/City/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 15/15/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE 2008/2008/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 100th/100th/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/O 101st/101st/JJ/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O for/for/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O both/both/DT/O from/from/IN/O free/free/JJ/O kicks/kick/VBZ/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O goals/goal/NNS/O also/also/RB/O meant/mean/VBD/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O now/now/RB/DATE scored/score/VBN/O against/against/IN/O each/each/DT/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O other/other/JJ/O 19/19/CD/NUMBER teams/team/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O time/time/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 2/2/CD/DATE December/December/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON became/become/VBD/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Ballon/Ballon/NNP/PERSON d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O recipient/recipient/JJ/O since/since/IN/O George/George/NNP/PERSON Best/best/JJS/PERSON in/in/IN/O 1968/1968/CD/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O finished/finish/VBD/O with/with/IN/O 446/446/CD/NUMBER points/point/NNS/O ,/,/,/O 165/165/CD/NUMBER ahead/ahead/RB/O of/of/IN/O runner-up/runner-up/JJ/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O awarded/award/VBN/O the/the/DT/O Silver/silver/NN/O Ball/Ball/NNP/O after/after/IN/O finishing/finish/VBG/O with/with/IN/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O as/as/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Club/Club/NNP/MISC World/World/NNP/MISC Cup/Cup/NNP/MISC on/on/IN/O 19/19/CD/DATE December/December/NNP/DATE ./././O
On/on/IN/O 8/8/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O uninjured/uninjured/JJ/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single-car/single-car/JJ/O accident/accident/NN/O in/in/IN/O which/which/WDT/O he/he/PRP/O wrote/write/VBD/O off/off/RP/O his/he/PRP$/O Ferrari/Ferrari/NNP/ORGANIZATION 599/599/CD/NUMBER GTB/GTB/NNP/O Fiorano/Fiorano/NNP/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O tunnel/tunnel/NN/O along/along/IN/O the/the/DT/O A538/a538/NN/O near/near/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/LOCATION Airport/Airport/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
A/a/DT/O breathalyser/breathalyser/NN/O test/test/NN/O he/he/PRP/O gave/give/VBD/O to/to/TO/O police/police/NNS/O officers/officer/NNS/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O scene/scene/NN/O was/be/VBD/O negative/negative/JJ/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O he/he/PRP/O attended/attend/VBD/O training/training/NN/O later/later/RB/O that/that/IN/O morning/morning/NN/TIME ./././O
Four/four/CD/DATE days/day/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Premier/Premier/NNP/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC player/player/NN/O ever/ever/RB/O to/to/TO/O be/be/VB/O named/name/VBN/O the/the/DT/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION World/World/NNP/O Player/Player/NNP/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O addition/addition/NN/O to/to/TO/O being/be/VBG/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/MISC player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O the/the/DT/O award/award/NN/O since/since/IN/O Luís/Luís/NNP/PERSON Figo/Figo/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O 2001/2001/CD/DATE ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O first/first/RB/ORDINAL since/since/IN/O the/the/DT/O final/final/JJ/O against/against/IN/O Chelsea/Chelsea/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Internazionale/Internazionale/NNP/ORGANIZATION that/that/WDT/O sent/send/VBD/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION into/into/IN/O the/the/DT/O quarter-finals/quarter-final/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O against/against/IN/O Porto/Porto/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O 40-yard/40-yard/JJ/O game-winning/game-winning/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O as/as/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION advanced/advance/VBD/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O semi-finals/semi-final/NNS/O ./././O
For/for/IN/O this/this/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON holds/hold/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O distinction/distinction/NN/O of/of/IN/O being/be/VBG/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O the/the/DT/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Puskás/Puskás/NNP/O Award/award/NN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O an/a/DT/O honor/honor/NN/O handed/hand/VBN/O by/by/IN/O FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O best/best/JJS/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE year/year/NN/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O later/later/RB/O called/call/VBD/O it/it/PRP/O the/the/DT/O best/best/JJS/O goal/goal/NN/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O ever/ever/RB/O scored/score/VBN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON participated/participate/VBD/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC final/final/JJ/O ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O made/make/VBD/O little/little/JJ/O impact/impact/NN/O in/in/IN/O United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER loss/loss/NN/O to/to/TO/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O finished/finish/VBD/O with/with/IN/O 53/53/CD/NUMBER appearances/appearance/NNS/O in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O four/four/CD/NUMBER higher/higher/JJR/O than/than/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE previous/previous/JJ/DATE year/year/NN/DATE ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O scored/score/VBD/O sixteen/sixteen/CD/NUMBER fewer/fewer/JJR/O goals/goal/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O 26/26/CD/NUMBER -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O than/than/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O career-best/career-best/JJ/O total/total/NN/O of/of/IN/O 42/42/CD/NUMBER from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O previous/previous/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 11/11/CD/DATE June/June/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION accepted/accept/VBD/O an/a/DT/O unconditional/unconditional/JJ/O offer/offer/NN/O of/of/IN/O #/#/#/MONEY 80/80/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY from/from/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION for/for/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON after/after/IN/O it/it/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O revealed/reveal/VBN/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O again/again/RB/O had/have/VBD/O expressed/express/VBN/O his/he/PRP$/O desire/desire/NN/O to/to/TO/O leave/leave/VB/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O ./././O
It/it/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O confirmed/confirm/VBN/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O representative/representative/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Glazer/Glazer/NNP/PERSON family/family/NN/O that/that/IN/O the/the/DT/O sale/sale/NN/O was/be/VBD/O fully/fully/RB/O condoned/condone/VBN/O by/by/IN/O Ferguson/Ferguson/NNP/PERSON ./././O
When/when/WRB/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O eventually/eventually/RB/O completed/complete/VBN/O his/he/PRP$/O transfer/transfer/NN/O to/to/TO/O Real/real/JJ/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O expressed/express/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O gratitude/gratitude/NN/O towards/towards/IN/O Ferguson/Ferguson/NNP/PERSON for/for/IN/O helping/help/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O develop/develop/VB/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O player/player/NN/O ,/,/,/O saying/say/VBG/O ,/,/,/O ``/``/``/O He/he/PRP/O 's/be/VBZ/O been/be/VBN/O my/my/PRP$/O father/father/NN/O in/in/IN/O sport/sport/NN/O ,/,/,/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O important/important/JJ/O factors/factor/NNS/O and/and/CC/O most/most/JJS/O influential/influential/JJ/O in/in/IN/O my/my/PRP$/O career/career/NN/O ./././O ''/''/''/O
Real/real/JJ/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 10/10/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O On/on/IN/O 26/26/CD/DATE June/June/NNP/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION confirmed/confirm/VBD/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON would/would/MD/O join/join/VB/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O on/on/IN/O 1/1/CD/DATE July/July/NNP/DATE 2009/2009/CD/DATE from/from/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION for/for/IN/O #/#/#/MONEY 80/80/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O $/$/$/MONEY 93.9/93.9/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O expensive/expensive/JJ/O footballer/footballer/NN/O in/in/IN/O history/history/NN/O ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O agreeing/agree/VBG/O terms/term/NNS/O and/and/CC/O signing/sign/VBG/O a/a/DT/O six-year/six-year/JJ/DURATION contract/contract/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O contract/contract/NN/O is/be/VBZ/O worth/worth/JJ/O $/$/$/MONEY 11/11/CD/MONEY million/million/CD/MONEY per/per/IN/O year/year/NN/DURATION and/and/CC/O it/it/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O a/a/DT/O $/$/$/MONEY 1/1/CD/MONEY billion/billion/CD/MONEY buy-out/buy-out/NN/O clause/clause/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O presented/present/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O media/media/NNS/O as/as/IN/O a/a/DT/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O on/on/IN/O 6/6/CD/DATE July/July/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O handed/hand/VBN/O the/the/DT/O number/number/NN/O 9/9/CD/NUMBER jersey/jersey/NN/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O shirt/shirt/NN/O was/be/VBD/O presented/present/VBN/O to/to/TO/O him/he/PRP/O by/by/IN/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION legend/legend/NN/O Alfredo/Alfredo/NNP/PERSON Di/Di/NNP/PERSON Stéfano/Stéfano/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O welcomed/welcome/VBN/O by/by/IN/O between/between/IN/O 80,000/80,000/CD/NUMBER and/and/CC/NUMBER 85,000/85,000/CD/NUMBER fans/fan/NNS/O at/at/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O presentation/presentation/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Santiago/Santiago/NNP/LOCATION Bernabéu/Bernabéu/NNP/LOCATION Stadium/Stadium/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O surpassing/surpass/VBG/O Diego/diego/JJ/PERSON Maradona/Maradona/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O 75,000/75,000/CD/NUMBER fans/fan/NNS/O when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O presented/present/VBN/O in/in/IN/O Italy/Italy/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O transferred/transfer/VBN/O from/from/IN/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/LOCATION to/to/TO/O Napoli/Napoli/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O 1984/1984/CD/DATE ./././O
The/the/DT/O event/event/NN/O was/be/VBD/O broadcasted/broadcast/VBN/O live/live/JJ/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O Spanish/spanish/JJ/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Portuguese/portuguese/JJ/LOCATION public/public/JJ/O TV/tv/NN/O stations/station/NNS/O ,/,/,/O RTVE/rtve/NN/ORGANIZATION and/and/CC/O RTP/rtp/NN/O respectively/respectively/RB/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION debut/debut/NN/O on/on/IN/O 21/21/CD/DATE July/July/NNP/DATE in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Shamrock/Shamrock/NNP/ORGANIZATION Rovers/Rovers/NNPS/ORGANIZATION ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O came/come/VBD/O one/one/CD/DATE week/week/NN/DATE later/later/RB/DATE with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O penalty/penalty/NN/O in/in/IN/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O LDU/LDU/NNP/ORGANIZATION Quito/Quito/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 29/29/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON capped/cap/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION debut/debut/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O Real/Real/NNP/O 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O penalty/penalty/NN/O spot/spot/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Deportivo/Deportivo/NNP/ORGANIZATION La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Coruña/Coruña/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 15/15/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER free-kicks/free-kick/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Zürich/Zürich/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC goals/goal/NNS/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O broke/break/VBD/O a/a/DT/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION club/club/NN/O record/record/NN/O when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O league/league/NN/O match/match/NN/O against/against/IN/O Villarreal/Villarreal/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O thus/thus/RB/O became/become/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL ever/ever/RB/O player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O score/score/NN/NUMBER in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL four/four/CD/NUMBER La/La/NNP/O Liga/Liga/NNP/O appearances/appearance/NNS/O ./././O
An/a/DT/O ankle/ankle/NN/O injury/injury/NN/O suffered/suffer/VBD/O on/on/IN/O 10/10/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O while/while/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O on/on/IN/O international/international/JJ/O duty/duty/NN/O with/with/IN/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION against/against/IN/O Hungary/Hungary/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O kept/keep/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O out/out/RP/O until/until/IN/O 25/25/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O in/in/IN/O turn/turn/NN/O caused/cause/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O miss/miss/VB/O both/both/DT/O of/of/IN/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC group/group/NN/O stage/stage/NN/O matches/match/VBZ/O against/against/IN/O Milan/Milan/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON made/make/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL post-injury/post-injury/JJ/O start/start/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER El/El/NNP/ORGANIZATION Clásico/Clásico/NNP/ORGANIZATION defeat/defeat/VB/O to/to/TO/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION on/on/IN/O 29/29/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE ./././O
On/on/IN/O 6/6/CD/DATE December/December/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O sent/send/VBN/O off/off/RP/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL time/time/NN/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION career/career/NN/O in/in/IN/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O against/against/IN/O Almería/Almería/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O match/match/NN/O which/which/WDT/O also/also/RB/O saw/see/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O miss/miss/VB/O a/a/DT/O penalty/penalty/NN/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O carded/card/VBN/O first/first/RB/ORDINAL for/for/IN/O removing/remove/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O shirt/shirt/NN/O during/during/IN/O a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O celebration/celebration/NN/O ,/,/,/O then/then/RB/O for/for/IN/O kicking/kick/VBG/O out/out/RP/O at/at/IN/O an/a/DT/O opponent/opponent/NN/O three/three/CD/DATE minutes/minute/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/MISC World/World/NNP/MISC Player/Player/NNP/MISC of/of/IN/MISC the/the/DT/DATE Year/year/NN/DATE award/award/NN/O and/and/CC/O also/also/RB/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2009/2009/CD/DATE Ballon/Ballon/NNP/PERSON d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O award/award/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 5/5/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O an/a/DT/O away/away/RB/O game/game/NN/O against/against/IN/O Mallorca/Mallorca/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Gonzalo/Gonzalo/NNP/PERSON Higuaín/Higuaín/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O 53/53/CD/NUMBER league/league/NN/O goals/goal/NNS/O during/during/IN/O the/the/DT/O course/course/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O and/and/CC/O became/become/VBD/O Real/Real/NNP/O 's/'s/POS/O highest/highest/JJS/O scoring/score/VBG/O league/league/NN/O duo/duo/NN/O in/in/IN/O their/they/PRP$/O history/history/NN/O ./././O
2010/2010/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 11/11/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O With/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O departure/departure/NN/O of/of/IN/O Raúl/raúl/NN/O during/during/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE summer/summer/NN/DATE of/of/IN/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O handed/hand/VBN/O the/the/DT/O No./no./NN/O 7/7/CD/NUMBER jersey/jersey/NN/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 23/23/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O four/four/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O against/against/IN/O Racing/race/VBG/ORGANIZATION de/de/FW/ORGANIZATION Santander/santander/FW/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O goals/goal/NNS/O he/he/PRP/O has/have/VBZ/O ever/ever/RB/O scored/score/VBN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O match/match/NN/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O completed/complete/VBD/O a/a/DT/O goalscoring/goalscoring/NN/O run/run/NN/O of/of/IN/O six/six/CD/NUMBER consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O matches/match/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O three/three/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O one/one/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O two/two/CD/NUMBER for/for/IN/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O which/which/WDT/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O in/in/IN/O each/each/DT/O match/match/NN/O ,/,/,/O totalling/total/VBG/O 11/11/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O is/be/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O most/most/RBS/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON has/have/VBZ/O scored/score/VBN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O month/month/NN/DURATION ./././O
Before/before/IN/ORGANIZATION Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O by/by/IN/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Camp/Camp/NNP/O Nou/Nou/NNP/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Athletic/Athletic/NNP/ORGANIZATION Bilbao/Bilbao/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O final/final/JJ/O match/match/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O calendar/calendar/NN/O year/year/NN/DURATION saw/see/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O score/score/VBP/NUMBER a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 8/8/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER trashing/trashing/NN/O of/of/IN/O Levante/Levante/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Copa/Copa/NNP/O del/del/NNP/O Rey/Rey/NNP/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON began/begin/VBD/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O very/very/RB/O promising/promising/JJ/O outlook/outlook/NN/O ,/,/,/O especially/especially/RB/O after/after/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION acknowledged/acknowledge/VBD/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O broken/break/VBN/O numerous/numerous/JJ/O goalscoring/goalscoring/NN/O records/record/NNS/O ,/,/,/O previously/previously/RB/DATE settled/settle/VBN/O and/and/CC/O held/hold/VBN/O by/by/IN/O classic/classic/JJ/O players/player/NNS/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O Alfredo/Alfredo/NNP/PERSON Di/Di/NNP/PERSON Stéfano/Stéfano/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Hugo/Hugo/NNP/PERSON Sánchez/Sánchez/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Manuel/Manuel/NNP/PERSON Alday/Alday/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON began/begin/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O scoring/score/VBG/O spree/spree/NN/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O two/two/CD/NUMBER vital/vital/JJ/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O tight/tight/JJ/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O away/away/RB/O to/to/TO/O Getafe/Getafe/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O then/then/RB/O consolidated/consolidate/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O massive/massive/JJ/O performances/performance/NNS/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O and/and/CC/O assisting/assist/VBG/O Kaká/Kaká/NNP/PERSON to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL league/league/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O after/after/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O return/return/NN/O from/from/IN/O injury/injury/NN/O ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Villarreal/Villarreal/NNP/PERSON on/on/IN/O 9/9/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE ./././O
One/one/CD/NUMBER game/game/NN/O away/away/RB/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O middle/middle/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O a/a/DT/O very/very/RB/O clear/clear/JJ/O chance/chance/NN/O of/of/IN/O breaking/break/VBG/O Telmo/Telmo/NNP/PERSON Zarra/Zarra/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O and/and/CC/O Hugo/Hugo/NNP/PERSON Sánchez/Sánchez/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O 38/38/CD/NUMBER League/League/NNP/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O since/since/IN/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O the/the/DT/O league/league/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O top/top/JJ/O scorer/scorer/NN/O with/with/IN/O 22/22/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O above/above/IN/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON ./././O
However/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O shortly/shortly/RB/O after/after/IN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON experienced/experience/VBD/O the/the/DT/O biggest/biggest/JJS/O goal/goal/NN/O drought/drought/NN/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O entire/entire/JJ/O career/career/NN/O ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O only/only/RB/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O more/more/JJR/DURATION than/than/IN/DURATION a/a/DT/DURATION month/month/NN/DURATION ./././O
During/during/IN/O this/this/DT/O period/period/NN/O ,/,/,/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION acknowledged/acknowledge/VBD/O to/to/TO/O have/have/VB/O hit/hit/VBN/O the/the/DT/O crossbar/crossbar/NN/O more/more/RBR/O than/than/IN/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER times/time/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O most/most/JJS/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O shots/shot/NNS/O belonging/belong/VBG/O to/to/TO/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O almost/almost/RB/O all/all/DT/O having/have/VBG/O happened/happen/VBN/O during/during/IN/O crucial/crucial/JJ/O moments/moment/NNS/O in/in/IN/O drawn/draw/VBN/O matches/match/NNS/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON then/then/RB/O made/make/VBD/O a/a/DT/O massive/massive/JJ/O comeback/comeback/NN/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 7/7/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER trashing/trashing/NN/O of/of/IN/O Málaga/Málaga/NNP/LOCATION on/on/IN/O 3/3/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O but/but/CC/O was/be/VBD/O affected/affect/VBN/O by/by/IN/O a/a/DT/O muscle/muscle/NN/O injury/injury/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O end/end/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O match/match/NN/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O forced/force/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O spend/spend/VB/O 10/10/CD/DURATION days/day/NNS/NUMBER on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O sidelines/sideline/NNS/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O April/April/NNP/DATE he/he/PRP/O made/make/VBD/O another/another/DT/O massive/massive/JJ/O comeback/comeback/NN/O from/from/IN/O injury/injury/NN/O ,/,/,/O sustaining/sustain/VBG/O a/a/DT/O three-game/three-game/JJ/O scoring/score/VBG/O streak/streak/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O including/include/VBG/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC quarter-finals/quarter-final/NNS/O against/against/IN/O Tottenham/Tottenham/NNP/ORGANIZATION Hotspur/Hotspur/NNP/ORGANIZATION -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O thus/thus/RB/O arriving/arrive/VBG/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O historical/historical/JJ/O series/series/NN/O of/of/IN/O four/four/CD/NUMBER El/El/NNP/O Clásico/Clásico/NNP/O encounters/encounter/VBZ/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O short/short/JJ/O of/of/IN/O breaking/break/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O personal/personal/JJ/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O 42/42/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O achieved/achieve/VBN/O at/at/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2007/2007/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 08/08/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O ./././O
During/during/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL league/league/NN/O edition/edition/NN/O of/of/IN/O El/El/NNP/LOCATION Clásico/Clásico/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O penalty/penalty/NN/O spot/spot/NN/O and/and/CC/O took/take/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O tally/tally/NN/O to/to/TO/O 41/41/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ,/,/,/O also/also/RB/O taking/take/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O scoring/score/VBG/O streak/streak/NN/O to/to/TO/O four/four/CD/NUMBER games/game/NNS/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 20/20/CD/DATE April/April/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O winning/win/VBG/O goal/goal/NN/O against/against/IN/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE 103rd/103rd/JJ/DATE minute/minute/NN/DATE of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Copa/Copa/NNP/O del/del/NNP/O Rey/Rey/NNP/O final/final/JJ/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O would/would/MD/O later/later/RB/O be/be/VB/O chosen/choose/VBN/O as/as/IN/O both/both/DT/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O and/and/CC/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O best/best/JJS/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O by/by/IN/O several/several/JJ/O fan/fan/NN/O polls/poll/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O those/those/DT/O of/of/IN/O Marca/Marca/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O website/website/NN/O ./././O
7/7/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE saw/see/VBD/O Real/real/JJ/O travel/travel/NN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Ramón/Ramón/NNP/PERSON Sánchez/Sánchez/NNP/PERSON Pizjuán/Pizjuán/NNP/PERSON to/to/TO/O take/take/VB/O on/on/RP/O Sevilla/Sevilla/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O where/where/WRB/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON led/lead/VBD/O the/the/DT/O thrashing/thrashing/NN/O of/of/IN/O a/a/DT/O woeful/woeful/JJ/O Andalusian/andalusian/JJ/MISC side/side/NN/O ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O four/four/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 6/6/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O ./././O
These/these/DT/O four/four/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O took/take/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O to/to/TO/O 46/46/CD/NUMBER for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O which/which/WDT/O surpassed/surpass/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O previous/previous/JJ/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O 42/42/CD/NUMBER in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O season/season/NN/O playing/playing/NN/O for/for/IN/O Manchester/Manchester/NNP/ORGANIZATION United/United/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Three/three/CD/DATE days/day/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE he/he/PRP/O reached/reach/VBD/O 49/49/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O by/by/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O another/another/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Getafe/Getafe/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 15/15/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O two/two/CD/NUMBER free-kick/free-kick/NN/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Villarreal/Villarreal/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O equalled/equal/VBD/O the/the/DT/O La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION record/record/NN/O with/with/IN/O most/most/JJS/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O season/season/NN/O with/with/IN/O 38/38/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O a/a/DT/O record/record/NN/O previously/previously/RB/DATE held/hold/VBN/O by/by/IN/O Telmo/Telmo/NNP/PERSON Zarra/Zarra/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Hugo/Hugo/NNP/PERSON Sánchez/Sánchez/NNP/PERSON ./././O
On/on/IN/O 21/21/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O last/last/JJ/O league/league/NN/O match/match/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O against/against/IN/O Almería/Almería/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O taking/take/VBG/O his/he/PRP$/O Pichichi/Pichichi/NNP/O total/total/NN/O to/to/TO/O 41/41/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION total/total/NN/O to/to/TO/O 40/40/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER 40/40/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O La/La/NNP/O Liga/Liga/NNP/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
By/by/IN/O doing/do/VBG/O this/this/DT/O ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O European/european/JJ/MISC Golden/Golden/NNP/MISC Shoe/Shoe/NNP/MISC award/award/NN/O once/once/RB/DATE again/again/RB/O ,/,/,/O becoming/become/VBG/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O win/win/VB/O the/the/DT/O trophy/trophy/NN/O in/in/IN/O two/two/CD/NUMBER different/different/JJ/O leagues/league/NNS/O ./././O
The/the/DT/O sports/sport/NNS/O newspaper/newspaper/NN/O Marca/Marca/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O who/who/WP/O awards/award/VBZ/O the/the/DT/O Pichichi/Pichichi/NNP/ORGANIZATION Trophy/trophy/NN/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O included/include/VBD/O the/the/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O scored/score/VBD/O on/on/IN/O 18/18/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE 2010/2010/CD/DATE against/against/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Sociedad/Sociedad/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O goal/goal/NN/O count/count/NN/O ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O had/have/VBD/O been/be/VBN/O officially/officially/RB/O attributed/attribute/VBN/O to/to/TO/O Pepe/Pepe/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Should/should/MD/O this/this/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O be/be/VB/O granted/grant/VBN/O to/to/TO/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O his/he/PRP$/O goal/goal/NN/O count/count/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Pichichi/Pichichi/NNP/ORGANIZATION Trophy/trophy/NN/ORGANIZATION would/would/MD/O tally/tally/NN/O 41/41/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON also/also/RB/O broke/break/VBD/O Zarra/Zarra/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O most/most/JJS/O goals/goal/NNS/O per/per/IN/O minute/minute/NN/DURATION ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O scored/score/VBD/O every/every/DT/SET 70.7/70.7/CD/SET minutes/minute/NNS/NUMBER ./././O
However/however/RB/O ,/,/,/O regardless/regardless/RB/O of/of/IN/O this/this/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O polemic/polemic/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O record-breaking/record-breaking/JJ/O figures/figure/NNS/O became/become/VBD/O a/a/DT/O source/source/NN/O of/of/IN/O major/major/JJ/O attention/attention/NN/O from/from/IN/O public/public/JJ/O media/media/NNS/O ,/,/,/O such/such/JJ/O as/as/IN/O being/be/VBG/O included/include/VBN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Sports/Sports/NNP/O Illustrated/Illustrated/NNP/O World/World/NNP/O XI/XI/NNP/O ,/,/,/O rating/rating/NN/O him/he/PRP/O as/as/IN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O best/best/JJS/O footballers/footballer/NNS/O ./././O
Accounting/accounting/NN/O for/for/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ended/end/VBD/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O total/total/NN/O of/of/IN/O 53/53/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O not/not/RB/O granting/grant/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O controversial/controversial/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O from/from/IN/O Pepe/Pepe/NNP/PERSON -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O ,/,/,/O having/have/VBG/O scored/score/VBN/O 25/25/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O with/with/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O right/right/JJ/O foot/foot/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O excluding/exclude/VBG/O free-kicks/free-kick/NNS/O and/and/CC/O penalty-kicks/penalty-kick/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O and/and/CC/O 9/9/CD/NUMBER with/with/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O left/left/JJ/O foot/foot/NN/O ./././O
2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O pre-season/pre-season/JJ/O began/begin/VBD/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O MLS/MLS/NNP/ORGANIZATION team/team/NN/O Los/Los/NNP/ORGANIZATION Angeles/Angeles/NNP/ORGANIZATION Galaxy/Galaxy/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O goals/goal/NNS/O from/from/IN/O Callejón/Callejón/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Joselu/Joselu/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O Benzema/Benzema/NNP/PERSON ./././O
Four/four/CD/DATE days/day/NNS/DATE later/later/RB/DATE Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/DURATION second/second/JJ/DURATION half/half/NN/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Guadalajara/Guadalajara/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O preseason/preseason/NN/O performance/performance/NN/O was/be/VBD/O highly/highly/RB/O praised/praise/VBN/O as/as/IN/O world/world/NN/O media/media/NNS/O kept/keep/VBD/O hailing/hail/VBG/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O extreme/extreme/JJ/O competitiveness/competitiveness/NN/O and/and/CC/O motivation/motivation/NN/O ,/,/,/O even/even/RB/O during/during/IN/O friendly/friendly/JJ/O matches/match/NNS/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 17/17/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 100th/100th/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O with/with/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O first-half/first-half/JJ/O equaliser/equaliser/NN/O against/against/IN/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE Spanish/spanish/JJ/MISC Supercup/Supercup/NNP/MISC in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Camp/Camp/NNP/MISC Nou/Nou/NNP/MISC ./././O
On/on/IN/O 27/27/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O opened/open/VBD/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION season/season/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 6/6/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O at/at/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Zaragoza/Zaragoza/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
In/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DATE first/first/JJ/DATE weeks/week/NNS/DATE of/of/IN/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O physical/physical/JJ/O performance/performance/NN/O was/be/VBD/O subject/subject/JJ/O to/to/TO/O scrutiny/scrutiny/NN/O by/by/IN/O world/world/NN/O media/media/NNS/O ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O Castrol/Castrol/NNP/ORGANIZATION released/release/VBD/O a/a/DT/O television/television/NN/O film/film/NN/O named/name/VBN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON :/:/:/O Tested/test/VBN/O to/to/TO/O the/the/DT/O Limit/Limit/NNP/O where/where/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O put/put/VBN/O to/to/TO/O test/test/VB/O in/in/IN/O several/several/JJ/O fields/field/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O mental/mental/JJ/O and/and/CC/O physical/physical/JJ/O ./././O
Conclusions/conclusion/NNS/O from/from/IN/O the/the/DT/O movie/movie/NN/O and/and/CC/O doctors/doctor/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/DURATION weeks/week/NNS/DURATION following/follow/VBG/O claimed/claim/VBN/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O best/best/JJS/O athletes/athlete/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O world/world/NN/O ,/,/,/O excelling/excel/VBG/O in/in/IN/O football/football/NN/O and/and/CC/O outstanding/outstanding/JJ/O in/in/IN/O almost/almost/RB/O every/every/DT/O other/other/JJ/O category/category/NN/O ./././O
-LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O citation/citation/NN/O needed/need/VBN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O Several/several/JJ/O sources/source/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O weasel/weasel/NN/O words/word/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O drew/draw/VBD/O comparisons/comparison/NNS/O between/between/IN/O him/he/PRP/O and/and/CC/O other/other/JJ/O top/top/JJ/O athletes/athlete/NNS/O ,/,/,/O including/include/VBG/O sprinter/sprinter/NN/O Usain/Usain/NNP/PERSON Bolt/Bolt/NNP/PERSON ./././O
-LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O citation/citation/NN/O needed/need/VBN/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O On/on/IN/O 24/24/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O including/include/VBG/O two/two/CD/NUMBER penalties/penalty/NNS/O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O 6/6/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Rayo/Rayo/NNP/PERSON Vallecano/Vallecano/NNP/PERSON at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Santiago/Santiago/NNP/LOCATION Bernabéu/Bernabéu/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
This/this/DT/O was/be/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O ninth/ninth/JJ/ORDINAL La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O and/and/CC/O tenth/tenth/NN/ORDINAL hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 27/27/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O Real/Real/NNP/O 's/'s/POS/O opening/opening/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Ajax/Ajax/NNP/ORGANIZATION at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Santiago/Santiago/NNP/LOCATION Bernabéu/Bernabéu/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/MISC Champions/Champions/NNPS/MISC League/League/NNP/MISC ./././O
On/on/IN/O 22/22/CD/DATE October/October/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O not/not/RB/O scoring/score/VBG/O in/in/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O previous/previous/JJ/O three/three/CD/NUMBER games/game/NNS/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O tenth/tenth/NN/ORDINAL La/La/NNP/O Liga/Liga/NNP/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O and/and/CC/O eleventh/eleventh/NN/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O total/total/NN/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O match/match/NN/O away/away/RB/O to/to/TO/O Málaga/Málaga/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION won/win/VBD/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O twelfth/twelfth/JJ/ORDINAL Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O followed/follow/VBD/O on/on/IN/O 6/6/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 7/7/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER victory/victory/NN/O over/over/IN/O Osasuna/Osasuna/NNP/ORGANIZATION that/that/WDT/O ensured/ensure/VBD/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION stayed/stay/VBD/O top/top/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O table/table/NN/O heading/head/VBG/O into/into/IN/O the/the/DT/O international/international/JJ/O break/break/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 19/19/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O Real/Real/NNP/O 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O of/of/IN/O Valencia/Valencia/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 26/26/CD/DATE November/November/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER penalties/penalty/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O of/of/IN/O Atlético/Atlético/NNP/LOCATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O El/El/NNP/LOCATION Derbi/Derbi/NNP/LOCATION madrileño/madrileño/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 3/3/CD/DATE December/December/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER defeat/defeat/NN/O of/of/IN/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION de/de/IN/ORGANIZATION Gijón/Gijón/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O three/three/CD/NUMBER finalists/finalist/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Ballon/Ballon/NNP/O d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 13/13/CD/DATE December/December/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O against/against/IN/O SD/sd/NN/PERSON Ponferradina/Ponferradina/NNP/PERSON in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O Copa/Copa/NNP/O del/del/NNP/O Rey/Rey/NNP/O Round/Round/NNP/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O match/match/NN/O ended/end/VBN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 17/17/CD/DATE December/December/NNP/DATE 2011/2011/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O twelfth/twelfth/JJ/ORDINAL La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O and/and/CC/O thirteenth/thirteenth/JJ/ORDINAL overall/overall/JJ/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 6/6/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER win/win/VB/O away/away/RB/O to/to/TO/O Sevilla/Sevilla/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O third/third/JJ/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2010/2010/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 11/11/CD/NUMBER UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Best/best/JJS/O Player/Player/NNP/O in/in/IN/O Europe/Europe/NNP/LOCATION Award/award/NN/O ,/,/,/O behind/behind/IN/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O Xavi/Xavi/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE FIFA/FIFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Ballon/Ballon/NNP/O d'Or/d'Or/NNP/O ,/,/,/O behind/behind/IN/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON and/and/CC/O ahead/ahead/RB/O of/of/IN/O Xavi/Xavi/NNP/PERSON ./././O
In/in/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O next/next/JJ/O game/game/NN/O in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION at/at/IN/O home/home/NN/O to/to/TO/O Granada/Granada/NNP/PERSON Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O fifth/fifth/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 5/5/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O ./././O
He/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O notably/notably/RB/O criticised/criticise/VBN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O public/public/JJ/O media/media/NNS/O -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O who/who/WP/O ?/?/./O -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O
for/for/IN/O not/not/RB/O celebrating/celebrate/VBG/O the/the/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 22/22/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER penalties/penalty/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Athletic/Athletic/NNP/ORGANIZATION Bilbao/Bilbao/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O on/on/IN/O 28/28/CD/DATE January/January/NNP/DATE scored/score/VBD/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL and/and/CC/O winning/winning/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Zaragoza/Zaragoza/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON also/also/RB/O scored/score/VBD/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O against/against/IN/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O Copa/Copa/NNP/O del/del/NNP/O Rey/Rey/NNP/MISC Quarter-finals/quarter-final/NNS/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O Real/Real/NNP/O lost/lose/VBD/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER on/on/IN/O aggregrate/aggregrate/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 12/12/CD/DATE February/February/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O ,/,/,/O his/he/PRP$/O thirteenth/thirteenth/NN/ORDINAL in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O fourteenth/fourteenth/JJ/ORDINAL for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER home/home/NN/O win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Levante/Levante/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
This/this/DT/O win/win/VBP/O stretched/stretch/VBN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O lead/lead/NN/O over/over/IN/O second-placed/second-placed/JJ/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION to/to/TO/O 10/10/CD/NUMBER points/point/NNS/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 24/24/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON reached/reach/VBD/O more/more/JJR/O than/than/IN/O 100/100/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O just/just/RB/O three/three/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O at/at/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION when/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O scored/score/VBD/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O two/two/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O match/match/NN/O against/against/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Sociedad/Sociedad/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL quickest/quickest/JJS/O La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O to/to/TO/O reach/reach/VB/O that/that/DT/O milestone/milestone/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O league/league/NN/O after/after/IN/O Isidro/Isidro/NNP/PERSON Lángara/Lángara/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O reaching/reach/VBG/O the/the/DT/O milestone/milestone/NN/O in/in/IN/O 92/92/CD/NUMBER matches/match/NNS/O and/and/CC/O breaking/break/VBG/O the/the/DT/O previous/previous/JJ/O club/club/NN/O record/record/NN/O held/hold/VBN/O by/by/IN/O Puskás/Puskás/NNP/PERSON ./././O
As/as/IN/O of/of/IN/O 24/24/CD/DATE March/March/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O averaged/average/VBN/O 1.01/1.01/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O per/per/IN/O game/game/NN/O in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 11/11/CD/DATE April/April/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O a/a/DT/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O against/against/IN/O Atletico/Atletico/NNP/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 4/4/CD/NUMBER win/win/VB/O ,/,/,/O as/as/RB/O well/well/RB/O as/as/IN/O assisting/assist/VBG/O the/the/DT/O last/last/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O ./././O
His/he/PRP$/O hat-trick/hat-trick/NN/O ,/,/,/O one/one/CD/NUMBER goal/goal/NN/O from/from/IN/O a/a/DT/O free/free/JJ/O kick/kick/NN/O ,/,/,/O one/one/CD/NUMBER from/from/IN/O 30/30/CD/NUMBER yards/yard/NNS/O on/on/IN/O the/the/DT/O left/left/JJ/O wing/wing/NN/O and/and/CC/O one/one/CD/NUMBER penalty/penalty/NN/O ,/,/,/O gave/give/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O 40/40/CD/NUMBER league/league/NN/O goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O making/make/VBG/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O only/only/JJ/O player/player/NN/O in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/O Liga/Liga/NNP/O history/history/NN/O ,/,/,/O or/or/CC/O in/in/IN/O any/any/DT/O other/other/JJ/O major/major/JJ/O European/european/JJ/LOCATION league/league/NN/O ,/,/,/O to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER 40/40/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O two/two/CD/NUMBER seasons/season/NNS/O ,/,/,/O even/even/RB/O doing/do/VBG/O so/so/RB/O in/in/IN/O consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O seasons/season/NNS/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON officially/officially/RB/O broke/break/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O previous/previous/JJ/O record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O 40/40/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O La/La/NNP/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION season/season/NN/O on/on/IN/O 14/14/CD/DATE April/April/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O scoring/score/VBG/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O against/against/IN/O Sporting/Sporting/NNP/ORGANIZATION Gijón/Gijón/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
On/on/IN/O 13/13/CD/DATE May/May/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O the/the/DT/O last/last/JJ/O matchday/matchday/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O against/against/IN/O Mallorca/Mallorca/NNP/LOCATION which/which/WDT/O made/make/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL player/player/NN/O ever/ever/RB/O to/to/TO/O score/score/NN/NUMBER against/against/IN/O every/every/DT/O team/team/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O single/single/JJ/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O La/La/NNP/LOCATION Liga/Liga/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O finished/finish/VBD/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O total/total/NN/O of/of/IN/O 46/46/CD/NUMBER league/league/NN/O goals/goal/NNS/O and/and/CC/O 60/60/CD/NUMBER goals/goal/NNS/O in/in/IN/O every/every/DT/O competition/competition/NN/O ,/,/,/O breaking/break/VBG/O the/the/DT/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION record/record/NN/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O set/set/VBN/O the/the/DT/O previous/previous/JJ/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
In/in/IN/O May/May/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON claimed/claim/VBD/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O believed/believe/VBD/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O had/have/VBD/O played/play/VBN/O better/better/JJR/O than/than/IN/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON this/this/DT/O season/season/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O on/on/IN/O 13/13/CD/DATE June/June/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O he/he/PRP/O won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Trofeo/Trofeo/NNP/O Alfredo/Alfredo/NNP/PERSON Di/Di/NNP/PERSON Stefano/Stefano/NNP/PERSON as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O best/best/JJS/O La/la/NN/ORGANIZATION Liga/Liga/NNP/ORGANIZATION player/player/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O ./././O
2012/2012/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 13/13/CD/NUMBER season/season/NN/O On/on/IN/O 23/23/CD/DATE August/August/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O against/against/IN/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2012/2012/CD/DATE Supercopa/Supercopa/NNP/MISC de/de/IN/MISC España/España/NNP/MISC at/at/IN/MISC Camp/Camp/NNP/MISC Nou/Nou/NNP/MISC ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O made/make/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL Madrid/Madrid/NNP/LOCATION player/player/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O history/history/NN/O of/of/IN/O El/El/NNP/LOCATION Clásico/Clásico/NNP/LOCATION to/to/TO/O score/score/VB/NUMBER for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O fourth/fourth/JJ/ORDINAL game/game/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O row/row/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O Camp/Camp/NNP/MISC Nou/Nou/NNP/MISC ./././O
Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION won/win/VBD/O the/the/DT/O return/return/NN/O leg/leg/NN/O at/at/IN/O Santiago/Santiago/NNP/LOCATION Bernabéu/Bernabéu/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O with/with/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scoring/score/VBG/O the/the/DT/O winning/win/VBG/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 2/2/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O ./././O
With/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL leg/leg/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON equalled/equal/VBD/O the/the/DT/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION record/record/NN/O of/of/IN/O Iván/Iván/NNP/PERSON Zamorano/Zamorano/NNP/PERSON of/of/IN/O scoring/score/VBG/O in/in/IN/O five/five/CD/NUMBER consecutive/consecutive/JJ/O El/El/NNP/O Clásico/Clásico/NNP/O matches/match/VBZ/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O second/second/JJ/ORDINAL -LRB-/-lrb-/-LRB-/O tied/tie/VBN/O with/with/IN/O Lionel/Lionel/NNP/PERSON Messi/Messi/NNP/PERSON -RRB-/-rrb-/-RRB-/O in/in/IN/O the/the/DT/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION Best/best/JJS/O Player/Player/NNP/O in/in/IN/O Europe/Europe/NNP/LOCATION Award/award/NN/O ,/,/,/O behind/behind/IN/O Andrés/Andrés/NNP/PERSON Iniesta/Iniesta/NNP/PERSON ./././O
On/on/IN/O 2/2/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE 2012/2012/CD/DATE ,/,/,/O Cristiano/Cristiano/NNP/PERSON Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON scored/score/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O first/first/JJ/ORDINAL league/league/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O season/season/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 3/3/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER win/win/VBP/O over/over/IN/O Granada/Granada/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O which/which/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O also/also/RB/O his/he/PRP$/O 200th/200th/JJ/O career/career/NN/O goal/goal/NN/O in/in/IN/O league/league/NN/O matches/match/VBZ/O played/play/VBN/O in/in/IN/O England/England/NNP/LOCATION ,/,/,/O Spain/Spain/NNP/LOCATION and/and/CC/O Portugal/Portugal/NNP/LOCATION ./././O
He/he/PRP/O added/add/VBD/O another/another/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O which/which/WDT/O was/be/VBD/O his/he/PRP$/O 150th/150th/JJ/O goal/goal/NN/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O in/in/IN/O 149/149/CD/NUMBER matches/match/NNS/O played/play/VBD/O ./././O
This/this/DT/O goal/goal/NN/O made/make/VBD/O him/he/PRP/O the/the/DT/O 10th/10th/JJ/ORDINAL highest/highest/JJS/O scorer/scorer/NN/O for/for/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION in/in/IN/O all/all/DT/O competitions/competition/NNS/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON was/be/VBD/O substituted/substitute/VBN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O 63rd/63rd/JJ/ORDINAL minute/minute/NN/DURATION by/by/IN/O team/team/NN/O mate/mate/NN/O Gonzalo/Gonzalo/NNP/PERSON Higuain/Higuain/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O due/due/JJ/O to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O minor/minor/JJ/O thigh/thigh/NN/O injury/injury/NN/O ./././O
After/after/IN/O the/the/DT/O match/match/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON claimed/claim/VBD/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O unhappy/unhappy/JJ/O with/with/IN/O a/a/DT/O ``/``/``/O professional/professional/JJ/O issue/issue/NN/O ''/''/''/O after/after/IN/O he/he/PRP/O refused/refuse/VBD/O to/to/TO/O celebrate/celebrate/VB/O his/he/PRP$/O 149th/149th/NN/O and/and/CC/O 150th/150th/NN/O goals/goal/NNS/O for/for/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O ./././O
Several/several/JJ/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O teammates/teammate/NNS/O claimed/claim/VBD/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON had/have/VBD/O the/the/DT/O full/full/JJ/O support/support/NN/O of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O team/team/NN/O ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O agent/agent/NN/O ,/,/,/O Jorge/Jorge/NNP/PERSON Mendes/Mendes/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O insisted/insist/VBD/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O always/always/RB/O knew/know/VBD/O about/about/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O client/client/NN/O 's/'s/POS/O admission/admission/NN/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O was/be/VBD/O unhappy/unhappy/JJ/O with/with/IN/O life/life/NN/O at/at/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON dismissed/dismiss/VBD/O the/the/DT/O notion/notion/NN/O that/that/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O post-match/post-match/JJ/O declaration/declaration/NN/O of/of/IN/O ``/``/``/O sadness/sadness/NN/O ''/''/''/O was/be/VBD/O related/relate/VBN/O to/to/TO/O a/a/DT/O desire/desire/NN/O for/for/IN/O a/a/DT/O new/new/JJ/O and/and/CC/O improved/improve/VBN/O contract/contract/NN/O at/at/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O ./././O
Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION president/president/NN/O ,/,/,/O Florentino/Florentino/NNP/PERSON Perez/Perez/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O claimed/claim/VBD/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON did/do/VBD/O not/not/RB/O want/want/VB/O to/to/TO/O leave/leave/VB/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O that/that/IN/O he/he/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O unhappy/unhappy/JJ/O for/for/IN/O other/other/JJ/O reasons/reason/NNS/O ./././O
Former/former/JJ/O Barcelona/Barcelona/NNP/ORGANIZATION president/president/NN/O ,/,/,/O Joan/Joan/NNP/PERSON Laporta/Laporta/NNP/PERSON ,/,/,/O stated/state/VBD/O that/that/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON is/be/VBZ/O under/under/IN/O a/a/DT/O lot/lot/NN/O of/of/IN/O pressure/pressure/NN/O and/and/CC/O would/would/MD/O not/not/RB/O have/have/VB/O realized/realize/VBN/O the/the/DT/O impact/impact/NN/O of/of/IN/O his/he/PRP$/O revelation/revelation/NN/O ./././O
When/when/WRB/O he/he/PRP/O returned/return/VBD/O to/to/TO/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION ,/,/,/O after/after/IN/O international/international/JJ/O duty/duty/NN/O ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON stated/state/VBD/O he/he/PRP/O is/be/VBZ/O focused/focus/VBN/O on/on/IN/O achieving/achieve/VBG/O further/further/JJ/O success/success/NN/O with/with/IN/O the/the/DT/O club/club/NN/O ./././O
Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION coach/coach/NN/O José/José/NNP/PERSON Mourinho/Mourinho/NNP/PERSON stated/state/VBD/O ``/``/``/O If/if/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON is/be/VBZ/O sad/sad/JJ/O but/but/CC/O plays/play/VBZ/O like/like/IN/O he/he/PRP/O does/do/VBZ/O ,/,/,/O that/that/DT/O 's/be/VBZ/O perfect/perfect/JJ/O for/for/IN/O me/I/PRP/O ''/''/''/O ,/,/,/O and/and/CC/O believed/believe/VBD/O that/that/IN/O UEFA/UEFA/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O decision/decision/NN/O to/to/TO/O elect/elect/VB/O Iniesta/Iniesta/NNP/PERSON as/as/IN/O the/the/DT/O best/best/JJS/O player/player/NN/O in/in/IN/O Europe/Europe/NNP/LOCATION in/in/IN/O 2011/2011/CD/DATE --/--/:/O 12/12/CD/NUMBER could/could/MD/O have/have/VB/O been/be/VBN/O one/one/CD/NUMBER of/of/IN/O the/the/DT/O reasons/reason/NNS/O behind/behind/IN/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON 's/'s/POS/O unhappiness/unhappiness/NN/O ./././O
On/on/IN/O 15/15/CD/DATE September/September/NNP/DATE ,/,/,/O Ronaldo/Ronaldo/NNP/PERSON appeared/appear/VBD/O in/in/IN/O Real/real/JJ/ORGANIZATION Madrid/Madrid/NNP/ORGANIZATION 's/'s/POS/O fourth/fourth/JJ/ORDINAL league/league/NN/O match/match/NN/O in/in/IN/O a/a/DT/O 1/1/CD/NUMBER --/--/:/O 0/0/CD/NUMBER away/away/RB/O loss/loss/NN/O against/against/IN/O Sevilla/Sevilla/NNP/ORGANIZATION ./././O
