The/O story/O follows/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON 's/O third/O year/O at/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION as/O he/O is/O informed/O that/O a/O prisoner/O named/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION has/O escaped/O from/O Azkaban/LOCATION and/O wants/O to/O murder/O him/O ./O 
The/O film/O stars/O Daniel/PERSON Radcliffe/PERSON as/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON ,/O alongside/O Rupert/PERSON Grint/PERSON and/O Emma/PERSON Watson/PERSON as/O Harry/PERSON 's/O best/O friends/O Ron/PERSON Weasley/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON Granger/PERSON ./O 
It/O is/O the/O sequel/O to/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Chamber/O of/O Secrets/O and/O is/O followed/O by/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Goblet/O of/O Fire/O ./O 
The/O film/O was/O released/O on/O 31/O May/O 2004/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION and/O on/O 4/O June/O 2004/O in/O North/LOCATION America/LOCATION ,/O as/O the/O first/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON film/O released/O into/O IMAX/O theaters/O and/O to/O be/O using/O IMAX/O Technology/O ./O 
It/O is/O also/O the/O last/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON film/O to/O be/O released/O on/O VHS/O as/O well/O as/O the/O last/O film/O until/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Half-Blood/O Prince/O to/O be/O rated/O PG/O in/O North/LOCATION America/LOCATION ./O 
The/O film/O was/O nominated/O for/O two/O Academy/O Awards/O --/O Original/O Music/O Score/O and/O Visual/O Effects/O --/O at/O the/O 77th/O Academy/O Awards/O in/O 2005/O ./O 
While/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O grossed/O a/O total/O of/O $/O 796.6/O million/O worldwide/O ,/O its/O box/O office/O performance/O ranks/O as/O the/O lowest-grossing/O in/O the/O series/O ./O 
Nonetheless/O ,/O it/O currently/O stands/O as/O the/O thirty-ninth/O highest-grossing/O film/O of/O all-time/O ./O 
Plot/O Now/O 13/O years/O old/O ,/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON has/O been/O spending/O the/O summer/O at/O Privet/LOCATION Drive/LOCATION ,/O absorbing/O most/O of/O his/O time/O studying/O new/O spells/O ./O 
When/O Uncle/O Vernon/PERSON 's/O sister/O ,/O Marge/PERSON ,/O comes/O for/O a/O visit/O and/O infuriates/O Harry/PERSON by/O insulting/O his/O parents/O ,/O he/O loses/O his/O temper/O and/O accidentally/O causes/O her/O to/O inflate/O and/O fly/O away/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON then/O threatens/O to/O curse/O Vernon/PERSON when/O he/O tries/O to/O discipline/O him/O but/O flees/O ,/O fed/O up/O with/O his/O life/O at/O Privet/LOCATION Drive/LOCATION ./O 
Shortly/O after/O seeing/O a/O large/O black/O dog/O watching/O him/O ,/O the/O Knight/O Bus/O appears/O and/O delivers/O Harry/PERSON to/O the/O Leaky/O Cauldron/O ,/O where/O Minister/O of/O Magic/PERSON Cornelius/PERSON Fudge/PERSON tells/O him/O he/O will/O not/O be/O arrested/O for/O the/O use/O of/O magic/O on/O his/O aunt/O ./O 
After/O reuniting/O with/O Ron/PERSON ,/O and/O Hermione/PERSON ,/O Harry/PERSON learns/O that/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION ,/O a/O convicted/O supporter/O of/O Lord/O Voldemort/PERSON ,/O has/O escaped/O Azkaban/O prison/O and/O is/O likely/O intending/O to/O kill/O Harry/PERSON ./O 
Harry/PERSON ,/O Ron/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON head/O back/O to/O school/O on/O the/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION Express/ORGANIZATION ./O 
They/O unknowingly/O share/O a/O compartment/O with/O the/O new/O Defense/O Against/O the/O Dark/O Arts/O teacher/O ,/O Remus/PERSON Lupin/PERSON ,/O who/O is/O sleeping/O ./O 
When/O the/O train/O abruptly/O stops/O ,/O Dementors/O board/O ,/O searching/O for/O Black/PERSON because/O Harry/PERSON mentioned/O his/O name/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O Dementors/O enters/O their/O compartment/O ,/O prompting/O Harry/PERSON to/O pass/O out/O whilst/O under/O the/O impression/O of/O a/O woman/O screaming/O ./O 
At/O this/O time/O ,/O Lupin/PERSON awakes/O and/O repels/O the/O Dementor/O with/O a/O Patronus/O Charm/O ./O 
At/O Hogwarts/LOCATION ,/O Albus/PERSON Dumbledore/PERSON informs/O students/O that/O the/O Dementors/O will/O be/O guarding/O the/O school/O while/O Black/O is/O at/O large/O ./O 
Professor/O Lupin/PERSON is/O introduced/O ,/O and/O Hagrid/PERSON is/O announced/O as/O the/O new/O Care/O of/O Magical/O Creatures/O teacher/O ./O 
Lupin/PERSON 's/O lessons/O prove/O enjoyable/O ;/O he/O focuses/O on/O practice/O ,/O not/O just/O theory/O ,/O and/O encourages/O less/O confident/O students/O such/O as/O Neville/PERSON when/O he/O faces/O a/O boggart/O in/O the/O form/O of/O his/O worst/O fear/O ,/O Professor/O Snape/PERSON ./O 
However/O ,/O Hagrid/PERSON 's/O first/O class/O goes/O awry/O when/O Draco/PERSON Malfoy/PERSON deliberately/O provokes/O the/O Hippogriff/O ,/O Buckbeak/PERSON ,/O who/O then/O attacks/O him/O ./O 
Draco/PERSON 's/O father/O Lucius/PERSON Malfoy/PERSON has/O Buckbeak/PERSON sentenced/O to/O death/O on/O court/O ./O 
Later/O the/O trio/O find/O a/O crowd/O at/O the/O door/O to/O their/O dormitory/O ,/O and/O The/O Fat/O Lady/O missing/O from/O her/O portrait/O ./O 
She/O is/O located/O in/O a/O different/O picture/O ,/O and/O she/O tells/O Dumbledore/PERSON that/O Black/PERSON has/O entered/O the/O castle/O ./O 
Filch/O ,/O Lupin/PERSON and/O Snape/PERSON secure/O and/O search/O the/O castle/O ,/O but/O they/O find/O no/O one/O ./O 
As/O the/O Gryffindor/O Dormitory/O has/O been/O compromised/O ,/O the/O students/O sleep/O in/O the/O main/O hall/O which/O allows/O Harry/PERSON to/O overhear/O an/O argument/O between/O Snape/PERSON and/O Dumbledore/PERSON about/O Lupin/PERSON 's/O suspected/O role/O ./O 
During/O a/O stormy/O Quidditch/O match/O ,/O several/O Dementors/O approach/O and/O overpower/O Harry/PERSON ,/O causing/O him/O to/O fall/O off/O his/O broomstick/O ,/O which/O is/O then/O destroyed/O by/O the/O Whomping/O Willow/O ./O 
Lupin/PERSON secretly/O teaches/O Harry/PERSON to/O defend/O himself/O against/O Dementors/O using/O the/O Patronus/O charm/O ./O 
As/O Harry/PERSON lacks/O parental/O permission/O to/O visit/O Hogsmeade/PERSON ,/O Fred/PERSON and/O George/PERSON -LRB-/O who/O intercept/O him/O despite/O his/O invisible/O cloak/O due/O to/O his/O footprints/O in/O the/O snow/O -RRB-/O give/O him/O their/O Marauder/O 's/O Map/O ,/O a/O magical/O document/O showing/O every/O person/O 's/O location/O within/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION ,/O as/O well/O as/O secret/O passageways/O in/O and/O out/O of/O the/O school/O castle/O ./O 
At/O Hogsmeade/LOCATION ,/O Harry/PERSON notices/O Fudge/O and/O Madam/PERSON Rosmerta/PERSON ,/O discussing/O Black/O ./O 
He/O follows/O them/O after/O he/O hears/O mentioning/O his/O name/O ,/O and/O overhears/O that/O Black/PERSON is/O his/O godfather/O and/O was/O his/O parents/O '/O best/O friend/O ./O 
Black/O was/O accused/O of/O divulging/O the/O Potters/O '/O secret/O whereabouts/O to/O Voldemort/PERSON and/O murdering/O their/O mutual/O friend/O Peter/PERSON Pettigrew/PERSON by/O blowing/O him/O up/O ./O 
Out/O of/O anger/O ,/O Harry/PERSON vows/O to/O avenge/O his/O parents/O ,/O and/O kill/O Black/PERSON ./O 
Late/O at/O night/O ,/O Harry/PERSON is/O reading/O the/O Marauder/O 's/O map/O ,/O when/O he/O notices/O Peter/PERSON Pettigrew/PERSON 's/O name/O on/O it/O ./O 
He/O exits/O the/O dormitory/O and/O follows/O him/O ./O 
He/O follows/O Pettigrew/PERSON ,/O on/O the/O map/O ,/O but/O is/O unable/O to/O see/O him/O anywhere/O ./O 
He/O instead/O sees/O Snape/PERSON on/O the/O map/O ,/O but/O fails/O to/O avoid/O him/O ./O 
Snape/PERSON initially/O confiscates/O the/O map/O ,/O but/O hands/O it/O over/O to/O Lupin/O who/O arrives/O to/O take/O Harry/PERSON to/O his/O classroom/O ,/O keeping/O the/O map/O and/O admonishing/O Harry/PERSON for/O wandering/O the/O castle/O while/O Black/O is/O at/O large/O ./O 
Before/O leaving/O ,/O Harry/PERSON mentions/O to/O Lupin/O seeing/O Pettigrew/PERSON on/O the/O map/O ,/O leaving/O Lupin/O astonished/O ./O 
After/O a/O class/O of/O Divination/O ,/O Professor/O Trelawney/PERSON enters/O a/O trance/O and/O predicts/O that/O the/O Dark/O Lord/O 's/O servant/O will/O return/O that/O night/O ./O 
Later/O ,/O Harry/PERSON ,/O Ron/PERSON ,/O and/O Hermione/PERSON visit/O Hagrid/PERSON to/O console/O him/O over/O Buckbeak/PERSON 's/O impending/O execution/O ./O 
While/O there/O ,/O they/O discover/O Scabbers/O ,/O Ron/PERSON 's/O missing/O rat/O ./O 
Fudge/O ,/O Dumbledore/PERSON ,/O and/O an/O executioner/O arrive/O at/O Hagrid/ORGANIZATION 's/O to/O carry/O out/O Buckbeak/PERSON 's/O execution/O ,/O and/O the/O three/O students/O hurry/O away/O to/O avoid/O being/O discovered/O ./O 
Scabbers/O suddenly/O bites/O Ron/PERSON ,/O escaping/O ,/O and/O as/O the/O trio/O chase/O him/O a/O large/O dog/O appears/O and/O drags/O both/O Ron/PERSON and/O Scabbers/O into/O a/O hole/O at/O the/O Whomping/O Willow/O 's/O base/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON are/O attacked/O by/O the/O tree/O but/O also/O manage/O to/O enter/O the/O underground/O passage/O to/O the/O Shrieking/O Shack/O ./O 
There/O they/O discover/O that/O the/O dog/O is/O actually/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION ,/O who/O is/O an/O Animagus/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON attacks/O Black/O ,/O but/O Lupin/PERSON arrives/O and/O disarms/O Harry/PERSON ./O 
After/O exchanging/O a/O few/O cryptic/O words/O with/O Black/PERSON ,/O Lupin/PERSON then/O embraces/O him/O as/O an/O old/O friend/O ./O 
When/O confronted/O by/O Hermione/PERSON ,/O Lupin/PERSON admits/O to/O being/O a/O werewolf/O ,/O and/O he/O and/O Black/PERSON begin/O to/O explain/O that/O Black/PERSON is/O innocent/O ./O 
Professor/O Snape/PERSON bursts/O in/O ,/O intending/O to/O hand/O over/O Black/O to/O the/O Dementors/O ,/O but/O Harry/PERSON ,/O having/O doubts/O ,/O knocks/O him/O out/O with/O a/O spell/O ./O 
Lupin/PERSON and/O Black/PERSON explain/O that/O Scabbers/O is/O actually/O Peter/PERSON Pettigrew/PERSON ,/O an/O Animagus/O who/O committed/O the/O crime/O for/O which/O Black/PERSON was/O convicted/O ./O 
Lupin/PERSON and/O Black/PERSON force/O Pettigrew/PERSON back/O into/O his/O human/O form/O preparing/O to/O kill/O him/O ,/O but/O Harry/PERSON intervenes/O saying/O that/O his/O father/O would/O not/O have/O wanted/O his/O two/O best/O friends/O to/O become/O killers/O ./O 
Pettigrew/PERSON is/O instead/O to/O be/O turned/O over/O to/O the/O Dementors/O ./O 
As/O the/O group/O heads/O to/O the/O castle/O ,/O the/O full/O moon/O rises/O ;/O Lupin/O transforms/O into/O a/O werewolf/O ,/O and/O Pettigrew/PERSON manages/O to/O escape/O in/O the/O confusion/O ./O 
Lupin/PERSON and/O Black/O fight/O in/O their/O animal/O forms/O ,/O until/O Lupin/PERSON is/O distracted/O by/O another/O animal/O 's/O howls/O ./O 
Dementors/O attack/O Black/O and/O Harry/PERSON ./O 
As/O Dementors/O are/O preparing/O to/O suck/O out/O their/O souls/O and/O perform/O the/O Dementor/O 's/O Kiss/O ,/O Harry/PERSON sees/O a/O distant/O figure/O cast/O a/O powerful/O stag-shaped/O Patronus/O that/O scatters/O the/O Dementors/O ,/O and/O sends/O them/O away/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON believes/O the/O mysterious/O figure/O is/O his/O dead/O father/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON passes/O out/O from/O the/O trauma/O ,/O and/O awakens/O to/O find/O he/O is/O in/O Hogwarts/LOCATION and/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION has/O been/O captured/O ./O 
Acting/O on/O advice/O from/O Dumbledore/PERSON ,/O Hermione/PERSON reveals/O that/O she/O possesses/O a/O time-turner/O that/O she/O has/O used/O all/O year/O to/O take/O multiple/O classes/O simultaneously/O ./O 
She/O and/O Harry/PERSON travel/O back/O in/O time/O three/O hours/O ,/O watching/O themselves/O repeat/O that/O night/O 's/O events/O ./O 
They/O free/O Buckbeak/O ,/O and/O return/O to/O the/O Whomping/O Willow/O ./O 
As/O the/O Dementors/O overpower/O Black/PERSON and/O his/O earlier/O self/O ,/O Harry/PERSON realizes/O that/O he/O himself/O was/O the/O one/O to/O cast/O the/O Patronus/O ,/O and/O rushes/O to/O do/O so/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON then/O rescue/O Black/PERSON ,/O who/O escapes/O on/O Buckbeak/O ,/O commenting/O that/O they/O are/O both/O now/O fugitives/O ./O 
Lupin/PERSON resigns/O the/O next/O day/O ,/O knowing/O that/O parents/O will/O object/O to/O a/O werewolf/O teaching/O their/O children/O ./O 
Shortly/O after/O ,/O Black/PERSON anonymously/O sends/O Harry/PERSON a/O Firebolt/O ,/O the/O fastest/O racing/O broom/O ever/O made/O ./O 
Cast/O Daniel/PERSON Radcliffe/PERSON as/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON Rupert/PERSON Grint/PERSON as/O Ron/PERSON Weasley/PERSON ,/O Harry/PERSON 's/O best/O friend/O ./O 
Emma/PERSON Watson/PERSON as/O Hermione/PERSON Granger/PERSON ,/O Harry/PERSON 's/O other/O best/O friend/O and/O the/O brains/O of/O the/O trio/O ./O 
Robbie/PERSON Coltrane/PERSON as/O Rubeus/PERSON Hagrid/PERSON ,/O the/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION gamekeeper/O and/O the/O new/O Care/O of/O Magical/O Creatures/O teacher/O ./O 
Michael/PERSON Gambon/PERSON as/O Albus/PERSON Dumbledore/PERSON ,/O the/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION Headmaster/O ./O 
Gambon/PERSON assumed/O the/O role/O after/O Richard/PERSON Harris/PERSON ,/O who/O played/O Dumbledore/PERSON in/O the/O previous/O two/O films/O ,/O died/O on/O 25/O October/O 2002/O ./O 
Despite/O his/O illness/O ,/O Harris/PERSON was/O determined/O to/O film/O his/O part/O ,/O telling/O a/O visiting/O David/PERSON Heyman/PERSON not/O to/O recast/O the/O role/O ./O 
Four/O months/O after/O Harris/PERSON 's/O death/O ,/O Cuarón/PERSON chose/O Gambon/PERSON as/O his/O replacement/O ./O 
Gambon/PERSON was/O unconcerned/O with/O bettering/O or/O copying/O Harris/PERSON ,/O instead/O giving/O his/O own/O interpretation/O ,/O putting/O on/O a/O slight/O Irish/O accent/O for/O the/O role/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O completing/O his/O scenes/O in/O three/O weeks/O ./O 
Rumours/O of/O Ian/PERSON McKellen/PERSON being/O offered/O the/O role/O started/O to/O spread/O ,/O but/O when/O confronted/O ,/O he/O turned/O the/O rumors/O down/O ,/O stating/O that/O he/O has/O played/O a/O similar/O character/O in/O Gandalf/O of/O The/O Lord/O of/O the/O Rings/O trilogy/O ./O 
He/O also/O stated/O it/O would/O have/O been/O inappropriate/O to/O take/O Harris/PERSON '/O role/O ,/O as/O the/O late/O actor/O had/O called/O McKellen/PERSON a/O ``/O dreadful/O ''/O actor/O ./O 
Harris/PERSON 's/O family/O had/O expressed/O an/O interest/O in/O seeing/O Harris/PERSON 's/O close/O friend/O Peter/PERSON O'Toole/PERSON being/O chosen/O as/O his/O replacement/O ./O 
Richard/PERSON Griffiths/PERSON as/O Vernon/PERSON Dursley/PERSON ,/O Harry/PERSON 's/O Muggle/O uncle/O ./O 
Gary/PERSON Oldman/PERSON as/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION ,/O an/O escapee/O from/O the/O Wizarding/O prison/O Azkaban/O and/O Harry/PERSON 's/O godfather/O ./O 
Oldman/PERSON accepted/O the/O part/O because/O he/O needed/O the/O money/O ,/O as/O he/O had/O not/O taken/O on/O any/O major/O work/O in/O several/O years/O as/O he/O had/O decided/O to/O spend/O more/O time/O with/O his/O children/O ./O 
He/O drew/O inspiration/O from/O Cuarón/LOCATION ,/O whom/O he/O described/O as/O having/O ``/O such/O enthusiasm/O and/O a/O joy/O for/O life/O ,/O ''/O and/O compared/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION to/O John/PERSON Lennon/PERSON ./O 
He/O was/O ``/O surprised/O by/O how/O difficult/O it/O was/O to/O pull/O off/O ''/O ,/O comparing/O the/O role/O to/O Shakespearean/O dialogue/O ./O 
Oldman/PERSON suggested/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION 's/O hairstyle/O ,/O while/O Cuarón/PERSON designed/O his/O tattoos/O ./O 
He/O had/O read/O the/O first/O book/O ,/O and/O his/O children/O were/O fans/O of/O the/O series/O ./O 
The/O part/O made/O Oldman/PERSON a/O hero/O with/O his/O children/O and/O their/O schoolmates/O ./O 
Fiona/PERSON Shaw/PERSON as/O Petunia/PERSON Dursley/PERSON ,/O Harry/PERSON 's/O Muggle/O aunt/O ./O 
Maggie/PERSON Smith/PERSON as/O Minerva/PERSON McGonagall/PERSON ,/O the/O Transfiguration/O teacher/O at/O Hogwarts/LOCATION ./O 
Timothy/PERSON Spall/PERSON as/O Peter/PERSON Pettigrew/PERSON ,/O a/O friend/O of/O Harry/PERSON 's/O parents/O said/O to/O have/O been/O killed/O by/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Thewlis/PERSON ,/O who/O had/O previously/O auditioned/O for/O the/O role/O of/O Professor/O Quirrell/PERSON in/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Philosopher/O 's/O Stone/O ,/O was/O Cuarón/PERSON 's/O first/O choice/O for/O the/O role/O of/O Lupin/O ./O 
He/O accepted/O the/O role/O on/O advice/O from/O Ian/PERSON Hart/PERSON ,/O the/O man/O who/O was/O cast/O as/O Quirrell/PERSON ,/O who/O told/O him/O that/O Lupin/PERSON was/O ``/O the/O best/O part/O in/O the/O book/O ./O ''/O 
Cuarón/PERSON told/O Thewlis/PERSON that/O he/O thought/O Lupin/PERSON was/O gay/O ,/O pitching/O him/O as/O a/O ``/O gay/O junkie/O ''/O ,/O although/O his/O idea/O turned/O out/O to/O be/O incorrect/O ./O 
Thewlis/PERSON had/O seen/O the/O first/O two/O films/O and/O had/O only/O read/O part/O of/O the/O first/O book/O ,/O although/O after/O taking/O the/O role/O he/O read/O the/O third/O ./O 
He/O was/O excited/O about/O the/O prospect/O of/O making/O a/O children/O 's/O film/O ,/O and/O thoroughly/O enjoyed/O filming/O ./O 
Emma/PERSON Thompson/PERSON as/O Sybill/PERSON Trelawney/PERSON ,/O the/O Divination/O teacher/O at/O Hogwarts/LOCATION ./O 
Julie/PERSON Walters/PERSON as/O Molly/PERSON Weasley/PERSON ,/O the/O Weasley/PERSON matriarch/O and/O a/O mother/O figure/O to/O Harry/PERSON ./O 
Production/O Development/O With/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O ,/O production/O of/O the/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON films/O switched/O to/O an/O eighteen-month/O cycle/O ,/O which/O producer/O David/PERSON Heyman/PERSON explained/O was/O ``/O to/O give/O each/O -LRB-/O film/O -RRB-/O the/O time/O it/O required/O ./O 
``/O Chris/PERSON Columbus/PERSON ,/O the/O director/O of/O the/O previous/O two/O films/O ,/O decided/O not/O to/O return/O and/O helm/O the/O third/O instalment/O as/O he/O ``/O had/O n't/O seen/O -LRB-/O his/O -RRB-/O own/O kids/O for/O supper/O in/O the/O week/O for/O about/O two/O and/O a/O half/O years/O ./O ''/O 
Even/O so/O ,/O he/O remained/O on/O as/O a/O producer/O alongside/O Heyman/PERSON ./O 
Guillermo/PERSON del/PERSON Toro/PERSON was/O approached/O to/O direct/O ,/O but/O considered/O the/O film/O ``/O so/O bright/O and/O happy/O and/O full/O of/O light/O ,/O that/O -LRB-/O he/O -RRB-/O was/O n't/O interested/O ./O 
``/O Marc/PERSON Forster/PERSON turned/O down/O the/O film/O because/O he/O had/O made/O Finding/O Neverland/O and/O did/O not/O want/O to/O direct/O child/O actors/O again/O ./O 
Warner/ORGANIZATION Bros./ORGANIZATION then/O composed/O a/O three-name/O short/O list/O for/O Columbus/LOCATION 's/O replacement/O ,/O which/O comprised/O Callie/PERSON Khouri/PERSON ,/O Kenneth/PERSON Branagh/PERSON -LRB-/O who/O played/O Gilderoy/PERSON Lockhart/PERSON in/O Chamber/O of/O Secrets/O -RRB-/O and/O eventual/O selection/O Alfonso/PERSON Cuarón/PERSON ./O 
Cuarón/PERSON was/O initially/O nervous/O about/O accepting/O as/O he/O had/O not/O read/O any/O of/O the/O books/O ,/O or/O seen/O the/O films/O ./O 
After/O reading/O the/O series/O ,/O he/O changed/O his/O mind/O and/O signed/O on/O to/O direct/O ,/O as/O he/O had/O immediately/O connected/O to/O the/O story/O ./O 
Cuarón/PERSON 's/O appointment/O pleased/O J./PERSON K./PERSON Rowling/PERSON who/O loved/O his/O film/O Y/O tu/O mamá/O también/O and/O was/O impressed/O with/O his/O adaptation/O of/O A/O Little/O Princess/O ./O 
Heyman/PERSON found/O that/O ``/O tonally/O and/O stylistically/O ,/O -LRB-/O Cuarón/O -RRB-/O was/O the/O perfect/O fit/O ./O ''/O 
As/O his/O first/O exercise/O with/O the/O actors/O who/O portray/O the/O central/O trio/O ,/O Cuarón/PERSON assigned/O Radcliffe/PERSON ,/O Grint/PERSON and/O Watson/PERSON to/O write/O an/O autobiographical/O essay/O about/O their/O character/O ,/O written/O in/O the/O first/O person/O ,/O spanning/O birth/O to/O the/O discovery/O of/O the/O magical/O world/O ,/O and/O including/O the/O character/O 's/O emotional/O experience/O ./O 
Of/O Rupert/PERSON Grint/PERSON 's/O essay/O ,/O Cuarón/PERSON recalls/O ,/O ``/O Rupert/PERSON did/O n't/O deliver/O the/O essay/O ./O 
When/O I/O questioned/O why/O he/O did/O n't/O do/O it/O ,/O he/O said/O ,/O `/O I/O 'm/O Ron/PERSON ;/O Ron/PERSON would/O n't/O do/O it/O ./O '/O 
So/O I/O said/O ,/O `/O Okay/O ,/O you/O do/O understand/O your/O character/O ./O '/O 
That/O was/O the/O most/O important/O piece/O of/O acting/O work/O that/O we/O did/O on/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/LOCATION ,/O because/O it/O was/O very/O clear/O that/O everything/O they/O put/O in/O those/O essays/O was/O going/O to/O be/O the/O pillars/O they/O were/O going/O to/O hold/O on/O to/O for/O the/O rest/O of/O the/O process/O ./O ''/O 
Filming/O Principal/O photography/O began/O on/O 24/O February/O 2003/O ,/O at/O Leavesden/ORGANIZATION Film/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION ,/O and/O concluded/O in/O October/O 2003/O ./O 
Some/O sets/O for/O the/O film/O were/O built/O in/O Glen/PERSON Coe/PERSON ,/O Scotland/LOCATION ,/O near/O the/O Clachaig/O Inn/O ./O 
The/O indoor/O sets/O ,/O including/O ones/O built/O for/O the/O previous/O two/O films/O ,/O are/O mainly/O in/O Leavesden/ORGANIZATION Film/ORGANIZATION Studios/ORGANIZATION ./O 
The/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION Lake/ORGANIZATION was/O filmed/O from/O Loch/PERSON Shiel/PERSON ,/O Loch/PERSON Eilt/PERSON and/O Loch/PERSON Morar/PERSON in/O the/O Scottish/O Highlands/O ./O 
Incidentally/O ,/O the/O train/O bridge/O ,/O which/O was/O also/O featured/O in/O the/O Chamber/O of/O Secrets/O ,/O is/O opposite/O Loch/PERSON Shiel/PERSON and/O was/O used/O to/O film/O the/O sequences/O when/O the/O Dementor/O boarded/O the/O train/O ./O 
A/O small/O section/O of/O the/O triple-decker/O bus/O scene/O ,/O where/O it/O weaves/O in/O between/O traffic/O ,/O was/O filmed/O in/O North/LOCATION London/LOCATION 's/O Palmers/ORGANIZATION Green/ORGANIZATION ./O 
Some/O parts/O were/O also/O filmed/O in/O and/O around/O Borough/O Market/O and/O Lambeth/LOCATION Bridge/LOCATION in/O London/LOCATION ./O 
The/O Honeydukes/O set/O in/O this/O film/O is/O a/O redress/O of/O the/O set/O of/O Flourish/O &/O Blotts/O that/O was/O seen/O in/O Chamber/O of/O Secrets/O ,/O which/O ,/O in/O turn/O ,/O was/O a/O redress/O of/O the/O Ollivanders/O set/O from/O the/O first/O film/O ./O 
Rowling/PERSON allowed/O Cuarón/O to/O make/O minor/O changes/O to/O the/O book/O ,/O on/O the/O condition/O that/O he/O stuck/O to/O the/O book/O 's/O spirit/O ./O 
She/O allowed/O him/O to/O place/O a/O sundial/O on/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION '/O grounds/O ,/O but/O rejected/O a/O graveyard/O ,/O as/O that/O would/O play/O an/O important/O part/O in/O the/O then/O unreleased/O sixth/O book/O ./O 
Rowling/PERSON said/O she/O ``/O got/O goosebumps/O ''/O when/O she/O saw/O several/O moments/O in/O the/O film/O ,/O as/O they/O inadvertently/O referred/O to/O events/O in/O the/O final/O two/O books/O ,/O she/O stated/O ``/O people/O are/O going/O to/O look/O back/O on/O the/O film/O and/O think/O that/O those/O were/O put/O in/O deliberately/O as/O clues/O ./O ''/O 
When/O filming/O concluded/O ,/O Cuarón/PERSON found/O that/O it/O had/O ``/O been/O the/O two/O sweetest/O years/O of/O my/O life/O ,/O ''/O and/O expressed/O his/O interest/O in/O directing/O one/O of/O the/O sequels/O ./O 
Effects/O Cuarón/O originally/O wanted/O to/O move/O away/O from/O CGI/O toward/O puppetry/O ./O 
He/O hired/O master/O underwater/O puppeteer/O Basil/O Twist/O to/O help/O ,/O using/O puppets/O to/O study/O the/O potential/O movement/O of/O the/O Dementors/O ./O 
Once/O it/O became/O apparent/O that/O puppetry/O would/O be/O too/O expensive/O and/O unable/O to/O portray/O the/O specific/O elements/O of/O the/O Dementors/O ,/O Cuarón/PERSON turned/O to/O CGI/O ;/O however/O ,/O he/O and/O his/O team/O did/O use/O footage/O of/O Dementor/O puppets/O underwater/O as/O a/O basis/O for/O the/O flowing/O movements/O of/O the/O computer-generated/O Dementors/O ./O 
The/O Knight/O Bus/O segment/O when/O Harry/PERSON is/O being/O taken/O to/O The/O Leaky/O Cauldron/O uses/O the/O technique/O known/O as/O bullet/O time/O ,/O popularized/O in/O The/O Matrix/O series/O of/O films/O ./O 
This/O segment/O takes/O humorous/O advantage/O of/O the/O magic/O quality/O of/O the/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON world/O by/O having/O the/O Muggle/O world/O go/O into/O bullet/O time/O while/O inside/O the/O Knight/O Bus/O ,/O Harry/PERSON ,/O Stan/PERSON Shunpike/PERSON and/O Ernie/PERSON Prang/PERSON -LRB-/O and/O the/O talking/O shrunken/O head/O -RRB-/O keep/O moving/O in/O real/O time/O ./O 
Music/O The/O Academy/O Award-nominated/O score/O was/O the/O third/O and/O final/O score/O in/O the/O series/O to/O be/O composed/O and/O conducted/O by/O John/PERSON Williams/PERSON ./O 
It/O was/O released/O on/O CD/O on/O 25/O May/O 2004/O ./O 
In/O general/O ,/O this/O film/O 's/O music/O is/O not/O as/O bright/O as/O that/O of/O the/O previous/O films/O ,/O with/O distinct/O medieval/O influences/O in/O the/O instrumentation/O ./O 
One/O of/O the/O new/O themes/O ,/O ``/O Double/O Trouble/O ,/O ''/O was/O written/O during/O production/O so/O that/O a/O children/O 's/O choir/O could/O perform/O it/O in/O Hogwarts/ORGANIZATION 's/O Great/O Hall/O in/O one/O of/O the/O film/O 's/O earlier/O scenes/O ./O 
The/O lyrics/O of/O ``/O Double/O Trouble/O ''/O are/O from/O a/O ritual/O performed/O by/O the/O Weïrd/O Sisters/O in/O Act/O 4/O ,/O Scene/O 1/O of/O Shakespeare/PERSON 's/O Macbeth/O ./O 
The/O film/O 's/O trailer/O prominently/O features/O the/O cues/O ``/O Anticipation/O ''/O and/O ``/O Progeny/O ''/O by/O Brand/O X/O Music/O ./O 
Differences/O from/O the/O book/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O was/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O of/O publication/O ,/O the/O series/O '/O longest/O book/O ./O 
The/O increasing/O plot/O complexity/O necessitated/O a/O looser/O adaptation/O of/O the/O book/O 's/O finer/O plot/O lines/O and/O back-story/O ./O 
The/O film/O opens/O with/O Harry/PERSON using/O magic/O to/O light/O his/O wand/O in/O short/O bursts/O ,/O whereas/O in/O the/O same/O scene/O in/O the/O book/O ,/O he/O uses/O a/O torch/O as/O performing/O magic/O is/O illegal/O for/O wizards/O under/O the/O age/O of/O seventeen/O ./O 
Also/O in/O the/O book/O ,/O there/O is/O no/O shrunken/O head/O in/O the/O Knight/O bus/O ,/O while/O in/O the/O film/O ,/O a/O rude/O shrunken/O head/O talks/O through/O most/O of/O the/O Knight/O bus/O scene/O ./O 
The/O connection/O between/O Harry/PERSON 's/O parents/O and/O the/O Marauder/O 's/O map/O is/O only/O briefly/O mentioned/O ,/O as/O is/O Remus/PERSON Lupin/PERSON 's/O association/O to/O both/O the/O map/O and/O James/PERSON Potter/PERSON ./O 
Additionally/O ,/O it/O was/O never/O mentioned/O who/O the/O Marauders/O were/O or/O who/O the/O nicknames/O -LRB-/O Mooney/PERSON ,/O Wormtail/O ,/O Padfoot/O ,/O and/O Prongs/O -RRB-/O belonged/O to/O ./O 
Some/O exposition/O was/O removed/O for/O dramatic/O effect/O :/O both/O the/O Shrieking/O Shack/O and/O Scabbers/O the/O rat/O are/O mentioned/O only/O very/O briefly/O in/O the/O film/O ,/O while/O they/O receive/O a/O more/O thorough/O coverage/O in/O the/O novel/O ./O 
Most/O of/O Sirius/ORGANIZATION Black/ORGANIZATION 's/O back/O story/O is/O also/O cut/O ,/O with/O no/O mention/O of/O the/O manner/O of/O his/O escape/O from/O Azkaban/O ./O 
On/O account/O of/O pace/O and/O time/O considerations/O ,/O the/O film/O glosses/O over/O detailed/O descriptions/O of/O magical/O education/O ./O 
Only/O one/O Hippogriff/O ,/O Buckbeak/O ,/O is/O seen/O ,/O and/O only/O Malfoy/LOCATION and/O Harry/PERSON are/O seen/O interacting/O with/O the/O Hippogriff/O during/O Care/O of/O Magical/O Creatures/O lessons/O ,/O and/O most/O other/O lessons/O ,/O including/O all/O of/O Snape/PERSON 's/O potions/O classes/O ,/O were/O cut/O from/O the/O film/O ./O 
The/O Fidelius/O Charm/O 's/O complicated/O description/O is/O removed/O entirely/O from/O the/O film/O ,/O with/O no/O explanation/O given/O of/O exactly/O how/O Black/PERSON betrayed/O the/O Potters/O to/O Lord/O Voldemort/PERSON ./O 
Many/O of/O this/O scene/O 's/O lines/O are/O redistributed/O amongst/O Cornelius/PERSON Fudge/PERSON and/O Minerva/PERSON McGonagall/PERSON ;/O in/O compensation/O ,/O McGonagall/O 's/O exposition/O of/O the/O Animagus/O transformation/O is/O instead/O given/O by/O Snape/PERSON ./O 
In/O the/O film/O ,/O where/O Harry/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON have/O traveled/O back/O in/O time/O and/O are/O hiding/O outside/O of/O Hagrid/PERSON 's/O hut/O ,/O it/O is/O heavily/O implied/O that/O Dumbledore/PERSON somehow/O knows/O that/O they/O are/O there/O ,/O as/O he/O distracts/O the/O other/O characters/O at/O key/O moments/O or/O slows/O down/O the/O proceedings/O -LRB-/O such/O as/O by/O suggesting/O that/O he/O sign/O Buckbeak/PERSON 's/O execution/O order/O as/O well/O ,/O then/O after/O Fudge/O agrees/O he/O says/O it/O will/O take/O some/O time/O as/O he/O has/O an/O extremely/O long/O name/O -RRB-/O ,/O which/O allows/O Harry/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON time/O to/O free/O Buckbeak/O unseen/O ./O 
In/O the/O book/O ,/O Dumbledore/PERSON merely/O comments/O that/O the/O executioner/O must/O sign/O the/O order/O ,/O right/O before/O he/O is/O about/O to/O leave/O the/O cabin/O to/O execute/O Buckbeak/PERSON ./O 
The/O embryonic/O romantic/O connection/O between/O Ron/PERSON and/O Hermione/PERSON is/O more/O prominent/O in/O the/O film/O than/O the/O book/O ;/O in/O response/O to/O criticism/O of/O the/O first/O two/O films/O for/O sacrificing/O character/O development/O for/O mystery/O and/O adventure/O ,/O the/O emotional/O development/O of/O all/O three/O lead/O characters/O is/O given/O more/O attention/O in/O the/O third/O film/O ./O 
However/O ,/O some/O critics/O and/O fans/O thought/O that/O the/O result/O was/O a/O murky/O plotline/O ./O 
That/O said/O ,/O any/O mention/O of/O the/O beginnings/O of/O Harry/PERSON 's/O crush/O on/O Cho/PERSON Chang/PERSON is/O removed/O ./O 
Harry/PERSON 's/O darker/O side/O is/O first/O glimpsed/O in/O this/O film/O ,/O when/O Harry/PERSON proclaims/O ,/O ``/O I/O hope/O he/O -LRB-/O Black/O -RRB-/O finds/O me/O ./O 
Cause/O when/O he/O does/O ,/O I/O 'm/O gonna/O be/O ready/O ./O 
When/O he/O does/O ,/O I/O 'm/O gonna/O kill/O him/O !/O ''/O 
Also/O ,/O Harry/PERSON receives/O the/O Firebolt/O at/O the/O film/O 's/O end/O ,/O while/O in/O the/O book/O he/O receives/O it/O anonymously/O at/O Christmas/O and/O it/O is/O confiscated/O for/O a/O few/O weeks/O to/O be/O checked/O for/O possible/O jinxes/O by/O Professor/O Flitwick/PERSON and/O Madam/PERSON Hooch/PERSON ./O 
Distribution/O Marketing/O As/O with/O the/O series/O '/O previous/O instalments/O ,/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O was/O a/O large/O merchandising/O opportunity/O ./O 
The/O video/O game/O version/O ,/O designed/O by/O EA/ORGANIZATION UK/ORGANIZATION ,/O was/O released/O 25/O May/O 2004/O in/O North/LOCATION America/LOCATION and/O 29/O May/O 2004/O in/O Europe/LOCATION ./O 
Mattel/ORGANIZATION released/O film/O tie-ins/O that/O included/O the/O Harry/ORGANIZATION Potter/ORGANIZATION Championship/ORGANIZATION Quidditch/ORGANIZATION board/O game/O and/O character/O action/O figures/O ./O 
Lego/PERSON also/O expanded/O on/O its/O previous/O merchandising/O for/O the/O first/O two/O films/O with/O the/O release/O of/O sets/O ranging/O from/O the/O Knight/O Bus/O to/O the/O Shrieking/O Shack/O ./O 
Release/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O held/O its/O New/LOCATION York/LOCATION premiere/O at/O Radio/O City/O Music/O Hall/O on/O 23/O May/O 2004/O ,/O followed/O by/O its/O London/LOCATION premiere/O at/O Leicester/LOCATION Square/LOCATION on/O 30/O May/O 2004/O ./O 
The/O film/O then/O opened/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION on/O 31/O May/O 2004/O and/O on/O 4/O June/O 2004/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION ./O 
Reaction/O Box/O office/O Upon/O release/O ,/O the/O film/O broke/O the/O record/O for/O biggest/O single/O day/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION Kingdom/LOCATION 's/O box/O office/O history/O making/O #/O 5.3/O million/O on/O a/O Monday/O ./O 
It/O went/O on/O to/O break/O records/O both/O with/O and/O without/O previews/O making/O a/O stunning/O #/O 23.9/O million/O including/O previews/O and/O #/O 9.3/O million/O excluding/O them/O ./O 
The/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O currently/O has/O the/O highest-opening/O weekend/O at/O the/O U.K./LOCATION 's/O box/O office/O ./O 
It/O went/O on/O to/O make/O a/O total/O of/O #/O 45.6/O million/O in/O the/O U.K./LOCATION ./O 
The/O film/O made/O $/O 93.7/O million/O during/O its/O opening/O weekend/O in/O the/O United/LOCATION States/LOCATION and/O Canada/LOCATION at/O 3,855/O theaters/O ,/O achieving/O ,/O at/O the/O time/O ,/O the/O third/O biggest-opening/O weekend/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
This/O opening/O also/O broke/O Hulk/PERSON 's/O record/O -LRB-/O $/O 62.1/O million/O -RRB-/O for/O the/O highest-opening/O weekend/O for/O a/O film/O released/O in/O June/O ./O 
The/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O held/O this/O record/O for/O five/O years/O until/O Transformers/O :/O Revenge/O of/O the/O Fallen/O topped/O it/O in/O 2009/O with/O $/O 108.9/O million/O ./O 
The/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O made/O a/O total/O of/O $/O 796.6/O million/O worldwide/O ,/O which/O made/O it/O 2004/O 's/O second/O highest-grossing/O film/O worldwide/O behind/O Shrek/O 2/O ./O 
In/O the/O U.S./LOCATION and/O Canada/LOCATION ,/O it/O was/O only/O the/O year/O 's/O sixth/O highest-grossing/O film/O ,/O making/O $/O 249.5/O million/O ./O 
Everywhere/O else/O in/O the/O world/O ,/O however/O ,/O it/O was/O the/O year/O 's/O number/O one/O film/O ,/O making/O $/O 547/O million/O compared/O to/O Shrek/ORGANIZATION 2/O 's/O $/O 478.6/O million/O ./O 
Despite/O its/O successful/O box/O office/O run/O ,/O Azkaban/O is/O currently/O the/O lowest-grossing/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON film/O -LRB-/O all/O the/O other/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON films/O have/O grossed/O more/O than/O US/LOCATION $/O 875/O million/O worldwide/O -RRB-/O ./O 
Still/O ,/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O is/O currently/O the/O thirty-seventh/O highest-grossing/O film/O in/O history/O ./O 
Critical/O reception/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O earned/O notable/O critical/O acclaim/O ,/O garnering/O a/O 91/O %/O ``/O Certified/O Fresh/O ''/O approval/O rating/O at/O the/O review/O aggregator/O Rotten/O Tomatoes/O with/O a/O consensus/O stating/O ,/O ``/O In/O Cuaron/PERSON 's/O hands/O ,/O Azkaban/PERSON has/O emotional/O depth/O to/O go/O along/O with/O the/O technical/O wizardry/O ./O ''/O 
The/O film/O also/O received/O a/O score/O of/O 82/O out/O of/O 100/O at/O Metacritic/ORGANIZATION ,/O which/O signifies/O ``/O universal/O acclaim/O ./O ''/O 
Mick/PERSON LaSalle/PERSON of/O the/O San/ORGANIZATION Francisco/ORGANIZATION Chronicle/ORGANIZATION lauded/O the/O film/O 's/O more/O mature/O tone/O and/O said/O it/O was/O ``/O darker/O ,/O more/O complex/O ,/O rooted/O in/O character/O ./O 
``/O The/O Hollywood/O Reporter/O called/O the/O film/O ``/O a/O deeper/O ,/O darker/O ,/O visually/O arresting/O and/O more/O emotionally/O satisfying/O adaptation/O of/O the/O J.K./PERSON Rowling/PERSON literary/O phenomenon/O ,/O ''/O especially/O compared/O to/O the/O first/O two/O instalments/O ./O 
Peter/PERSON Travers/PERSON of/O Rolling/ORGANIZATION Stone/ORGANIZATION gave/O the/O film/O three-and-a-half/O out/O of/O four/O stars/O :/O ``/O Not/O only/O is/O this/O dazzler/O by/O far/O the/O best/O and/O most/O thrilling/O of/O the/O three/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON movies/O to/O date/O ,/O it/O 's/O a/O film/O that/O can/O stand/O on/O its/O own/O even/O if/O you/O never/O heard/O of/O author/O J.K./PERSON Rowling/PERSON and/O her/O young/O wizard/O hero/O ./O ''/O 
Stephanie/PERSON Zacharek/PERSON of/O Salon.com/O asserts/O it/O to/O be/O ``/O one/O of/O the/O greatest/O fantasy/O films/O of/O all/O time/O ./O ''/O 
Nicole/PERSON Arthur/PERSON of/O The/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION praised/O the/O film/O as/O ``/O complex/O ,/O frightening/O ,/O -LRB-/O and/O -RRB-/O nuanced/O ./O 
``/O Roger/PERSON Ebert/PERSON gave/O the/O film/O three-and-a-half/O out/O of/O four/O stars/O ,/O saying/O that/O the/O film/O was/O not/O quite/O as/O good/O as/O the/O first/O two/O ,/O but/O still/O called/O it/O ``/O delightful/O ,/O amusing/O and/O sophisticated/O ''/O Claudia/PERSON Puig/PERSON from/O USA/LOCATION Today/O found/O the/O film/O to/O be/O ``/O a/O visual/O delight/O ,/O ''/O and/O added/O that/O ``/O Cuaron/O is/O not/O afraid/O to/O make/O a/O darker/O film/O and/O tackle/O painful/O emotions/O ./O ''/O 
while/O Richard/PERSON Roeper/PERSON called/O the/O film/O ``/O a/O creative/O triumph/O ./O ''/O 
Sean/PERSON Smith/PERSON from/O Newsweek/ORGANIZATION said/O :/O ``/O The/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O boasts/O a/O brand-new/O director/O and/O a/O bold/O new/O vision/O ,/O ''/O he/O also/O called/O the/O film/O ``/O moving/O ,/O ''/O praising/O the/O performances/O by/O Radcliffe/PERSON and/O Watson/PERSON ,/O while/O Entertainment/O Weekly/O praised/O the/O film/O for/O being/O more/O mature/O than/O its/O predecessors/O ./O 
Some/O of/O the/O criticism/O came/O from/O The/ORGANIZATION Washington/ORGANIZATION Post/ORGANIZATION :/O ``/O Put/O delicately/O ,/O this/O is/O one/O long/O sit/O ,/O made/O all/O the/O more/O so/O by/O a/O turgid/O story/O ,/O a/O dour/O visual/O palette/O and/O uninspiring/O action/O ./O ''/O 
Rex/PERSON Reed/PERSON ,/O of/O The/ORGANIZATION New/ORGANIZATION York/ORGANIZATION Observer/ORGANIZATION ,/O also/O pointed/O out/O some/O unnecessary/O stylistic/O changes/O ,/O calling/O it/O ``/O the/O silliest/O ,/O as/O well/O as/O the/O most/O contrived/O --/O and/O confusing/O --/O of/O them/O all/O ./O ''/O 
Accolades/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O was/O nominated/O for/O Best/O Original/O Music/O Score/O -LRB-/O John/PERSON Williams/PERSON -RRB-/O and/O Best/O Visual/O Effects/O at/O the/O 77th/O Academy/O Awards/O held/O in/O 2005/O ./O 
This/O was/O the/O second/O film/O in/O the/O series/O to/O be/O nominated/O for/O an/O Oscar/O ./O 
The/O film/O also/O ranks/O at/O No./O 471/O in/O Empire/O magazine/O 's/O 2008/O list/O of/O the/O 500/O greatest/O movies/O of/O all/O time/O ./O 
IGN/ORGANIZATION designated/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O as/O the/O fifth/O best/O fantasy/O film/O ./O 
In/O 2011/O ,/O the/O film/O was/O voted/O Film/O of/O the/O Decade/O at/O the/O First/O Light/O Awards/O by/O children/O aged/O 5/O --/O 15/O ./O 
American/ORGANIZATION Film/ORGANIZATION Institute/ORGANIZATION recognition/O AFI/ORGANIZATION 's/O 100/O Years/O .../O 100/O Movies/O -LRB-/O 10th/O Anniversary/O Edition/O -RRB-/O --/O Nominated/O AFI/ORGANIZATION 's/O 10/O Top/O 10/O --/O Nominated/O Fantasy/O Film/O References/O External/O links/O Official/O website/O -LRB-/O US/LOCATION -RRB-/O Official/O website/O -LRB-/O UK/LOCATION -RRB-/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O at/O the/O Internet/O Movie/O Database/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Azkaban/ORGANIZATION at/O AllRovi/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Azkaban/ORGANIZATION at/O Rotten/O Tomatoes/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/ORGANIZATION of/ORGANIZATION Azkaban/ORGANIZATION at/O Box/O Office/O Mojo/O Harry/PERSON Potter/PERSON and/O the/O Prisoner/O of/O Azkaban/O at/O Metacritic/LOCATION 
